<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://kymira.ca/blog</id>
    <title>Kymira Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-03-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kymira.ca/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Kymira Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://kymira.ca/img/favicon2.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Style Study - Hades]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study"/>
        <updated>2025-03-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A week spent studying the art style of the video game Hades, as led by Jen Zee.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Second style study of the year is the art of Hades, the hit Supergiant game and one of my all time faves.</p>
<p>My approach to this week was to re-create some existing game assets and then adapt one of my characters into a Hades styled portrait shot. A slightly different approach from my Root week as I found this style much more difficult and just mentally draining because of how central the line art is to the style.</p>
<p>Main focuses for the week:</p>
<ul>
<li>Line art style</li>
<li>Colours</li>
<li>Ink black shadows</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="research">Research<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#research" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Research" title="Direct link to Research">​</a></h2>
<p>I knew this would be a pretty easy art style to research because Hades is so beloved. So there are multiple videos of people breaking down the style, people sharing their research, others compiling a list of inspiration and techniques used from multiple interviews with the art director.</p>
<p>Which is an amazing amount of resources to learn from, but because this is an official in-house style used by multiple artists, there aren’t really first hand reports from them. Which I think makes sense because while the style is going to be replicated, you don’t need to make it super easy for people to make knock-offs.</p>
<p>There is however one very short sequence in <a href="https://youtu.be/oQPk9J7spw0?si=3PLDkZbc8TjjvVIh&amp;t=831" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">episode 3 of the the Developing Hell</a> documentary that shows the layers coming together on Jen Zee’s screen.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="style-inspiration">Style inspiration<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#style-inspiration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Style inspiration" title="Direct link to Style inspiration">​</a></h3>
<p>While I did 5 years of art in highschool, I never really learned much about… art styles. Our teacher touched on a few classical artists but there was a big push to focus on Canadian content so the only artists I know are like The Group of Seven.</p>
<p>Because of that it makes learning about professional artist inspirations all the more beneficial. These are some of the names that came up when Jen Zee talk’s about the inspiration for Hades’s look:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mike Mignola (Specifically inspired the direction of the Hades art)</li>
<li>Yoji Shinkawa (For his strongly sculpted character art)</li>
<li>Fred Taylor (For his use of colour and setting)</li>
</ul>
<p>Then there were a few art techniques and inspirations that have also been identified by artists or mentioned by the team. And have been put into a huge list <a href="https://www.pointnthink.fr/en/the-art-of-hades-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in this Point n’ Click blog post</a>. Covering things like classic Greek statues, the importance of diversity, pottery art, and the myths themselves.</p>
<p>As someone who spends a lot of time looking at reference images, and now this year trying to do more studies, it’s cool to see someone else’s clear lines that link what an artist is currently doing to what has come before.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="breakdowns">Breakdowns<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#breakdowns" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Breakdowns" title="Direct link to Breakdowns">​</a></h3>
<p>I think I’ve shared this video before but it’s easily one of my favourite approaches to style studies; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abHLAgvhUGs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Breaking Down the Hades Art Style</a>. Thom catches a lot of details and does a really cool basic sphere to show off the important style features.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-sphere-25ebf6f6e10766db579802d45a8f46b2.png" width="2646" height="1382" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Another interesting breakdown is <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/kDyR9x" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dayron Desmet’ study to create a style bible</a> where he goes over multiple different facets of the style before designing his own 3 accessories in the game style.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="style-warm-ups">Style warm-ups<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#style-warm-ups" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Style warm-ups" title="Direct link to Style warm-ups">​</a></h2>
<p>I started with recreating a few smaller art assets from Hades. No full character portraits, except for Dusa who is probably the smallest portrait in the game.</p>
<p>I chopped these birds off of Artemis’s bow because I love them but also hardly noticed them before since they’re so far away from the rest of her body. I suspect they’re cropped out in most scenes when she’s on the screen.</p>
<p>I struggled with these guys a lot. I felt like I wasn’t getting the shapes down. I hated the way the line art looked. I had no wait in the fixed sized brush. Sunday and Monday were mostly try &gt; delete &gt; restart. Then I finally mentally gave myself permission to not try to match the shapes as accurately and really turned up stabilisation on the brush settings.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-practices-a214ae39439c6eb3ee43aac4a5aca883.jpg" width="4973" height="1958" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The wallet came out okay but my drop of focus on the shape made for some uneven edges but I enjoyed the gold bits.</p>
<p>Dusa was more of a struggle, just being more complex than the previous two practice pieces. But I really wanted to draw the snakes so I stuck with this one even with her slightly off-tilt face.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-piece">Final piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#final-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final piece" title="Direct link to Final piece">​</a></h2>
<p>I had already made up my mind to use Skril as my Hades adaptation character, I have a few outfits for her, so I wouldn't have to start from zero design wise.  What I did need was a pose.</p>
<p>I tried sketching out a few options and then decided the hand forward pose was the right amount of drama. Used <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/598978819231278895/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this as my reference</a>.</p>
<p>Following the workflow from the Style Breakdown video I started with the lines. I now had more confidence in the process and also the look of the lines compared to my earlier practices. One change up I did go for was to not do the hard black shadows in the first pass. Sticking to only the functional lines.</p>
<p>I then moved on to flats which was a study in itself. Due to an old laptop dying I didn’t have easy access to a Skril reference and instead colour picked them from a photograph of a marker piece from 5 years ago. This ended up being decently accurate.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-base-colours-ee6651ea91c7807720ff56472410a808.jpg" width="1322" height="1890" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>But I had a problem, Hades portraits are colour balanced very carefully.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="colour-breakdown">Colour breakdown<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#colour-breakdown" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Colour breakdown" title="Direct link to Colour breakdown">​</a></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours1-9370b217fc52b6a7335ca8aac4b16329.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q">
From reading and watching other people break down the style it became clear that I shouldn’t have too many different saturated colours. Characters usually have one main focus colour, often their outfit, while the other large swatches of colour are more de-saturated.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours2-e81391f7024710c319620d95a48466d1.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I also checked the values but these didn’t say much to me. If anything it only highlighted that the colour balance does a lot of work to make the characters easily readable without having any very high values (Less white and less high contrast zones than I would have thought). Or maybe the sheer amount of pure black was throwing off my evaluation.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours-values-ad27b604c1a24d5a653a7a2fa4756798.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>With this knowledge I changed up Skril’s skin, horn, and hair colour.  Leaving just the saturated reds and golds. As the red fell into a similar zone as the prime colours for Hypnos and Meg:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours3-d1f468a3a3b0365d0e5fb715bf2b456b.jpg" width="210" height="140" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-skril-desat-462d5b2e3b5c9eaae4c343fc36650333.jpg" width="1889" height="2700" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>With the colours changed I spent some time choosing the shadow and terminator line colour for my main colours. The terminator line colour is one of the unique calling card features of the Hades style. The terminator line is the line of colour around the darker shadow colour. Usually it would just be a colour between the base and the shadow but in this style it’s usually a colour between the two but also decently hue shifted.</p>
<p>With lines, flats, and shading done, it was time to start adding the black shadows. I don’t know if it was good to leave this part for last. If only because I ended up covering multiple areas I spent time shading…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-shadows-fce9128cf8f02907fc99ed396a9ed808.jpg" width="1889" height="2700" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m still not sure if there should be more black. General art advice is to not use pure whites or pure blacks so it still feels extreme to me to have those big black areas.</p>
<p>With the piece nearly done, it was time for random sparkles.</p>
<p>This is another unique feature of the style that people have noticed. All art pieces have what appear to be random specks of teal, purple, pink, and a few other colours. I couldn’t find any evidence of these colours being applied in a specific way so I kind of just put them around randomly.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-done-82347598a6cf11cd67b41183a26f297f.jpg" width="1283" height="2130" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-i-missed">What I missed<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#what-i-missed" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What I missed" title="Direct link to What I missed">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a few places where I deviated from the official style.</p>
<p>Firstly is in my smooth lines. In Hades art you'll almost never find a perfect circle, even perfect curves are rare. But I was drawing a curvy lady so I drew curvy lines. I also hadn't been able to build up line confidence in my warm-ups and I was relying a lot of brush stabalization to get lines I was happy with. Downside being that those almost come out <strong>too</strong> perfect.</p>
<p>Another issue, building on those curved lines was my lack of squares. A lot of Hades art has points and hard curves, also called 'Sharp Shape Language' in Thom's breakdown. If you look at characters fingers you'll see they have square tips. This was a bit because of the lines and a bit because I forgot. Line work is what I struggle with so it takes up a lot of my attention. So while I'm focused on just trying to get lines I like I forgot there were other rules to be following.</p>
<p>For colours I feel like I maybe didn't use enough? The official art has an almost busy feeling to it when you look closely. There is a lot going on. While I left some rather large basic red zones in my pieces. I probably could have tried a few ways of making it more lively.</p>
<p>Oh and I didn't draw legs. I thought the image would crop higher up for the fake screenshot so I hadn't bothered to give them lines and then by the end of it I didn't want to go back and add them back in lol.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="in-game-screenshot">“In-game” screenshot<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#in-game-screenshot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to “In-game” screenshot" title="Direct link to “In-game” screenshot">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-box-final-c7f003753dafe07c9e5d979eaba42bd9.jpg" width="788" height="521" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Making fake Hades screenshots is a pretty popular artist project so finding all the pieces needed was very easy. But in case anyone ever comes looking here they are in one place.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="text-box">Text box<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#text-box" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Text box" title="Direct link to Text box">​</a></h3>
<p>I suspect a few people have done this themselves already, but <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/theemonkeyprince/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TheeMonkeyPrince</a>’s <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/theemonkeyprince/art/Hades-Dialogue-Box-Template-859250942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> comes up first in a search result. There’s some clear pixelation issues found in the shape they used to hide text from the screenshot they used but that’s easy to fix with a little blur.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fonts">Fonts<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#fonts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fonts" title="Direct link to Fonts">​</a></h3>
<p>I didn’t have these ready to go when I started the text box but as I suspected someone had done the research long ago. Even named which font is used for what in this <a href="https://graphicdesign.stackexchange.com/questions/163095/what-fonts-are-used-in-the-video-game-hades" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">helpful StackExchange comment</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-fonts-8b5a9f907dd8c20d0477c1d5223baae7.png" width="1248" height="120" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’ve become very fond of the font for character names which is titled <a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Caesar+Dressing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Caesar Dressing</a>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background" title="Direct link to Background">​</a></h3>
<p>For the background, I grabbed <a href="https://joannetran.artstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joanne Tran</a>’s official work <a href="https://joannetran.artstation.com/projects/v2401Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">from her ArtStation page</a> where she’s shared a lot of Hades art.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I have given myself a stretch goal of creating a more Underdark themed background to use in my fake screenshot since that's where Skril's from. Just not sure when I'll have time to squeeze in an extra background.</p>
<p>This study took a few days longer than I normally allow. Fell on a D&amp;D week and I lose my creative window on D&amp;D days to D&amp;D prep. And then I felt under the weather on Sunday so that was my main art days gone. So instead of my planned WAP week I'm going to spend this week getting familiar with some tools.</p>
<p>I upgraded to Clip Studio v4 last week so I'm excited to try out some of it's new features. And I want to learn the new features in the ToonSquid v2 release that happened a few months ago. So maybe I'll try and get back into some animation stuff this week.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="style study" term="style study"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anatomy practice - Yoga]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses"/>
        <updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drawing bodies in yoga poses.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last practice in the weekly rotation is classic anatomy and posing. I don’t even dislike doing pose practice but doing it for a week straight is a little much and by day 4 I’m tired of it. But I still want to push myself through the motions so I don’t just try to keep cutting corners with it.</p>
<p>I am still trying to keep these weeks on a theme to be a little more focused and also to keep getting new kinds of poses. This week is yoga, so not the most natural of poses but a good reminder in the ways bodies can bend and move. With the extra difficulty of really needing to focus on the length of limbs because they often need to land in certain places.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Drawing what poses I can remember, which isn’t very many.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.1-1aad99928cdf1c1483bf99554cb8c346.png" width="1489" height="1168" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Doing some quick figure studies to remember shapes better.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.2-6db51203a06fd7ba282d389cf2ee4212.jpg" width="1544" height="1065" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>My current approach to the study days is to do a trace version as it really helps to figure out the limbs you can’t see and then do a free hand version to try to reinforce what I got from the trace. What I want to add to my practice days is one for pushing the pose. Which wouldn’t have really worked for yoga as it’s already a rather extreme shape for a body to take but I think will work well for other activities.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.3-b82bd1fc7b709041ac15b94f13708831.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.4-fe72cea4b8428aaaceebe9a6d48d9e2d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---reference-studies">Day 4 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-4---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.5-08a19a625daec3709806a6cda44d26c5.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.6-46cf79ac18130816e4686749ddb4b016.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.7-708ea0cdf8405eb4d006a4aace9c8075.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>For the test day I wanted to try different angles instead of different poses. Since I struggled to get much beyond profile shots for yoga poses I thought it would be good to make my brain work by changing the camera angle.</p>
<p>I did two basic poses first, warrior and cobra. Then I did front angles for both and then a top down, birds eye view for warrior. I think I maybe kept things too sketchy and worry these might not be readable. But since it’s mostly practice on making sure body parts are in the correct place and not using this for a future piece I do want to keep things sketchy and light.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.8-d1ea42631df68f528eb789775b1d5753.jpg" width="806" height="454" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Something I struggled with this week was finding references of yoga poses not in full profile. It’s just how most photography is done as it’s the best way to view the pose if you want to replicate it yourself. But it made for rather static looking bodies when they’re all at the exact same angle. Next anatomy theme needs to be something that’s, weirdly, photographed less.</p>
<p>This anatomy week brings my first practice cycle of the year to a close. Did one; Style study, WAP, Reference study, and one anatomy week. So today the cycle starts again as I return to style studies, with this week's style being The Art of Hades (the video game). A fairly iconic style now, the game has a huge fandom of people replicating the style so I know I’ll find Youtube videos. But there isn’t as much from the studio and art director, which makes sense as you don’t really want another game copying your visual style.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-yoga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of yoga poses.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reference Study - Fey Boat]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat"/>
        <updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking 3 reference images and making them into 1.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I was preparing my art practice goals for the new year I knew I wanted to practice finishing pieces more often. My WAP weeks were about expanding my mental library of images and drawing things I don’t often draw. But those barely ever left the sketch phase as they were focused on getting the shapes down. The style studies are a lot of fun and I’ll keep doing them but they mean working in a very focused way to achieve a rather limited goal, matching someone else’s style. And while these will help me learn things that will eventually become my style, the execution won’t always feel natural.</p>
<p>And so I came up with this new exercise after watching a few “learning from references” art tutorial videos on YouTube. Basically the idea is that instead of just using one image as inspiration you use multiple so you’re leaning less on one particular artist or style.</p>
<p>Last week in my <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-41" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">beetles WAP</a> I wrote about how this would go. Rolling dice to select 3 images and then go from there. So we’ll start with my 3 images:</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-images">Reference Images<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#reference-images" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reference Images" title="Direct link to Reference Images">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_refs-a7050718f8ae8426611287bf5be5da35.jpg" width="2340" height="815" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I was pretty excited about getting the boat first. Thought I could do some sort of Dredge inspired piece with it. The piece is by concept artist <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/r33nO" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arthus Pilorget</a>.</p>
<p>But then I got the colour palette… which isn’t very Dredge like at all. The Genshin Impact Kazuha palette was put together by <a href="https://ko-fi.com/s/090280618a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Caramello__o over on Ko-fi</a>.</p>
<p>Dice roll 3 added these nature spirit guys by <a href="https://x.com/dagasi_yk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dagasi_yk on Twitter</a> as the main characters.</p>
<p>Wanting to expand my ideas beyond just the three images so I made a mini board of things I felt were in a similar vibe. <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/2025-num-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Full board</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="thumbnailing">Thumbnailing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#thumbnailing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Thumbnailing" title="Direct link to Thumbnailing">​</a></h2>
<p>First step was to do some basic brainstorming. Starting with what first came to mind and then pushing the POV around to see if the scene got more interesting from other angles.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_thumbnails-c1f37a72fe1109b58f5efaeac14ef79c.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="basic-colours-and-shapes">Basic colours and shapes<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#basic-colours-and-shapes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Basic colours and shapes" title="Direct link to Basic colours and shapes">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sketch-2f8c816c115192426339f6625989de9c.jpg" width="3456" height="1944" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I had a decent amount of time on Sunday so after choosing which thumbnail to go with I enlarged it and started to play around with the main colours. I was fairly fixated on have a big orange sky, which may have not been the best choice in the end but I found it rather pleasant to work with as it gave a quickly, otherworldly-ness, to the piece.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1-progress">Day 1 progress<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#day-1-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 progress" title="Direct link to Day 1 progress">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s not often that I give myself a whole week to work on a single piece. During my Root style study week I made 3 complete pieces in 7 days. Having 7 days for one felt extravagant.</p>
<p>Or at least it did until I started painting. I couldn’t choose how I wanted to do the piece. Did I want hard black lines? Did I want lineless? A softer painting style? Or flat and blocky?</p>
<p>While I had 3 images as references to build the piece, I didn’t use any of them to really dictate the style. So I pulled up some digital painting videos and waited for inspiration to reach me. Eventually, I got my first piece down; the roof.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sunday1-a23b6ec386f46fe9c83cdbbaaa86d646.png" width="1392" height="1127" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I was pretty happy with how these shingles looked but my attempt to make it more readable by changing the colours instantly broke my colour palette and also made the scene look like it was made out of candy. But I already felt myself floundering so I pushed on. Grabbing the part of the image that interested me most, the little guys.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sunday2-5a888fc03e9bda734d353164d08cee92.png" width="331" height="698" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>These guys I was happy with. With these guys I could end my day not hating the piece.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="work-continues">Work continues<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#work-continues" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Work continues" title="Direct link to Work continues">​</a></h2>
<p>With the weekend done I made it a goal to try to put 1 hour into the piece everyday after work. Some days saw more progress than others. By Tuesday I had most of a boat.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_tuesday-939423d8f0bde3af6c0f692ae6af56ac.png" width="1068" height="832" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After that I kind of stopped saving progress shots….</p>
<p>I finished most of the boat before going to the background. I returned to my struggles of choosing a stylistic choice once more and you can see me growing impatient by turning to leaf brushes for the tree and grass brushes to fill in the small islands. I’m not against using these kinds of brushes but since I only use them for these 2 features and they’re off to the side on their own island it does make them stand out more by not being consistent with the rest of the piece. If I had thought ahead and maybe balanced the islands in the background differently I could probably have made it look more normalized. But I’m kind of a “just push through” kind of artist. A habit I’m going to try to fix.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-piece">Final piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#final-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final piece" title="Direct link to Final piece">​</a></h2>
<p>I was able to wrap up the whole thing on Saturday, rushing to get it done before running D&amp;D and having taken the morning off to make a map and draw some goblins for the game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_final-c8c72af12704e8575235d5d1dc91bcac.jpg" width="3456" height="1944" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Overall I think about somewhere between 10-15 hours went into this piece. Being able to take my time led to some parts I’m really happy with, like some of the wood texturing on the boat, how textured the clouds look, the little plant guys. There are definitely some areas I rushed either because I didn’t know how to accomplish what I wanted or because I was losing interest. I think next time I do this challenge I’m going to try to give myself a Friday deadline so I can spend a whole Saturday just working on light and shadows and colour corrections because that’s something I really enjoy but rarely give myself enough time to do properly.</p>
<p>I’m not sure how well I was able to stick to the palette. I probably wouldn’t have chosen these colours on my own so it was nice to have the restriction, but it also made me constantly worry about deviating too far when wanting to do some hue shifted shadows. I also didn't keep some of the main points I highlighted in my thumbnails. I didn't keep the side wheel which I really wanted, or have there be plants on the boat. It just felt like I had enough going on when I made the choices but I kind of regret it now.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>While I could talk about all the cut corners and the things I’m not particularly pleased with, this was a very big project for me and it makes me happy when I look at it. I do wish I had played with more foreground/background stuff but this was my first project in this practice format so plenty of time to take more chances in the future. Maybe I’ll even enforce the palette further by not allowing any shifts and having to use only the chosen colours as highlights and shadows. Lots of options for the next one!</p>
<p>Next week I’m going back to anatomy studies as it’s another facet I want to keep improving at and the secret to that one is basically just keep doing it.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 41]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41"/>
        <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 41 - Beetles]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First WAP of 2025!</p>
<p>I’m keeping some WAPs in the mix with my other practice things this year to give me some easier weeks and also to keep drawing things I don’t usually draw. It’s nice to return to a practice format that’s familiar and feels doable. Versus some of the larger challenges I’m also trying to give myself this year.</p>
<p>This first WAP is beetles, so I guess stop reading now if you don’t like looking at bugs as there will be zoomed in pictures of bugs.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Beetles aren’t too complex right? I can just draw some from the ether.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.1-467b3282dc16b9a7e6aa03f66ceef5f6.jpg" width="2179" height="1760" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a lot of hercules and rhinoceros beetles on Pinterest so that’s what I ended up focusing on. I didn’t know how large these bugs were until this week and boy, I’m not sure if I’m better off knowing or not.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.2-7eb055637a1f0a5c06c7994bf341e9e0.jpg" width="2484" height="1773" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Some of the biggest things I missed in my initial sketches were how complex beetle legs are. They are very spiky and have a decent amount of joints. I also missed that some have some antenna things going on but you need a very good photo to see them.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.3.1-24d79669425e23e8a092ceb4112257f4.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.3.2-18ab45a94f6e461afa9e7597dc4a56a2.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>There are some really nice stylized beetles out there. And it was nice to see how much people simplified the complicated limbs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.1-2509e8defbf5f42339db3955f6b20bcf.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Pinterest says this is by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/opossum_jesus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">opossum_jesus on Instagram</a> but their account is private so I can’t verify. There is also a Redbubble account selling a sticker version but it’s been taken down. So whoever drew this has been taking down their art from public spaces.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.2-903266f2a73b73b6b17a227dada6a6f9.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I didn’t do the really pretty pattern as it wasn’t going to contribute to grasping the shape of a beetle but i do really love this piece by Oddarette.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://cara.app/post/e8dafedc-1170-4eb4-94ad-fa3311ad83cc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By Oddarette on Cara</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.3-2b904afad7d053f3c369048e4d480149.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: A vector image from[Freepik]<a href="https://www.freepik.com/premium-vector/beetle-illustration-cartoon-character-drawing_69868105.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.freepik.com/premium-vector/beetle-illustration-cartoon-character-drawing_69868105.htm</a>)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>For test day I drew some basic guys but then also wanted to do a slightly more cartoon-y character. Hence the warrior beetle holding a staff in the corner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.5-25efb74724d8f704aa4107456971c569.jpg" width="2690" height="1995" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Insects definitely aren’t something I draw regularly, nor are they something I often want to look very closely at. But I think it’s important to draw them, and at least understand how to draw them as they are everywhere and looking at them so closely helps to demystify them. Makes me squirm a little less at each new photo.</p>
<p>It was nice to return to the WAP format, I feel like I can get through the daily task fairly quickly now. Made for a good practice exercise for a week where I was still feeling pretty ill and low energy. This coming week I’m trying something a little more intensive, doing an exercise to help learn how to draw from reference.</p>
<p>I created 3 pin boards:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colour schemes</li>
<li>Locations</li>
<li>Characters</li>
</ul>
<p>Then for each one of those boards I rolled a di so I would randomly get a colour scheme to use for a type of location which will feature a random character. Forcing me to get creative in how all three pieces fit together and create something new. I want these to be fully rendered pieces and I have the sketch for my first one completed already but I’m struggling with how to colour it. Do I want to try a digital painting style? Do I stick with my default black linework? Should I try to bring in some of the techniques I learned from my Root study week?????? Just so many options and none of them are working for me just yet.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-beetles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of beetles</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Style Study - Kyle Ferrin]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study"/>
        <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A week spent studying the art style of the board game Root, as done by Kyle Ferrin.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of my WAP year I did one style study, <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-34" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ken Sugimori’s Pokemon trainers</a>. This year I’m going to attempt to do a style study every month to push me out of my comfort zone and also to learn to break down what I’m looking at when it comes to art pieces.</p>
<p>Kyle Ferrin was an easy first choice as he has both a very distinct style that’s almost instantly recognizable to me and it’s extremely cute. For this study I’m focusing mostly on his visual style of the boardgame Root and not his whole portfolio but he is pretty consistent in some regards.</p>
<p>Before jumping in I wanted to identify the main things I wanted to learn or understand in this particular study:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ink work: Kyle uses blank ink for a lot of shadows, much more than I would usually</li>
<li>Shapes: We’re gonna be looking at a lot of little critters, how does he keep them recognizable?</li>
<li>Colours: The work in Root feels extremely vibrant while still natural.</li>
<li>Backgrounds: Kyle doesn’t do a lot of backgrounds but does have a few techniques he repeats.</li>
</ul>
<p>Studies are going to break down differently from my WAP weeks, and may even differ from artist to artist. I made a 5 day plan for this one and mostly managed to stick to it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---research-and-techniques">Day 1 - Research and techniques<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-1---research-and-techniques" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Research and techniques" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Research and techniques">​</a></h2>
<p>Root and Kyle are, thankfully, both very popular. An added bonus is that Kyle has some recorded streams of his full art process. This makes understanding his workflow pretty easy as you can watch him do it in real time. I was even able to find 2 interviews he did where he talks about art which led to a few gems that helped me approach this study week.</p>
<p>Interview 1: <a href="https://www.moregamesplease.com/art-in-boardgames/2018/3/15/kyle-ferrin-art-in-board-games-31" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kyle Ferrin: Art in Board Games #31</a></p>
<p>Interview 2: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/boardgames/comments/bu8a6l/interview_with_kyle_ferrin_artist_on_root/?rdt=54583" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Interview with Kyle Ferrin, Artist on Root!</a> (Original website seems broken)</p>
<p>It was in the images chosen for the More Games Please interview that I noticed the bush and tree techniques. So on day one I tried to recreate those techniques digitally. I then took my old goblin drawing and did an inking pass on it to practice where Kyle would put harder shadows, using this collection of skeleton warriors as examples to reference.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf_techniques1-bf0cb463cd44b34e8585b15afc24150b.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I then spent some time with the Root cover image and a collection of Kyle goblins. I love how expressive his characters are and I wanted to look more closely at Root character proportions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-faces-15d86904f3527b60123afb87f1795b3a.jpg" width="3840" height="1735" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---first-attempt-at-the-style">Day 2 - First attempt at the style<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-2---first-attempt-at-the-style" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - First attempt at the style" title="Direct link to Day 2 - First attempt at the style">​</a></h2>
<p>Feeling pretty excited by what I learned in day 1 I jumped into creating a Root fanart piece. I wanted to draw critters that aren’t as common in Root so I chose pigeon and squirrel. Kyle has done a few squirrels but I have to say they aren’t my favourite designs of his.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-full-scene1-0e4ce6745fd4c63a0e0e4750d4df6d07.jpg" width="2015" height="1443" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m happy with a lot of this piece but there are a few areas that stand out for improvement. Mostly the building. There aren’t many full buildings in the Root art so I didn’t have much to use as a reference. Because of that I kind of just floundered and used it to fill space. I also could have played with more line/ink colour variations instead of just black and white.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---workflow-replication">Day 3 - Workflow replication<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-3---workflow-replication" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Workflow replication" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Workflow replication">​</a></h2>
<p>To see Kyle’s workflow in action I watched his live stream from three months ago: <a href="https://youtu.be/kxlhol6JOhQ?si=ua68nO0f4xz1k0sk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leder Games | Art Stream with Kyle Ferrin!</a></p>
<p>Which seems to breakdown to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sketch</li>
<li>Ink</li>
<li>Scan</li>
<li>Digital colours</li>
</ol>
<p>So I would do the same. Instead of adding difficulty of coming up with a piece from scratch I decided to recreate a piece of Root art. I wanted something with a little bit of background as well as a character so I went with this raccoon behind a log piece.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Raccoon in behind a log by Kyle Ferrin" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kyle-forest-raccoon-bca23aeb7b245ced8eb1d16f2acfbbcc.jpg" width="736" height="1028" class="img_ev3q">
(This is an original Root piece.)</p>
<p>I did a sketch and then tested my pens because it’s been a long time since I inked anything by hand. Most of what I own are Microns which didn’t feel right for this, they are too small and precise. So I chose my pens that had more of a brush tip for larger areas.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/raccoon-inks-69861b128bfe57e65b28176c08ebf8ae.jpg" width="3072" height="4080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I don’t have a scanner so I had to rely on trying to get a good phone photo. It came out pretty decent after some level corrections in CSP but also felt like there were a lot of strange artifacts like red pixels and blurring in the photo.</p>
<p>I then colour picked from the original and tried out some digital watercolour brushes to get that textured look that Kyle gets. In the video Kyle shares the limited Root colour palette that he uses for all the board game pieces. And in one of the interviews he said:</p>
<p>“Most of the color pallet for the board art in Root is sampled from autumn foliage photography.”</p>
<p>So I also felt comfortable deviating a little from the source image as long as I kept the autumn colours in mind.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-copy-study-cf397222294342549691a70a1dfc2401.jpg" width="2004" height="3051" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>My own raccoon came out a little too small but I’m happy with the piece overall. I liked working with the water colour brushes as they keep the large colour areas interesting without even doing a shading pass. I did try taking some notes on areas of improvement.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-copy-study-notes-aca8bf19ed6d283e1dfa33cd26c4ca00.jpg" width="2004" height="3051" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You can see them side by side here:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-sidebyside-ae02cba9c1cdd34e990969cbd17a6147.jpg" width="3348" height="2193" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---watercolours">Day 4 - Watercolours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-4---watercolours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Watercolours" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Watercolours">​</a></h2>
<p>For day 4 I took it easy a bit by doing a physical watercolour pass on the inks I did previously. Mostly because I enjoy working with watercolours even if I’m not very skilled at them. Unfortunately my pens weren’t waterproof…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/raccoon-watercolour-f20d4e15d17665922fdb796bd105cab8.jpg" width="2254" height="3458" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Parts of it went okay while others got out of control rather quickly. But it was fun to do it physically after already doing the piece digitally.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---new-unique-piece-in-the-style">Day 5 - New unique piece in the style<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-5---new-unique-piece-in-the-style" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - New unique piece in the style" title="Direct link to Day 5 - New unique piece in the style">​</a></h2>
<p>For the last day I wanted to draw something new again. I did some thumbnailing and chose the parts of the style I definitely wanted to incorporate.</p>
<p>While most of the art for Root is small cards and mostly individual character pieces, I’ve been in full “scene” mode from working on the visual novel. So a background and multiple characters. Basically gave myself hard mode for the final. But I really enjoyed the ways of doing forest plants, I wanted to keep doing those.</p>
<p>I also didn’t let myself colour pick from an image and instead eye balled the colours to see how far off I would be. I don’t think any of the Root pieces do much foreground background stuff but I did darker a whole section to create some depth to the image. Trying to push the style a bit and also just bring in my own techniques for creating a scene.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-final-1e7ec3d2631398e70a5fcbb3b9b0f901.jpg" width="1691" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m pretty happy with the piece! Something I learned while working on it, while watching another Root art stream, was that Kyle works at very small sizes. He showed off the pens he used and it made me realize I’ve just been super over sizing everything. When I went to use my own pens my thoughts were “these are too small” when it turns out they were way too big. I didn’t imagine that he was working at such a small scale, but it makes filling in blacks so much easier when you are fighting to fill a whole page. Due to working at a larger size I also end up with a lot of empty space. Most of the Root pieces don't have much sky and I probably shouldn't have filled in more of the background with larger grasses and more trees.</p>
<p>Something learned from the interviews is that the colour palette and line work style for Root is chosen with a reason; communicating game state. The art pieces are meant to be easy to parse and understand at a glance thanks to high contrast, be that between lines, colours, or shapes. Something that I went against by darkening the foreground. I have the freedom of not drawing this fanart for a game but it's extremely interesting to learn why certain creative desicions are made for particular settings.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="resources">Resources<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#resources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Resources" title="Direct link to Resources">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m not the only person doing Kyle Ferrin or Root studies. I found one video on YouTube of another artist doing their best to replicate the style:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pfXEM3C8RZE?si=Qq0wve34b3kHabhh" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>The artist goes for a full digital approach which is what I did in my first attempt as well. I think it’s okay for a single character but the larger Root scenes with backgrounds and heavier inking feel like they really need a physical ink brush to capture the style properly.</p>
<p>I also found another person’s Root fanart over on Reddit that I really liked: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rootgame/comments/11kssrz/i_tried_to_recreate_the_root_artstyle_free_to_use/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I tried to recreate the Root artstyle!</a>. Their work also feels fully digital but I wasn’t able to find any active website or socials for them.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I feel like this was a very promising first style study. I’m happy with the pieces I produced for it and there are tricks here that I can see myself relying on to create more stylized backgrounds. It was a fun kind of investigation to really watch someone work and try to analyses their pieces. I’d also like to be able to draw my own lovable little guys but I think I still have more practice in that area to do. Downside to this study, I now want to buy all the Root games...</p>
<p>Find Kyle’s work at:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/d20plusmodifier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His Instagram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://kyleferrin.threadless.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His store</a></li>
<li>Check out other games Kyle has worked on at <a href="https://ledergames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leder Games</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve been very sick all this week so I might take it easy next week with a more classic WAP or even a week of focusing on some Littos bits and pieces.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="style study" term="style study"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 4]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4"/>
        <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going into the final week, I’ve done my (very likely) final pull request for art assets. Have done a few playthroughs of the game, hunting down any bugs. Between how hard we worked early in the month and our success at avoiding too much scope creep, we’re hoping to submit the game in the next day or two with a day to spare before the deadline.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Going into the final week, I’ve done my (very likely) final pull request for art assets. Have done a few playthroughs of the game, hunting down any bugs. Between how hard we worked early in the month and our success at avoiding too much scope creep, we’re hoping to submit the game in the next day or two with a day to spare before the deadline.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/week4-assets-a44526177e7b82fe90c539eedb7c2b4f.png" width="690" height="306" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I had pretty confidently thought I was done with backgrounds last week but while we were brainstorming final scenes it was clear having one more would help. This ended up launching a quick Clip Asset Store search, buying the CPS version update (I’ve been on v2.0 for years…) and hoping that nothing would break in the update.</p>
<p>It thankfully all went very smoothly and I got new Clip features to use out of it! And I drew I kitchen x_x Which I won’t share yet as it’s only for those who choose a specific ending.</p>
<p>It feels like we actually ended up with a lot of backgrounds for a game designed around lockdown. Helps that most of the characters live in the same building so I could keep the interior scenes consistent and reuse bits and pieces. As shown in this angled hallway shot that ties in with last week’s doorway shot. Didn’t think I’d be re-creating the wallpaper again and definitely had to re-learn the sequence of effects on it…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/apt_hallway-c18f38b48950bfc7225dbdeb22732071.png" width="1920" height="1280" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>But it also just became difficult to have emotional character scenes without giving the characters somewhere to go. And new backgrounds feel like game progression in this kind of game. Getting to see someone else’s apartment is both game progress and character relationship progress.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="assets">Assets<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Assets" title="Direct link to Assets">​</a></h2>
<p>Something I did in the last few days was do a shading pass on our 4 characters. I wasn’t sure I was going to have time when we started but I’m super happy it’s something I did in the end as it makes them fit into the scenes much better. The backgrounds all have shading so they look like part of the world by having their own shading.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-with-shading-12fcd9d61758433c7d6e3308a6616378.jpg" width="2035" height="798" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I also darkened Lauren’s skin tone to differentiate her more from Kim and show her wood nymph heritage.</p>
<p>Shading all the characters took about 2 days as I had to do each base differently and then jackets on top of bases.</p>
<p>I made an asset spread of all the Lauren pieces to show how few assets it takes to make what I feel like is a pretty expressive character.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-spread-4bf5cb11875f10c52cb67493953aa1d2.jpg" width="1500" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>When I was first brainstorming how to do the characters I had mentally mapped it as “draw a happy face” “draw a sad face” thinking that each expression would require a face. But after some VN research it was decided that the more efficient but more programmatically demanding way to do expressions was by working with multiple assets at once. So instead of a fully drawn happy face asset, a happy face was made out of: a smile + neutral eyes. While an angry face would be made out of: a frown + squinting eyes + angled brows. And then an embarrassed face could be: a frown + blush. Basically letting us remix different eye + mouth assets to create a lot more expressions than having to draw an individual face for each expression. I feel like this really worked out for us as whenever I play the game I’m tickled by how much the characters move from sentence to sentence (which is largely to do with my wife’s programming timing of them all).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s nearly time to package and upload the game to Itch! Some final fixes are going in and stress tested over the next 24 hours. Some issues are bound to have slipped through, it’s difficult to test every permutation of choices a player can make while going through the 2 days. So if you’re reading this and playing the game let us know if you see anything weird.</p>
<p>For me, next week is February so I’m back to smaller, weekly projects for art practice. With my first one being a style study of Kyle Ferrin, the board game artist of <a href="https://ledergames.com/products/root-a-game-of-woodland-might-and-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Root fame</a>. I also want to take some time next week and review all the assets I relied on for the game and share some of my favourites in their own blog post.</p>
<p>For LitToS, we’re probably going to take some time away from it and start looking for ways to make it a more sustainable project while lightly polishing what we have so far.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 3]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3"/>
        <updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s time for the week 3 summary. That’s 21 days of working on our game non-stop. Neither of us has taken a full day off since we started, doing probably 7-10 hours of work a day each (well, a little less for me on the days I go to my paying job). We’re still progressing at a nice pace but with more than half the month gone the to-do list feels a little scarier with each passing day.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s time for the week 3 summary. That’s 21 days of working on our game non-stop. Neither of us has taken a full day off since we started, doing probably 7-10 hours of work a day each (well, a little less for me on the days I go to my paying job). We’re still progressing at a nice pace but with more than half the month gone the to-do list feels a little scarier with each passing day.</p>
<p>The assets list increases a little every week. Last week there were 77 needed assets, this week ending at 82. Some of those are ‘nice-to-haves’ which I’m going to start tracking as stretch goals so they don’t contribute to the overall number necessary for launch.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/week3-assets-d1d625c1169c65f2f8d83ab25bb71c0f.png" width="766" height="272" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I was able to finish 2 huge bedrooms in the last 10 days. They were so intense for me that I felt so much relief when I opened a new canvas and could just bask in the emptiness of it. Managed a smaller, more abstract background for Day 2 in just a day, which felt nice and productive. After that I started to work on “end scenes” for the game. Visual novels often end on a unique art scene so we wanted some of those. Like the “reward” for finishing the game.</p>
<p>I was able to finish up one of the ending images pretty quickly and it’s one of the cutest things I’ve ever drawn. I want to post it online real bad but it’s basically a spoiler that I want people to first see in game. So in game it will stay for a few months.</p>
<p>This background doesn’t have any spoilers so check out this good wall. The door even opens! I was able to get this done pretty quickly as well thanks to some wood panelling assets and a wallpaper material from the Clip Store. It’s simple but I feel like it really sells the scene in engine.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/apt-hallway-60dd18c47ae85da352c215b090616311.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="assets">Assets<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Assets" title="Direct link to Assets">​</a></h2>
<p>Since I spent so much time populating a nerd room I ended up drawing a lot of Stuff to fill the room. Tried to give it a fair bit of character. This is my collection of Little Guys for Cass’s room.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/little-guys-swak-e1e808f2a5bf1399fcd960304a3e5180.jpg" width="573" height="410" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="making-a-montreal-like">Making a Montreal-like<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#making-a-montreal-like" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making a Montreal-like" title="Direct link to Making a Montreal-like">​</a></h2>
<p>The city in our game isn’t Montreal, but it’s got parts of Montreal with twists. It made sense to us to set the game in a city like Montreal since it’s where we live and we knew we could look around and find references easily. There are some clear Montreal landmarks that I used as reference for a few backgrounds so far.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/parc_vs_park-207490cd3ff50ae2b011d03bf4e350b9.jpg" width="3100" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This photo is my main inspiration for the park background. The statue changed into the amethyst obelisk and the cross on the mountain replaced by our magical school.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/outside-apartments-5a7e39ec887d61db18a27467d767b3a9.png" width="2648" height="1494" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The apartment front is based off of an apartment building where a friend lives.</p>
<p>The school in the game is called Crowstone and I used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ravenscrag,_Montreal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Montreal’s Ravenscrag manor</a> as inspiration. This manor turned psychiatric hospital (with an honestly very dark history that the Wiki page weirdly doesn’t mention) is a building near Mont Royal park but in the game I put it right on top of the hill to loom over the city. Making it visible in a few different backgrounds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ravenscrag-45977179a8df9a6a46f4e9f4fd2c843a.png" width="1454" height="832" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The street scene is also very Montreal, I would have loved to include the classic spiral staircases but I would have hated doing those in perspective. Also debated having a French stop sign but we decided against it since we don’t have any French in the game. And it is meant to be more of a fantasy world than the real world.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-day-89b3797c1dff066b134bb3b77cadb007.png" width="1280" height="724" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>There are a few other iconic Montreal features like churches everywhere, constant construction, random art installation, and great parks that I’d like to include in future backgrounds. Given the strong D&amp;D influence in our game world, churches would probably become temples to different gods, construction might be magic that works on its own. But each background takes me at least 2-4 days so we’ve really tried to limit our location in this first part of the game so these things won’t come up in the next version. But I’ll definitely be using more image inspiration like with the statue and hill photo reference because I’ve really enjoyed incorporating my everyday world into a fantasy story world.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m trying to wrap up the last art assets in the next 7 days so that we have a comfortable few days to implement everything and make sure it works before submitting the game to the jam. I’m feeling pretty confident about getting through the last needed art pieces but there’s still a lot of writing and other implementations to get done too.</p>
<p>Something I’m noticing for myself is that by spending so much time in the Creative Zone I find myself coming up with new ideas constantly. Not just art ideas but my other hobbies too. I want to do some video editing and make a trailer for the game. I have an idea for a level 1 intro adventure in D&amp;D. I want to work on my volunteer projects. I want to do art for the D&amp;D campaign I’m already running. And I recognize this feeling from my years doing NaNoWriMo. Part of it is longing for the thrill of a new project after being so intensely focused on a single one. Part of it is just that creative activity feeds creative energy. I’d love to say that I hope to carry this energy into February but there’s a solid chance I’ll crash and not want to touch my tablet for a while. I’ve started to get some back pain over the last few days so I’d like to give myself some rest time. So resting is my main plan for February 2nd, that and getting back into physio exercises.</p>
<p>You can still play Day 1 on our <a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/love-in-the-time-of-spellphage-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io page</a> for another week or so. We did a minor update after its first release to add a few more art assets and cat content. The current game will get replaced when we release Day 2 next week!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 2]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.</p>
<p>Not a huge change in the asset tracker as I wrapped up most of the small part and have spent the last 5 days in focused background mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/asset-tracking-week2-8ee3e007d5ece8383347068f29718aab.png" width="544" height="254" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="asset-creation">Asset creation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#asset-creation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Asset creation" title="Direct link to Asset creation">​</a></h2>
<p>Between backgrounds I was able to wrap up jackets (multiple forms for each character) for the 3 characters who can be seen outside on the first day of the game. Also designed this logo for an in-world restaurant:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/takeout-b8f96154c8d420e43885b0ac9bc6d3b6.png" width="254" height="300" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Drew a hand and a portal, multiple little cats. I really like doing these small one offs as I feel like I can experiment with them versus backgrounds which are way more demanding mentally. But since most of the small assets are done it’s been a pretty big week for background work.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I had a pretty terrible time with this street scene I worked on for 4 days.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-day-89b3797c1dff066b134bb3b77cadb007.png" width="1280" height="724" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m going to point out all the things wrong with it but I ask that you wipe the mistakes from your brain when you play the game.</p>
<p>I started fairly confidently, really loved the back line of buildings and managed to keep it mostly flat rectangles. Then I moved on to the right side of the street. Activated the perspective ruler and started to draw some buildings. It was decided that the eye line was too high and I told myself I would push all the lines down with the Transform tool once I had them done. But then I came back the next day and pushed them down and altered the perspective ruler and then started the left side. I didn’t realize how much I had altered the ruler by the time I was done with the lines on the left side. I kept returning to the right side, trying to push it down more, trying to fix the roof which I drew in after the shift because the top of the buildings didn’t exist in the first pass.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-perspective-lines-6337c03fc1bebab9261cb3c312117082.png" width="1282" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Something I had gotten good at for the first few days was Deleting My Art. A very common and helpful art tip. Didn’t like how a character was looking? Delete it. All the lines look bad? Delete them. There is learning to be taken from sticking with something incorrect and figuring out how to fix it, but I was mostly in ideation and discovery mode, so each deletion led to something better.</p>
<p>But as I feared with starting background, I fell into sunk cost fallacy and wasn’t willing to throw away 2 hours of work. The saving grace of the piece is that I am really happy with the left side buildings and the back row. It feels Montreal-esque without being too on the nose. And while I’m still struggling with colour selection in big pieces I don’t think there are too many mistakes.</p>
<p>I brought my fear into the next background I started and spent a lot of time in layout and perspective mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-room-measurements-f236e24903a38dbad90ab576bc982370.png" width="1281" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I am very happy with how main character Lauren’s room turned out. It doesn’t feel great to instantly jump into working on another character's bedroom but I’m hoping I can take what I learned from Lauren’s room and move a little faster. Lauren’s room took about 10 hours… I ended up downloading a lot of 3D objects from the Clip Studio Asset store which let me feel like I was playing with toys as I chose where to place them and size them.</p>
<p>I have 2-3 backgrounds to go, even if they all take 3 days each, which leaves me some wiggle room to revisit art pieces from earlier in the month and adding more details.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="version-01-launch">Version 0.1 launch<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#version-01-launch" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch" title="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch">​</a></h2>
<p>While conceptualizing our game we designed it around 7 days that the player would play through. When making a branching game, a solid rule is to build your Golden Path first. This can be your “happy” ending path, or the path you think most players will enjoy or gravitate towards.</p>
<p>Since our game is a romance sim it would mean choosing one of the love interests and completing their path before anyone else's. This proved difficult in a pretty big way in that one of the central parts of a romance sim is being able to choose who you romance. We worried that having one obviously foregrounded character would give the wrong vibe.</p>
<p>I kept pushing for finding a Golden Path during the build up week before the game as I’m familiar with watching new game makers spiral out of scope and get lost in the weeds. We talked it over multiple times, thinking about how the game breaks up in other ways. Just a day or two before the jam started we had the realization that if we wanted something that felt like a full game, we could scope by days instead of paths. We scoped down pretty drastically, to the first 2 days of the story. The major downside being that this scoping didn’t help with scoping down of asset requirements as we would still need art for each character and location.</p>
<p>And while this did mean rushing through as much art as possible in the first few days, I think this scope is what’s to credit for us being able to publish Day 1 as version 0.1 before the end of week two.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/littos-itch-3314046c65231a7437bbcbe7c4daffa5.png" width="2840" height="1404" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You can play Day 1 on our <a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/love-in-the-time-of-spellphage-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io page</a> however I do recommend downloading a version instead of playing in the browser as you’ll have a better audio and performance experience that way. We’ve gotten some positive feedback from friends already and possibly some Beta Tester who are strangers to us and have fewer reasons to be nice to us <!-- -->:o</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>The next big thing for the project is writing Day 2. We have some ideas on these scenes but it will likely be a fair bit of brainstorming still. For myself, I’ll likely be in background mode for the next week as we don’t even know all the scenes or locations we’ll need for Day 2 yet...</p>
<p>We’re also hoping to get feedback during week 3 and incorporate anything actionable before the end of the month.</p>
<p>It’s likely to be another focused week and I already feel myself longing to do art that doesn’t involve a perspective ruler. But feeling very accomplished in what we've been able to make so far!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 1]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New year new projects, starting with the Sealed With a Kiss game jam. My wife and I started work on the project bright and early on January first. With just a few days of vacation left I wanted to get as many assets done as I could before returning to work on Monday. Which has led to creating more art in a few days than any period last year.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New year new projects, starting with the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/swakjam-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sealed With a Kiss game jam</a>. My wife and I started work on the project bright and early on January first. With just a few days of vacation left I wanted to get as many assets done as I could before returning to work on Monday. Which has led to creating more art in a few days than any period last year.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/asset_tracking-842fa416ab5722a9e8be004a7fc5696c.png" width="1230" height="406" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The speed won’t last though. I got through most of the character art but now I’m mostly left with backgrounds and I probably won’t be able to get through more than one of those every few days. So far 5-8 hours seems like the average time they requires. But we’ll see how the next week goes, for now, it’s recap time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="asset-creation">Asset creation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#asset-creation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Asset creation" title="Direct link to Asset creation">​</a></h2>
<p>We had the basics of our game flow and story figured out before we started so I was able to get a pretty solid list of “to-do” work ready before day one. Characters were the priority as they take more than just drawing time but also programming time. So if I could get the characters done quickly it would give my wife more time to work with them in Ren’py.</p>
<p>I was able to get basic sketches down for each of the 4 main characters on day one which felt like an accomplishment and was already faster than I had planned for.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/character_sketches-07804267e8c9a5ff1c866a1f8d9a05d2.png" width="1607" height="691" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Aside from characters and backgrounds we also had some smaller assets that were needed. A wand for our energy mechanic, a large book for light novel scenes. It’s unlikely that we’ve reached the end of assets and new ones will continue to arise over the next few weeks. The asset tracker Total has already increased since I took that screenshot...</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="characters">Characters<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#characters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Characters" title="Direct link to Characters">​</a></h2>
<p>After the first sketches I let the characters sit for a day before returning to them. Art Director Wife wanted our main character to look a little more "student struggling" so I spent time revisiting her. Other characters had smaller fixes up I worked on during second passes. 7 days in and I think we have most of the final details for our cast.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/character_flats-bac79168f3041e09ce377b4460d33f31.png" width="1610" height="696" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Their designs are a mix of D&amp;D inspo meets Montreal in the 80s. I spent a fair bit of time scrolling through 80s fashion and trying to find a unique look for each of them. But then I remembered we set the story in December so everyone needs a jacket layer for being outside :| The scope just keeps growing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I haven’t done too much work on backgrounds yet but I have made the promising discovery of the default Pointillism brush in CSP. We had envisioned a slightly more abstract or impressionistic backgrounds and I wasn’t sure how to approach this. I spent a decent amount of time just testing brushes to find something pleasing to work with and look at. It’s worked for the one background that has a lot of plants and snow, now I’ll just hope it can hold up in backgrounds that have more buildings.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ao_day-819a6c377ba9cf8382836a9c138b5c96.png" width="1281" height="722" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Indoor scenes will be another whole thing. I don’t think pointillism will work as well there so I expect a decent amount of trial and error. So far I only have this computer background which still needs a fair bit of work but I wanted to get it in early since it’s a big part of the game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/computer_background-22481a10e68c6dfe174a7a26f3eade09.png" width="1924" height="1082" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>An additional added goal to backgrounds is having a day and night version of each scene. Ren’py has some shaders which can be applied to backgrounds and images on top of backgrounds which give a lot of options. But for outdoor scenes I’m going to try to do 2 versions of each:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ao_park_both-04ca40e0f3824ec7f9fdda1e074d619f.png" width="3840" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Also, a huge shout out to the Clip Studio Asset store. Everyone sharing assets is saving me hours of work, just some great stuff in there.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-game-so-far">The game so far<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#the-game-so-far" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The game so far" title="Direct link to The game so far">​</a></h2>
<p>While I’ve been fully focused on art assets my wife has been tackling everything else about the game. Launch screen, writing, sound effects, menus, energy mechanic, multiple text areas, music, assigning assets. Basically just everything.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/launch_screen-aa934a9db9f0cc4a691a37a942142e3a.png" width="2690" height="1496" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>As of today, the 8th, we’re almost done with day 1 of gameplay/story. This means written scenes and mechanics. There are still some missing key backgrounds, like our main character's room. We have some placeholder graphics in there currently for those. Once we have day 1 story all in place we’ll start sharing the game with some folks and try to get some feedback in hopes of actioning it before we get too far into day 2!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/day-1-activities-ca8d49e4832cc3c23f2be7ddfa3dfd37.png" width="2648" height="1490" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WAP Up]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year in review of my weekly art practice]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first launched into this goal of practicing art in a focused fashion every week I wasn’t sure I’d be able to maintain it. I also wasn’t sure if it was going to be a practice that would lead to noticeable improvements. Just drawing every day isn’t enough to keep getting better, so I was really relying on the focused methodology of practice flow to pay off.</p>
<p>Given my last 2 weeks of revisits, my new found near comfort drawing hands, and lack of fear of the blank page, I feel like it has. I did end up drawing mostly animals as a comfort zone, but then expanded my focus halfway through the year to include anatomy weeks to make sure I was still continuing to work on the fundamentals. Then in the last few months I tried to add the goal of completing a finished piece once a month as well. Easily making it my most productive art year in a decade.</p>
<p>Cara, the social media platform for artists, took off this year. I didn’t post all my finished work there but almost all these pieces are from this year:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/cara_2024-4eb6af427437f723325e7ca9667c2714.png" width="1080" height="1423" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I only posted a few of my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone backgrounds</a> there, the rest mostly only ever being posted to YouTube.</p>
<p>The best part is that I don’t feel burnt out on art. I didn’t have anyone to answer too, didn’t have many projects that took more than a week or two. Sure there were definitely days I wasn’t keen to do more WAP practice pieces, but every day I still wanted to try to find the time to do something.
Weekly Art Practice Subjects:
All my weekly themes in a list. This is mostly to create an easy way for me to find the ones I want in the future.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">1-10</th><th style="text-align:left">11-20</th><th style="text-align:left">21-30</th><th style="text-align:left">31-40</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Squirrels</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-11" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Books</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Waltz</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-31" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flowers</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pangolins</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-12" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Giant anteater</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Me</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-32" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon Hidden Ability Challenge</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pigeons</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-13" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Figure skating</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Skulls</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-33" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Swimming</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hands</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hawk</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-24" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sparrow</a></td><td style="text-align:left">Style study - <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-34" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon trainer</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hairstyles</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-15" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Penguin</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-25" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gymnastics</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Horses</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Goblins</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-16" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hyena</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Griffin</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-36" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bats</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rabbits</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Volleyball</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-27" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Material studies</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-37" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Running</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Landscapes</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-18" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sea turtle</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-28" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-38" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bicycle</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trees</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chameleon</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Horseback riding</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-39" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Revisit 1</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sword swing</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redraw (Butterfly girl)</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-30" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sugar glider</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Revisit 2</a></td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="beyond-the-wap">Beyond the WAP<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#beyond-the-wap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Beyond the WAP" title="Direct link to Beyond the WAP">​</a></h2>
<p>For a few of the weekly studies I did end up pushing the subject matter beyond the basic 5 days. For week 4’s Hands I ended up using those hands in an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fBSK7HGX5Nc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone video</a>. The Goblin from week 6 has been turned into an animated gif, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/lpQ1jxd11gk?si=6_Cmi73tp87CkN_3&amp;t=6860" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">critiqued on a Drawclass</a>, and animated in Godot. I used the Me piece on the About page on this website. After doing a Pokemon trainer of myself I also <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kymira.ca/post/3lbwsojqvw223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">made one of my wife</a>.</p>
<p>I think practicing can feel like it’s “going nowhere” when you don’t have finished pieces you’re proud of. If I look through my blog posts it does just feel like a bunch of messy sketches and those don’t have “a use”. But this is from productivity brainrot of everything you do needs to lead to something or produce something and a big part of taking on a creative project for me was to get away from that mindset. In 2023 when I spent the year doing 21 Draw classes I felt like I didn’t have much to show for all the class time I put in. This year I have physical sketchbooks and multiple iPads filled with everything I’ve been doing. But I still want more “finished” pieces not so much to have something to show for my time but because there’s only parts of art that you get to after the sketch phase. And this year has been a lot of the sketch phase.</p>
<p>It’s easy to forget that I was also making animated backgrounds for Altar Stone for 10 months of the year. And working on some side pieces that I just felt inspired to do.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ikto-elden-5b1023d6835fdf3eb3cd1b84fee581b9.png" width="2600" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="courses">Courses<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#courses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Courses" title="Direct link to Courses">​</a></h2>
<p>While 2023 had been about trying to take as many 21 Draw courses as I could, I didn’t focus on courses this year. I’m at the Drawclass level of the Drawfee Patreon which means one, 2 hour course every month which has been a nice way to mix up art practice as it’s often on something I’m not focusing on myself.</p>
<p>Like Julia’s room class:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-interiors-49f8e1658268e0c908ce0a887b4311c5.jpg" width="3500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>And Karina’s dynamic pose class:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-dynamicposes-1-6ddc3450e6f464d3e1a305907435fd74.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-dynamicposes-2-ed1b0a04f7a9c0033c2948f10cb81c87.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I spent some time looking at Domestika and did buy a map drawing course because I thought it would be a nice skill to develop for making D&amp;D locations. But I only ended up getting a few hours in before bouncing off it. Maybe I can revisit it during the winter holidays.</p>
<p>My favourite course of the year was probably Spencer Wan’s 2D visual effects course. It was a very intense 3(4?) hours but covered techniques I’d never seen before and really made a case for being an animator who specializes in effects. It felt like a course I could instantly take lessons from and apply them to Altar Stone videos. I shared my notes from it in my WAP 24 post (sparrows).</p>
<p>My course consumption will probably remain similar in 2025, Drawfee classes every month and a few one-offs here and there as they come up.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2025">2025<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#2025" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2025" title="Direct link to 2025">​</a></h2>
<p>I mentioned in one blog post already that I’m starting the year off by doing a game jam with my wife. I suspect it will be a rather big challenge, even while trying to keep the scope reasonable, so I won’t be doing any other art projects during the month.</p>
<p>In February I’m going to try to do a style study of a select artist (I’ve been putting together a list of artists I’d like to learn from). I’ve really been enjoying watching style study videos on YouTube and I’ll try to follow a similar format of how <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@thomoclock" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thom O'Clock</a> does his Render Breakdown series. I found his video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abHLAgvhUGs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the art style of Hades</a> very inspiring both in process and execution. These types of things seem decently effortful and intimidating so I’m setting my goals of doing 1 style study a month.</p>
<p>Another idea I have for a week-long project is a little less structured. I’ve created 3 Pinterest boards for the year, one is a collection of interesting looking places, one a collection of characters I like, and another for colour schemes I’d like to try. Once a month I’m going to randomly choose a piece from each Pinboard by rolling dice and then combing the character in the location while using the selected colour scheme. This is a bit of practice for learning to draw from references, to try to develop more environmental design skills and also work with colours I wouldn’t likely choose on my own.</p>
<p>I feel like anatomy studies are still important to keep in the rotation, and there are some WAP themes I wish I had thought of earlier. So I think my 2025 months might look something like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Week 1: Style Study</li>
<li>Week 2: Anatomy Week</li>
<li>Week 3: 3 Board Challenge</li>
<li>Week 4: Classic WAP</li>
</ul>
<p>I don’t yet know how much effort style study weeks or Pinterest style pieces will take. So I may need to simplify my schedule in the future. What made WAP so doable was that it was the same rotation every week. I found ways to make some days easier over time from doing it over and over again. Not sure I’ll have enough repeats to learn faster techniques for these new challenges but I'm excited to get started.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books - 2024 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Books I read in 2024]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was able to stick to my 1 book a month goal this year, squeezing in 2 extras. This was my first year of really seriously using the ebook library app, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libby_(service)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Libby</a>, since I was able to get it to finally sync with my Kobo. This makes for really random book consumption as what you’re reading at any time completely depends on when holds come in. But it also cutely led to me and my wife reading a lot of the same books.</p>
<p>In the last few years I’ve had a bit of focus to my book selection. For a while I wanted to wrap up all the series I had started. And then for a few years I had a growing number of water focused novels I wanted to read. I no longer have any large goals like that and am actually out there trying to find new authors to follow or catch up on. With the death of Twitter I no longer follow as many writers and readers so my to-read list hasn’t been growing all that quickly. The only serious source I go to for new stuff is <a href="https://kadoore.com/2024/12/14/2024-queer-adult-science-fiction-fantasy-books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">K. A. Doore’s yearly roundup of Queer Adult Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy Books</a>. I’m hoping library access will help make discovery easier going forward, but it’s a real shame how barely usable Libby is. An insult to app designers and librarians everywhere.</p>
<p>But on to the books. I tried writing this blog post a few times but found it was hard to talk about each one. So here are my top 3 and also my scoring (out of 3) for the rest.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/top-books-2024-0ce6b6d5aad599d458c35444a95668c3.jpg" width="2415" height="1200" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="floating-hotel-by-grace-curtis">Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#floating-hotel-by-grace-curtis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis" title="Direct link to Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Floating Hotel</strong> was a surprise read of this year, I wouldn’t have read it if it weren’t for my wife hyping it up. It’s kind of a cozy murder mystery in space. Its setting and writing are cozy while the characters and central story are more dramatic. A high end hotel well past its prime, travels between planets hosting celebrities and the rich. It’s also a home to its staff, outcasts who can’t return to their world or people running from their past. There’s also a whole evil emperor and repressive education system thing going on but that’s not really what things are about (but also is).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="he-who-drowned-the-world-by-shelley-parker-chan">He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#he-who-drowned-the-world-by-shelley-parker-chan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan" title="Direct link to He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>He Who Drowned The World</strong> is the sequel and conclusion to She Who Became the Sun. These two books are a powerful duo and have probably one of my favourite leading characters ever. The duology is rather violent and graphic which makes me hesitate to recommend it to people. But the main character is so driven and the villains merciless. So much backstabbing and betrayal but also loyalty and commitment to people and causes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-by-becky-chambers">A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-by-becky-chambers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers" title="Direct link to A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers">​</a></h2>
<p>It was nice to return to Becky Chambers after a few years. I loved her first 3 books but then I started to fall behind on her one-off releases. I really only got around to this one because our hold came up at the library. Compared to her other novels, which often take place in space, this one is set on a single planet (which I don’t think is earth) where the people are recovering from near disaster. They had accidentally created AI. The society had been supported by robot labour for a long time, and then the robots gained sentience and they didn’t want to labour for humans so they walked into the woods to disappear for a few decades. Just from that premise I was intrigued. Love the idea of a population of robots just peacing off to the woods, a common millennial wish.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rest">The rest<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#the-rest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The rest" title="Direct link to The rest">​</a></h2>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Book</th><th style="text-align:left">Thoughts</th><th style="text-align:left">Rating out of 3</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Siren Queen by Nghi Vo</td><td style="text-align:left">Historical rise of movies in a slightly magical world where making deals with a devil figure is the norm. Not nearly as many sirens as I was hoping for, way too slow and prose-y for me.</td><td style="text-align:left">1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Squid Empire by  Danna Staaf</td><td style="text-align:left">Non-fiction book about squid. Lots of good facts but I didn’t love the overall structure and flow.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Water Outlaws by S.L. Huang</td><td style="text-align:left">A decent alt-history &amp; magic adventure story. Has some similar vibes to things like She Who Became the Sun or The Poppy War but way less brutal.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Flux by Jinwoo Chong</td><td style="text-align:left">Had no idea what this was when I got into it. Was more sci-fi than expected and I liked how the main character was grappling with their childhood hero being exposed as a terrible guy.</td><td style="text-align:left">3</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Blood Ink Sister Scribe by Emma Törzs</td><td style="text-align:left">A fun adventure about magical books and those who can do magic. Got your classic rich boy and bodyguard duo, family members who haven’t spoken in years, and many, many family secrets.</td><td style="text-align:left">3</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Bookeaters by Sunyi Dean</td><td style="text-align:left">I was surprised at how dark this one started off for a book about a secret group of people who need to eat books to live.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Perséphone Station by Stina Leicht</td><td style="text-align:left">Ragtag team of ex-soliders protects secret, peaceful aliens. There was a lot of world building going on here that I wish the author showed more of in the story. But a solid space adventure overall.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Archive Undying by Emma Mieko Candon</td><td style="text-align:left">Huge robots are gods and human interfaces are needed to… feed them? Control them? Power them? A very cool world but I wish the story had been divided into 2 books because So Much Happens.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Cat Who Saves Books by Sosuke Natsukawa</td><td style="text-align:left">Kobo kept recommending this one to me so I finally bought it. Cute but a little childish and simple. I’m kind of confused about who the intended audience is as it features high schoolers who go into alternative worlds to defend the value of books. The arguments are fairly basic but I think meant to be taken like a big deal.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Familiar by Leigh Bardugo</td><td style="text-align:left">I worry I have too high of expectations for Bardugo as I haven’t really liked what she’s done since Six of Crows. This was well done but felt more formulaic than her previous work. Wanted it to be a book about women surviving men but still ended with what I felt was a boring couple.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Light from Uncommon Stars by Ryka Aoki</td><td style="text-align:left">A bit wild in its combo of student sacrifices and aliens who are running away from a cataclasm that threatens to end the known universe who are now running a doughnut shop. But its development and execution put it rather firmly in the “nothing really bad will happen here” camp.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Demon Haunted World by Carl Sagan and Ann Druyan</td><td style="text-align:left">Another non-fiction, but I didn’t finish this one as it was just way too long.</td><td style="text-align:left">Did not finish.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Hum by Helen Phillips</td><td style="text-align:left">So while I hated the ending (like a 2 page epilogue that nearly ruined the whole book for me. Just don’t read the epilogue maybe?), this book did grip me from the start due to the way the main character acted and just had me on edge the whole time. Doesn’t deserve to be called an “AI” book but does say some stuff about the current state of the world.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I rated a lot of the books a 2, and looking back on the year, it fits. There were few like, standout, amazing books that I read this year. But there was a general good enough consistency which helped me keep up my reading pace.</p>
<p>There were a lot of robots in books this year and I suspect that will continue as everyone is writing about AI now. I really loved the books I read in the last like 7ish years that had central AI plots or characters but now it feels a bit more like the “trendy thing” and I suspect the median quality of AI stories will be lower. And with Muderbot being turned into a TV series I worry more.</p>
<p>The other night I started reading To Shape a Dragon's Breath by Moniquill Blackgoose and I saw that there were 2 other books on the K.A. Doore list that mentioned dragons so now I’m kind of hoping 2025 is about dragon books. Feel those nostalgic Dragonriders of Pern feelings. Though I should probably assume that a new dragon trend is more likely brought about from Game of Thrones / House of the Dragon being huge TV hits. But as a kid who grew up obsessed with dragons, it’s always nice to see more of them.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="books" term="books"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 40]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40"/>
        <updated>2024-12-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 40 - Revisits]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WAP 40, the final WAP of 2024!</p>
<p>This is another week of revisiting animal subjects of the last year. I even tried to embrace slightly more cartoony looks for them. Really kind of trying to put my brain on auto-pilot and seeing what comes out. I went and included side by sides for each day as I realized that seeing the comparison was really what I was doing these 2 weeks for.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---sea-turtles">Day 1 - Sea turtles<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-1---sea-turtles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Sea turtles" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Sea turtles">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.1-c00802e98a5d212f91118f7089bab7d8.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.1.2-3157872e309a13de7b3c30e091122e91.jpg" width="3000" height="1200" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---chameleons">Day 2 - Chameleons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-2---chameleons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Chameleons" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Chameleons">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.2-4a8e4fa30c54e020be7b088501267a20.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.2.2-6cf42ce07b809b7f31a31f7b61a09d87.jpg" width="3000" height="1007" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---sparrows">Day 3 - Sparrows<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-3---sparrows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Sparrows" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Sparrows">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.3-79af39d5c46ad17bff9d664d8e9b8d67.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.3.2-82f84aeae9f678838f02bf2f1117b925.jpg" width="3000" height="1104" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---raccoons">Day 4 - Raccoons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-4---raccoons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Raccoons" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Raccoons">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.4-ccf692dec234bb2897f2f59f5cc5fa6e.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.4.2-0f137ecfc082de5bc798e10b563e4122.jpg" width="3000" height="1100" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---bats">Day 5 - Bats<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-5---bats" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Bats" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Bats">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.5-43c2276e2bad41b11d9c50581328fe17.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.5.2-daa051dbeefcff34e75a0d87cc81d828.jpg" width="3000" height="1105" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>And that’s the end of the year of WAPs. I’m happy I did these last 2 weeks as revisits, it’s reassuring that some of the things I learned from those weeks seem to have stuck around. It’s been an interesting year and I’m pretty proud of sticking with it. Even ended up blogging every week’s efforts which I hadn’t planned on being able to do, it didn’t feel like something I could keep up with at the start of the year. Having spent the last 2 weeks re-reading those old posts I do regret not writing more during the exercises. It would have been nice to return to a list of key features to focus on for each creature.</p>
<p>I’m putting together a summary post about my WAP year and art efforts for the year in general, which I hope to put up before returning to work.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video games - 2024 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Games I played in 2024]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I tried to break games down into what I loved and what was okay. This year I’m going to try organizing things a little differently. I liked a lot of games this year. Made a dent in my backlog, played some of the top regarded games of the year, and a lot of them were hits with me. So this will probably read like a long list of game recommendations.</p>
<p>Unlike your typical 'Best Of' list, I’m starting with my top games of the year instead of saving them for the end. Why make the people wait. Or read.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/top-games-2024-c51f0d4204245645393439f24b0b22c5.jpg" width="2500" height="908" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><strong>Cobalt Core</strong> was a very early game in the year for me. It came out in November 2023 so I wasn’t too far from release when I picked it up. It’s a deck builder disguised as a ship builder roguelike. I was almost turned off of it once I realized how many playthroughs were needed to unlock the full ending but the gameplay kept bringing me back. And eventually I found a rather consistent ship build that got me wins 70% of the time. The art is rather cutesy but I thought it had great humour and writing.</p>
<p>Probably don’t need to say much about the <strong>Elden Ring DLC</strong> since I had put Elden Ring in my top games last year. But for me I think I got a more true Elden Ring experience in the DLC than I did in the main game. I had watched my wife play through Elden Ring before I really got hooked so there wasn’t much mystery for me and I kind of just focused on the main line and one build. In the DLC I explored (nearly) every nook and cranny, going for a near completionist run without really trying. Just felt fully In It. People still complain about the DLC’s use of Shadowseeds as necessary for progressing in the game power-wise but I find their complaints unjustified and thought it was actually a clever way to reward exploration and not rushing through. While also not taking away your powers since many people were coming into the DLC after beating the main game.</p>
<p><strong>Return of the Obra Dinn</strong> was one that has been on my to-play list since it came out. But I didn’t love the visual style so I hesitated. Wanting to play more games on my Switch this year because I could then play games in the bath, I finally got it. And then played it for nearly 6 hours straight. Excellent mystery design, such a unique progression, so much UI design making it playable. Instantly became a game I encourage everyone to play.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="puzzlers">Puzzlers<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#puzzlers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Puzzlers" title="Direct link to Puzzlers">​</a></h2>
<p>So I said I was going to try to break things down a little differently. Mostly because there have been so many good games this year but they’ve all been very different styles. Obra Dinn wasn’t my first puzzle game of the year, I started with <strong>Cocoon,</strong> one of the top games from 2023. I loved how straightforward Cocoon was, how it made you feel just clever enough. While also giving you very minimal storytelling, you mostly went on vibes. I also like to describe it as a game for people who want to ponder over some orbs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="The meme of a wizard gazing at an orb but the orb has been replaced by the Cocoon orb within an orb." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ponder-orb-09bd382092436d5e6c7866bb66cc6b28.jpg" width="1244" height="750" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><strong>Animal Well</strong> was a more search-action platform puzzler. Another really unique style, interesting game play, but the extensive puzzles going levels deep was too much for me. I still think the game is great and I recommend it for people and tell them it feels good even just reaching the first credits. But I would have loved to have the experience of playing it at the same time as friends and sharing discoveries and maybe trying to figure out some of the more obtuse secrets.</p>
<p>Another one from the backlog was <strong>Chants of Sennaar</strong>. I don’t feel like this game ever got much hype but it was talked about on a gaming podcast I listen to and I was rather taken with the art style when I looked it up. The central game mechanic is deciphering languages used by different castes in a society so that you can try to figure out what’s going on. It has a similar game feel as Obra Dinn, where you are dragging and dropping your answers to the puzzles into menu slots. Which honestly, is probably where they got the design idea from and where the next game, <strong>The Case of the Golden Idol</strong>, likely got inspiration from too.</p>
<p>Golden Idol is a series of scenes, each containing mysteries you piece together through a bit of point and click investigating. It was really fun, and deployed a hint system that was enough to help me with a puzzle whenever I got stuck. I really like that as a mechanic because even though every game has been walkthrough to death online, it’s really nice to not pick up your phone and look for help and just be able to stay in the game.</p>
<p>I would honestly recommend all these games, I felt like they were all unique and all offered something a little different.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gatchas">Gatchas<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#gatchas" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Gatchas" title="Direct link to Gatchas">​</a></h2>
<p>While <strong>Genshin Impact</strong> is still my main gatcha game (I still play nearly every day), I tested the waters of a few others this year.</p>
<p><strong>Zenless Zone Zero</strong> is the newest Mihoyo game, one I was pretty excited for after years of small teases. I ended up only playing for 2 days before deciding it wasn’t really for me. I liked the character design, I liked the combat, but the general execution of being more locked into quests after the open world freedom of Genshin felt very restrictive. But I also knew it would want as much time as Genshin does and it’s hard to balance multiple huge games like that at the same time.</p>
<p>For a little over a month my wife and I played <strong>AFK Journey</strong>. This was also a time sink but it was when I wanted to get off Twitter so I was trying to get into the habit of opening games on my phone instead of opening brain numbing apps. It was fun while it lasted but didn’t have the staying power of Genshin to keep us coming back.</p>
<p>There are two gatchas that are staying a little better. <strong>Pokemon TCG Pocket</strong>, a game that’s mostly focused on giving you that “pulls” feeling. As it does give you 2 pulls every day without you having to do anything besides login. If this wasn’t such a strong IP I don’t think this game would last but it takes minimal time commitment and I love looking at Pokemon.</p>
<p>The other is <strong>Infinity Nikki</strong> which I thought I’d play for a week and then bounce but I’m now on week 3 or so and have basically embraced it as my killing time while tired game while waiting for the next big Genshin content drop. Infinity Nikki is very unique in its focus on fashion and story over combat, and I do love playing dress-up. But I will be surprised if I stick with this game longer than winter break.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="not-good-enough-at">Not good enough at<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#not-good-enough-at" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Not good enough at" title="Direct link to Not good enough at">​</a></h2>
<p>I consider myself pretty good at video games. I have what I consider decent reflexes and hand eye coordination for my age, enjoy puzzle solving and also believe in having to put the time in to get good at something. So I find it rare that I bounce off a game because I’m just not getting it. But it happened twice this year.</p>
<p>One was for <strong>Pacific Drive</strong>, a game I was very excited about because I loved some of its early trailers. But after multiple failed journeys in my car, and having to re-do missions over and over again, I just lost motivation. I felt like I was missing a key understanding for being able to get through even early missions. I saw some other people online with a similar complaint, and they were mostly told to “get good”. Others suggested that there were a few difficulty settings that can be changed. So if I do ever return to this I’d probably turn those on and try to enjoy the mystery of the world more.</p>
<p><strong>Rollderdrome</strong> was the other game I put down. I’d heard lots of good things about it and was super intrigued by the game player and weird setting, but I didn’t love the game feel. And the fact that you just went match to match without much going on between challenges meant I didn’t have much to latch onto besides the game play.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rest">The rest<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#the-rest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The rest" title="Direct link to The rest">​</a></h2>
<p>Okay I tried being organized but there are only a few left and they don’t really fit in a nice category.</p>
<p><strong>Dave the Diver</strong>, one of last year's huge breakouts. I had a lot of fun with this and was blown away by the pixel art. I put a lot of time into it even though it got rather repetitive and honestly killing fish over and over again didn’t feel great. But it had such addictive pacing.</p>
<p><strong>Night in the Woods</strong> was my only VN-esque game this year. A famously beloved indie darling that is very well executed and had a twist I didn’t see coming. It was also a nice length with good writing overall. Which is why it often came up in my game circles since I spend a lot of time talking about storytelling and writing in games. So I knew I had to get to this one eventually and I’m happy I finally did.</p>
<p>And I replayed <strong>Hades</strong>. I had a strong urge to start playing early access Hades 2 but when trying to balance how much time you play video games versus other things I didn’t want to put 30 hours into Hades 2 knowing I would likely put in those same 30 hours on the full release. So I will keep trying to avoid any spoilers for Hades 2 and just hope that it gets a full release soon.</p>
<p>This feels a bit like a ridiculous amount of games to play in a year, but most of them were nice, reasonably sized experiences. The puzzlers were in the 5-12 hours of gameplayer area. Dave the Diver and Elden Ring were probably the only games I put in over 30 hours. I’ve just really come to enjoy a video game that I can start playing on a Friday evening and wrap it up by Sunday evening. Just a nice weekend experience.</p>
<p>I do have a list of games I’d like to play in 2025 and I think most should also be in the smaller game category. Which does make me curious for what huge game will be able to grab me next, as there’s nothing on my radar for releases in 2025 that seems like a contender. Unless Hades 2 does a surprise drop...</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 39]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39"/>
        <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 39 - Revisits 1]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For these last 2 WAP weeks, I decided to change it up. For each of the days I would revisit one of the themes I had done in the previous 38 WAPs. I didn’t want this to be extra extra hard mode or anything, I just wanted to see how much of what I took out of those weeks stuck around. So I let myself re-read the original blog post and scroll through the Pintrest page of images before I settled in to do some drawing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---squirrels">Day 1 - Squirrels<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-1---squirrels" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Squirrels" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Squirrels">​</a></h2>
<p>Still love squirrels, happy to revisit them. They were my <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">very first WAP</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.1-c41b74dfca4d6130ea2f4ead0627e7bd.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Then compare the day 5 from squirrel week to this iteration 50 weeks later.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.1.2-013bfef92ddecb4898d9b9af4d1749fa.jpg" width="2500" height="908" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---pangolin">Day 2 - Pangolin<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-2---pangolin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Pangolin" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Pangolin">​</a></h2>
<p>Pangolins still very cute and still very tiresome to draw all the scales. Pangolins are from <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 2</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.2-631bcc9910ae7dd570dd17d2056fdf3b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---pigeons">Day 3 - Pigeons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-3---pigeons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Pigeons" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Pigeons">​</a></h2>
<p>Went a little more cartoony for pigeons. Did them back in <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 3</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.3-2a5e9dc30723260aee5de5383dbaf6d7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---rabbits">Day 4 - Rabbits<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-4---rabbits" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Rabbits" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Rabbits">​</a></h2>
<p>Hard to resist just drawing big circles of fur for rabbits still. Another early one from <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 7</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.4-537ec703c707d339d19ff0ae0b545c19.jpg" width="2500" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---hawks">Day 5 - Hawks<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-5---hawks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Hawks" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Hawks">​</a></h2>
<p>Still can’t drawk hawks in a way I love but these did come out pretty quickly and I don’t hate them. First pass at hawks was in <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 14</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.5-7318701c2a20f8052bf14b30db6b9176.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m happy with this being how I’m wrapping up the year long WAP project. It was fun to revisit the work I had done earlier in the year, and feels a little unreal to compare those weeks to the work done now. Interesting to see how my sketching style has changed and just feeling like my lines have gotten more confident.</p>
<p>I’ll be doing the same thing for next week, week 40, the final WAP. Besides that I’m putting together posts on my favourite books and video games of 2024 like I did last year. And then I’ll put together a big post as a bit of an art retrospective hopefully before the new year.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 38]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38"/>
        <updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 38 - Bikes]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the end of the year approached I thought it was time to tackle a theme I’d been avoiding. There are 3 subjects that are often either ridiculed or acknowledged as being weirdly difficult to draw. Hands, horses, bikes. These likely aren’t the hardest for everyone but they come up and have been on my mind since starting this year long project. At the start of the year I did hands, just a few weeks ago horses, so it felt like it was time to stop avoiding bikes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Pretty awful. I see bikes probably every single day, Montreal is a very active bike city, but it’s not enough for me to summon up bikes clearly in my mind.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.1-e723a3f375d7ae3d8cbcc76064390a93.jpg" width="2870" height="938" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Day two saw improvements quickly just by being able to look at some photos. However, a quick discovery: not that many exciting photos of bikes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.2-2989f2dc938e435f2b3ab2a8fc5d6c7d.jpg" width="2841" height="1834" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>The realization from day 2 was quickly apparent on day 3, the photos aren’t exciting and drawing bikes… also not exciting. Is drawing bikes hard because imagining a bike isn’t fun? I really had to push myself to just start working on bikes each day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.3.1-eab7633d5b5ac07c8b921d80e1284ce0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.3.2-e1cc81b66cc950d120d65005211553e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Things got a little nicer on day 4 if only because the references I chose to work with were big on simplification. Not including all the tiny metal bits in the wheels is a huge time saver and takes away the annoying act of having to draw 40 lines.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.4-dd4658adcc26c15126dabb5a7fbb7324.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.vectorstock.com/royalty-free-vector/bicyclist-rider-mans-bike-hand-drawn-sketch-vector-6224107" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sketchy bikes on VectorStock</a> and <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/diana-huang/art/Draw-People-on-Bicycles-and-Tricycles-510867169" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Diana-Huang on DeviantArt</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I put off day 5 for as long as I could because even though I found drawing bikes to be fairly boring I was afraid that boredom had stopped any memory of the shape of a bike from my mind. I was certain I was going to draw some kind of bike abomination.</p>
<p>But I decided to take it super slow and draw with some perspective to mix things up. Only to draw the best bike I’ve ever seen. Plus another bike in profile which is okay but doesn’t feel like as much of an accomplishment.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.5-2d1d44c8fa35b818ba8bb8d29a6066ad.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Even though I’m proud of the bike I drew on day 5 I’m still a little torn about this week. Inanimate objects just aren’t as interesting to approach this way due to their lack of movement and change. Living creatures have multiple shapes, sizes, motions, bikes just kind of… are. I had the same problem with a few other object weeks. If I were to keep up this kind of practice I’d probably try to find a different approach for inanimate objects.</p>
<p>I have 2 weeks left of WAP, during which I’ll also be putting together my practice format for next year. It won’t kick off until February as my wife and I are going to participate in <a href="https://itch.io/jam/swakjam-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sealed With A Kiss</a>, a month-long game jam to make a visual novel. A second go at Renpy for me after this year's NaNoRenO.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-bicycle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of bicycles</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 37]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37"/>
        <updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 37 - Running]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Possibly last anatomy week of 2024??? This week is running, which I was pretty surprised I hadn’t done yet. Even just went and skimmed my tracking sheet to double check.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Some early day 1 space misjudgements here. Chopped off the top of a head.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.1-b2f77ed8049904a90d9e07581659b258.jpg" width="2747" height="2016" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A fair bit better over day 1 I would say. It’s just so easy to mess up proportions on bodies in motion. I was also happy to find so many different angled shots on runners. Even though it did up the difficulty.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.2-7ff46f8c2be28f3adf4204c65cce260d.jpg" width="2586" height="1741" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.1-34720ca2dc3a590bf4bb4388230764e9.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.2-1909a472a0466bd64dabc4ed2094acc0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.3-f984d05caa0b1edba1f1ae2e32fbe1be.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I kind of wish I had leaned even further into anime runs for my style studies, but probably best to keep it balanced with other types of references. Anime just has lots of kinetic energy in their running animations. It’s through a lot of exaggeration which is still something I’m finding difficult to do.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.1-76a01cc36d51c8e365d66fec3e433a0a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: By <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/bintangpose/art/Male-pose-running-pose-655513693" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bintangpose on DeviantArt</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.2-d77dd07fbdb234461e1f0951a6868ecc.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: From a Korean <a href="https://www.clipstudio.net/drawing/archives/156316?epik=dj0yJnU9R2RxSkhLQW14NkVycHd5MnNPYkU1RzFoYjdFdHFHdHMmcD0wJm49YTlnaFRLRUgtemtWYy1ieEFCSHhZdyZ0PUFBQUFBR2RWMEhZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clip Studio blog post.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.3-035164593ec4ff9eb595c8608f715380.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/6Qdrr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TB Choi on ArtStation
</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Don’t love this final day, lots of mismatched angles from lower bodies to upper bodies. Couldn’t figure out the foot on the front facing one. The bird's eye view one came out okay though. And in profile feels easy enough now, but any angle beyond that becomes risky.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.5-c0bd210d5fa2488eba26ce6ff4c7a671.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I don’t have my last 3 weeks selected yet but I’m tempted to take up the challenge of bicycles. Which is terrifying. That or cars. Transportation objects, terrible. But also tempted to Maybe return to my very first WAP month and revisit some of my first subjects. See if any of the learning from the start of the year stuck around.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-running/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of runners</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 36]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36"/>
        <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 36 - Bats]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe I waited this long to do bats as a WAP theme. They’re an original favourite animal from my childhood, to the point that a book about different types of bats is one of my strongest childhood memories. However, the kids book Stellaluna may be the reason for my love of them:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A brown bat clumsily hangs onto a tree branch. The title Stellaluna is above her in the night sky." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/stellaluna-630ba2cd17d97e415a98dedeef7bf4d1.jpg" width="500" height="498" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 1 not too bad but I was probably picturing how dragons fly instead of bats. There is definitely more variety to bat faces than I could remember and I think my mental model of a bat has been fairly corrupted by cartoon versions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.1-565c6c92599e451b00baadb38b749972.jpg" width="2926" height="1797" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A little more variety, a better angle on the wings. Really seeing how boney bat wings are.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.2-38d404b778b636c678d5161bec094a73.jpg" width="2904" height="2005" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.3.1-ebf742cc32be2cf980ab5cc88aaa4e16.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>While bats are more known for flying, drawing them crawling on the ground is much easier. Perspective gets weird when creatures are flying, wings bend or get foreshortened. It’s hard to convey movement, especially with bats since they’re moving so fast.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.3.2-94b7dfd3571c174b0900d8982991e7c7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>All cartoon bats are so cute, it was very difficult to choose reference pieces for today.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.1-143967413e6fee679406e75828f357e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CKgRLO5DwID/#" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram bats by sarah.b.artist</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.2-a73d4f6f16ad2201cf0113f0dbf67322.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/sharkie19/art/Vampire-Bats-503728080" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vampire bats by sharkie19</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.3-3cfaf35518c596568baaa7d532c95652.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.inprnt.com/gallery/artcher/bat-rogue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bat rogue by Artcher</a>. I love this art piece so much T_T Very much an art style that I’d love to build a comfort with but I struggle to pull out such levels of cuteness.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>This one feels a little fumbled, but probably because I was fighting the urge to draw cute bats and I really just should have let myself draw cute bats. Instead you get Smokey, Tokey, and Ralph, as named by my wife.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.5-7172137ec3872f3b47b9045e4fe081e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>WAP 37 is already in the works and I’m tempted to push through to wrap up the year with WAP 40 but I also have a few other art projects I’d like to wrap up before the end of the year. I do have some time off coming up so I might be able to power through them with that extra time. If I don’t spend it making tofu pies.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-bat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of bats</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 35]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35"/>
        <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After my week of horse riders I thought it would be appropriate to tackle horses on their own. One of the fabled Hard to Draw things along with <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hands</a> and bicycles (which I have yet to try).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I thought day 1 was going pretty okay until I took a step back and got “dog” vibes from my first day of sketches. So I wasn’t exactly getting the legs right.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.1-2aab33e97bf0f4ef3f2f90f81ab1299e.jpg" width="3072" height="2151" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>The tiny head on the first left hand horse here makes me laugh. Horses really are about getting the proportions right while they themselves have pretty weird proportions. I don’t have a natural eye to judge the proper sizes of head and body versus long skinny legs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.2-77d7bac5548db7c65140b2b6443742fe.jpg" width="2861" height="2075" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>More time with references was very valuable. Breaking down the horse into 3 balls or 2 balls connected by a tube is a pretty good base. But their legs can look like different lengths depending on the pose so I still lack confidence in judging when they’re accurate.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.1-48854ce9adcf9c3d8a75731876bd0d6a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.2-d53e1a71a9af429d2f6644a6d5d1855e.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.3-1f5373342bd1895f681ebb9ec680479d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>There are some very good horse references out there. An animal that has been widely Disney’fied. I did enjoy giving them from over the top facial expressions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.4.1-2ae010af34de928141d09d1ceee6c652.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Cartoon horses by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B3ZrjZWlHdu/?epik=dj0yJnU9YS1uMF9vSno1UTUxSlYxRktsR1l4cGM1X3VMVkdZaW0mcD0wJm49VHlIMkVGTlE4X3ZSS0haSlZGcERxZyZ0PUFBQUFBR2MtY24w&amp;img_index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@mitchleeuwe on Instagram</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.4.2-7f5493a4272473f4c4e6cf4b355b6a91.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Horse expressions by <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/EQ4rv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedvig H-S</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I kind of wish I had leaned more into the cartoon versions for test day. The larger eyes and over the top manes add a lot of character to a horse. Keeping them on the more realistic side makes them kind of boring to me. I’ll admit, I don’t super love horses.</p>
<p>My wife wanted it recorded that she has named this horse Pumpkin Wonderful. Place your bets now.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.5-ff66c39a67c6c75f48e6ed7285923262.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Overall, horses, not so bad. They definitely have a unique body type which makes them a bit more of a challenge but I don’t feel afraid or annoyed to draw them again. Hands still feel more difficult by comparison. And now I’m considering doing bicycles before the end of the year. Try to get through the big 3.</p>
<p>Just a few weeks left in the year and I have my final subjects selected. Considering going through all my blog posts and finding my unfinished pieces as there was a lot I started this year but didn’t finish. I don’t have a great track record for returning to unfinished projects but who knows, maybe I’ve changed.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-horses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of horses.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 34]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34"/>
        <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s practice was a style/master study of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Sugimori" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ken Sugimori</a>, the original Pokemon artist, known for drawing all original 151 Pokemon.</p>
<p>I didn’t want to draw just Pokemon, instead leaning on my learnings from anatomy practice and my goal of a self-portrait, I wanted to make myself into a Pokemon trainer. I did a fair bit of YouTube research for this one and I’ll share the resources that were most helpful or insightful throughout the blog post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1---pose">Step 1 - Pose<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-1---pose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1 - Pose" title="Direct link to Step 1 - Pose">​</a></h2>
<p>Following the workflow learn from character design week, step one was to focus on the pose only. Starting from Pinterest I gathered up a bunch of references of original Pokemon trainer artwork as well as a few modern interpretations.</p>
<p>I tried out a few poses, 2 from game references and one that just felt like it really fit the aggressive trainer look.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.1-e614a9fbedc60a5b27955a82b896ebd6.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I didn’t deviate too much from the original poses, wanting this week to be more about design and technique than anatomy or dynamic posing. For proportions, faces, and general shape design, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sratMdLyzvw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rjamez Valdez 4 piece trainer tutorial</a> is absolutely excellent. This is someone who has spent a lot of time studying the originals and also drawing trainers. He breaks down each feature to make it seem easy.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2---design">Step 2 - Design<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-2---design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2 - Design" title="Direct link to Step 2 - Design">​</a></h2>
<p>Design is one of my weaknesses but I feel like by doing 3 mandatory base sketches I’m finally starting to find ways to work around my weaknesses. I definitely used to just do 1 sketch and run with it, but now, for a lot of my work, I try to force at least 3 iterations to either get out of my comfort zone or increase the appeal of the original sketch.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="3 copies of the pose sketch, each with a different hair and clothing style." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.2-9a1b37483e3570722d5c610c0713c195.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-3---lines--colours">Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-3---lines--colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours" title="Direct link to Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours">​</a></h2>
<p>So I messed up the process already. I should have forced myself to stay in step one longer because I really wasn’t happy with the hands. But the problem was that I had done them to match the reference image but then when looking at them again and trying out the hand pose in real life, it just didn’t make sense. So I ended up doing half the lines and then having to pause to re-work both hands over and over again. Even had my wife take a photo of my hand in the pose I wanted so I could use it as a visual reference.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.3-61cca4e6cb3b09b9061bee50a110b232.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Once I finally had the lines done I generated a colour palette from an image of mainline Pokemon trainers of the last 15-ish years. The palette of Pokemon art is rather specific so I didn’t want to choose colours on my own. They’re a combo of being rather muted with a few instances of strong saturation. I struggle with that balance so I tried to stay on the muted end of things. Which led to more beige than I really wanted…</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-4---rendering">Step 4 - Rendering<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-4---rendering" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 4 - Rendering" title="Direct link to Step 4 - Rendering">​</a></h2>
<p>Pokemon art has a very soft watercolour look to it. Where the original game work might have been done completely traditionally with water colours. Which makes for a challenge to duplicate digitally. But many have tried and I’ll share their experiences in the conclusion. I didn’t have to do too much experimenting as I was able to take other people’s brush recommendations and run with it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.4-3e4a37f1c447edc17617d6f056624181.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The shading is rather hard in Pokemon art, with some harsh lines. While the light is rather… light. I think what a lot of people learned was that you should be resisting the smudge tool and trying to keep those hard lines. I however, did not resist the smudge tool and ended up smudging most of my shadows as I didn’t like how hard they looked. I even did multiple shadow passes to add some harder lines back in after. I think this has led to way too much texture in the image which the original style doesn’t really have.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-5---adding-a-team">Step 5 - Adding a team<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-5---adding-a-team" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 5 - Adding a team" title="Direct link to Step 5 - Adding a team">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a lot of cute original trainer art pieces out on the internet. I copied their format of including your Pokemon team next to the trainer art. I didn’t want to spend a lot of time on the Pokemon so I just did quick sketch + lines and colour picked from the sprites to fill them in, then a touch of minimal shading.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.5-a83bcf6cf7722c4c7d40bd8c4fda0620.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>The most in-depth and helpful video on learning this style was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPyS9u3e5yg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mastering The Pokemon Art style! - Master Study</a> by IMTHEJOHKE. He does an intense 3 day style study in a format that I’d like to try out in the future. He talks about his experimentation to get the right look and also about his research. And it was funny to see him reference another style study video which happened to be the one I had watched just before, Subjectively’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BYrUE17SgdA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How to Draw in the Pokemon Style</a>.</p>
<p>Subjectively’s video was more focused on the Pokemon of Pokemon games but he shared the brushes he used in Procreate. Since the line and colouring style of Pokemon art is so unique this was a game changer for everyone in the comments.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="And image showing two Procreate brushes. The first being Gesinski Ink and the next Procreate&amp;#39;s Flat Brush. " src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/pokemon-brushes-c6648e521a73dc467ae5ee1fa9e0530e.jpg" width="2732" height="1522" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This is a screenshot from IMTHEJOHKE's video.</p>
<p>So while IMTHEJOHKE and Subjectively were really able to break down some of the larger pieces of the Pokemon style and how to replicate it digitally, I found Rjamez Valdez’s video series to be key to really making trainers. He seems to publish 1 video a year and has promised another one so I guess I’ll be waiting for that one to drop some day.</p>
<p>I haven’t done a style study like this before and it was really fun to go from idea to research to execution. It wouldn’t have been so easy if there wasn’t already people who had done the hard work and condensed their discovery into YouTube videos, so a challenge to myself will be to do a style study on my own instead of just second hand. But those are projects I hope to take into next year!</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/pok%C3%A9mon-trainers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of Pokemon trainers</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 33]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33"/>
        <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 33 - Swimming]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Action anatomy week, swimming. Some nice perspective shots but fewer variety to those shots than I expected.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>It quickly became obvious that foreshortening and proportion length would be the main difficulty with these.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.1-a580b15659a3e6cd1f720e52db4eff6d.jpg" width="2719" height="1947" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.2-374ceaf55ba9c0746449be8c5f032a14.jpg" width="2831" height="2126" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.3.1-ff30bd11b134f8ff1b624be4a2836980.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.3.2-0f137dcb30b12849b9008a93a50a3f45.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Reference options were pretty slim, I wasn't excited about these but once I started I appreciated the simplicity of the art. Made it easier to think about flowing lines which felt like an important feature to keep the movement looking fluid.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.4.1-efcd7d6e7a631d222c598e8cada6d2e5.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
Reference: <a href="https://www.etsy.com/ca/listing/154091122/swimming-illustration-gift-for-swimmer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vintage swimming instructional illustration</a> and <a href="https://www.etsy.com/ca/listing/1269769939/wild-swimming-print-sea-swimming-print" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Print by Penelope and the Ducks</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.4.2-61f7ce92693186c3515b1a5c76d9bdcd.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
Reference: <a href="https://www.casterman.com/Bande-dessinee/Catalogue/le-gout-du-chlore/9782203012165" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A page from the comic Le Goût du Chlore by Bastien Vivès</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.5-0611d1d04989a1991969016c9f1a79a8.jpg" width="3000" height="1514" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Rushed the last few days into the week as I got hit pretty hard by a vaccine reaction. And this coming week is busy with going into the office so I may not have a WAP for next week.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-swimming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of swimmers</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
</feed>