<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://kymira.ca/blog</id>
    <title>Kymira Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kymira.ca/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Kymira Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://kymira.ca/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 2]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2"/>
        <updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 is pangolins]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A wild week at work resulted in me spending most of my evenings trying not to think about it by drawing. So here are a bunch of sketches of pangolins.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Since day 1 is drawing from imagination I didn’t want to look at a single reference image before starting. This resulted in a funny mistake.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Messy pangolin sketches." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.1-f3bf864a06f40808808a4ed1efefadaa.jpg" width="3063" height="1886" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I had a moment early on, of asking myself, do pangolins have ears that poke out? I didn’t want to break the assignment by looking at a reference so I gave them little poky ears… which was wrong.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I was able to correct my mental image of pangolins on day 2. These quick sketches reinforced my thinking that these guys have a similar build to squirrels in a few ways. They have the same triangle-ish arms, smaller chest zone big butt zone, long tails. But even with those similarities I feel like they give off very different vibes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Quick pangolin sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.2-b682b36835920cbab8f5398b186a3a55.jpg" width="3072" height="1969" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I really like day 3. Having an image up and scrutinising it for the mistakes I made in the first 2 days feels like the learning coming together. However this is also when I get torn about being more detail oriented (draw all the armour scales) and skipping over that because it’s not the most educational in these exercises but is fun.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pangolin walking" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.3.1-f366f8ff573318a92f2e37b1a587278e.jpg" width="2498" height="900" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pangolin making lovey eyes at the camera." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.3.2-b3e16f0242cf156e9a13f774a721c855.jpg" width="2518" height="1430" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pangolin trying to be a ball." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.3.3-e97ddcd3729899aa4382c0539632d521.jpg" width="2558" height="1300" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Close up artsy shot of a pangolin." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.3.4-9a5d57678239d51c07c8f37c9769abb3.jpg" width="2549" height="1433" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Having seen a few stylizing pangolins in the wild previously I knew I could get some good variety here. I tried to choose some of the more stylized versions to learn from. Especially when it comes to different approaches to doing the scales.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Vector art simplified pangolins." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.4.1-ad65375ffcb05e90cf6e5886772d7079.jpg" width="1893" height="1350" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>These guys got simplified down to zig zag patterns which is pretty good. Though I don’t love how it makes them look so smooth.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.vectorstock.com/royalty-free-vector/cute-pangolin-animal-in-various-poses-set-rare-vector-25524101" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VectorStock</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pattern based pangolins" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.4.2-d62bdfc35ea032c8b4946036e07f7978.jpg" width="1893" height="1350" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>These guys have just the hint of triangles to convey where the scales would be. I feel like this is a nice compromise when working with simple shapes or a limited colour palette or size.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.redbubble.com/shop/ap/41700492" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redbubble shop</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Detailed cartoon pangolins" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.4.3-c80322479f3543b4ab49067a30c21f42.jpg" width="1691" height="1068" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>These ones were pretty normal and I didn’t want to spend all my time drawing on the scales so I moved on.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CkjYtc2LJH4/?igshid=MDJmNzVkMjY%3D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Peppermintnarwhal Instagram</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pink pangolin" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.4.4-a2820e3dd94cd66ca12a3aeaac7f9505.jpg" width="1893" height="1350" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Then this guy is mostly just has shapes thrown down to hint at the repetition and presence of the scales.</p>
<p>Reference: [Redbuddle shop](<a href="https://www.redbubble.com/i/sticker/Cute-Pangolin-Why-Hello-There-by-juliekhansard/29045257.EJUG5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.redbubble.com/i/sticker/Cute-Pangolin-Why-Hello-There-by-juliekhansard/29045257.EJUG5</a>_</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>This second time around felt less test-like than week one. This time the struggle was pangolin poses. While I felt like I had spent the week getting their shape down I didn’t really spend enough time watching them move about. Squirrels I see every day, I get them. Pangolins are pretty mysteries. So I felt a little limited by my ability to imagine them in a variety of poses.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Four digital pangolin sketches." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-2.5-811c628c109444138071e295c40497b8.jpg" width="1959" height="1242" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I do at least like them, I think these pieces are still cute and do look like pangolins. But the movement and idea of looking at videos alongside still images is a good takeaway for creatures moving forward.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-2#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Week 2 felt like it went pretty smoothly. And that’s with the hiccup of sending our iPad in for repairs. So this week's digital sketches were done on my Huion tablet that I set up for the first time in 3 years. This meant a little bit of adjustment time and tech troubleshooting before I could get to my daily practice. Slowed me down a bit but should now be prepared to survive without the iPad for a week.</p>
<p>Now to prep for week 3: Pigeons</p>
<p>My pangolin Pinterest board with all my reference images <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-2-pangolin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">can be found here</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 1]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First week of my new art practice schedule]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The way I titled this post implies that I’ll post one of these every week… I don’t think that’s feasible. I have most of the first week of January off so this week is already easier than every week which will follow this year. I think it’s more likely that I’ll try to summarise one or two weeks a month, or I’ll summarise a whole month of practice all at once. It will be difficult to find 15-30 minutes for art every day along with writing and blog management time.</p>
<p>But since I have the time now, I’ll detail how this first week of the Jacob Drawfee Schedule went for me.</p>
<p>Theme for week 1: Squirrels.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Squirrels have been one of my obsessions since moving into my most recent apartment. We have a large back patio with an active squirrel highway (telephone line) that provides a lot of entertainment. I have collected a lot of photographs of squirrels hanging out and in the summer we put out water to help them stay hydrated so they come by more often.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photograph of a squirrel visiting our water dish." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/patio-squirrel-db5dc6ae2a8df5998abac94cfffc178a.jpg" width="3072" height="4080" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I’ve been trying to draw squirrels for the last year but even with their small form I feel like there is always something lacking from my sketches. They felt like the perfect first theme, giving me a chance to finally troubleshoot what about the squirrel makes them difficult for me to draw. On Sunday I filled a page in my sketchbook with different squirrel attempts while sketching for 15 minutes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of my sketch book filled with sketchy squirrels." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.1-3ddc42b4a2347120d0081a49f0a411af.jpg" width="3072" height="2080" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-2---speed-sketching">Day 2 - Speed sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#day-2---speed-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Speed sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Speed sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I prepared for day 2 in advance by preparing a <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/squirrel-refs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest board</a> of squirrel photographs as day 2 is basically quick figure drawing. Using references but mostly to grasp shapes and movement of the subject. It did take some time to collect images so I suspect this will be something I’m trying to rush through before every new week starts.</p>
<p>I set my timer to 15 minutes again. I probably spent too much time on the first page squirrels, somewhere in the 2-4 minute zone on each. This didn’t feel like enough so I did a 2nd page where I forced myself to move through them a little faster.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of a sketchbook page." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.2.1-7944e073baf3322b4a2b4ff2c997de75.jpg" width="3016" height="1831" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of a sketchbook page covered in small squirrels" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.2.2-3609cffdfacb09ebc1598cf62b0afad0.png" width="1964" height="1460" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>These felt pretty messy but it was interesting to see these squirrels next to my day 1 non-reference squirrels and see how much of a difference that makes already.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-3---reference-drawing">Day 3 - Reference Drawing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#day-3---reference-drawing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference Drawing" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference Drawing">​</a></h2>
<p>I switched to the iPad for day 3 because I knew I’d want the ability to draw over reference images. I find this extremely helpful when trying to really get the anatomy and proper shape down from a reference. I chose 4 photos to start with and didn’t give myself a time limit. The goal for the day was 15 minutes but I think I spent closer to 20 minutes on each one.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Squirrel study 1" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.3.1-3bbba748b9020570869c8b67d0b6c79b.jpg" width="2514" height="1878" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Squirrel study 2" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.3.2-1746a557680ff1411d8232c38a576482.jpg" width="2441" height="1900" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Squirrel study 3" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.3.3-024ba19b8fee224767ae601a0c4a586a.jpg" width="2422" height="1693" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Squirrel study 4" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.3.4-205932e8ff470c29e755b04a7fafe515.jpg" width="2343" height="1805" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I was honestly very happy with the first study. I felt like I got the shapes right and captured a good squirrel face. 3 and 4 were tougher. In 3 I struggled to get the head right and 4 was so different from the other that I could barely get the proportion right. Hence breaking the image into sections and trying to figure it out from there. Overall I think I spent 2 hours from gathering the images to finalising the last one.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-4---style-study">Day 4 - Style study<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#day-4---style-study" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style study" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style study">​</a></h2>
<p>I was really excited for day 4 which is for study from other artists. This is to help identify how other artists simplify the harder parts of the subject and which parts they focus on. I know that this is one of my main weaknesses, I often feel trapped between trying to stick to the details of realism or going so simple I love the main features of a creature. Conveniently I already had a <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/squirrel-inspo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest board of squirrel art from last year</a>. Downside, there isn’t as much cartoon squirrel art as I would like.</p>
<p>I chose a few and started to approach them in the same way I did the reference photos. Try to figure out the central shapes, especially the ones that persisted between different artists. The small very simplified squirrels probably ended up being the most helpful as they often came in large groups.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Page one of style practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.4.1-9a86eb2b843ae808b7f6d95c8b0a6cb2.jpg" width="2714" height="1524" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Page two of style practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.4.2-665d270589ce90f51b1a8e215b7f6400.jpg" width="2177" height="1458" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>After sketching the reference images, I went and grabbed some more photos and then tried to draw the new photo while using the styles I was copying. This felt like a good stretch to try to apply the style I had been working from to something new instead of just trying to mimic the same image.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination-take-2">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination, take 2<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#day-5---drawing-from-imagination-take-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination, take 2" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination, take 2">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 5 was scary for me, felt like a test day. This day is meant to be an application of what you’d learned from the past 3 days of drawing from references. I was scared that it would feel like day 1 and that I would be uncomfortable putting pencil to paper without a reference to look at.</p>
<p>In hopes of not getting afraid of the blank page I wrote down a few actions that a squirrel could be doing, jump, sleep, climb, run, sit. I looked back and my past few days of pages and then started drawing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Day 5 sketches" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1.5-0f9e060a32148e356515e5ff08b7cf14.jpg" width="3072" height="1971" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I was honestly rather surprised with the results. I felt like I finally had a good grasp of squirrel faces and proportions, even managed to try out multiple poses without references. Sure none of them were super dynamic but we’re trying one thing pre week. I’m mostly shocked at how much difference 3 days made:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="side by side of day 1 and day 5" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-1-comparison-5261edb5164984e94c95020ddb0f2e67.jpg" width="3072" height="1111" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-1#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I feel like this first week is proof that this is a viable practice approach! I am still afraid of being able to commit to it every week for a year. And lowering how much time I can spend on each day will probably make progress slower (I’m aiming for 15-30 minutes every day instead of the 1-2 hours I did this week). But now that I’m familiar with what’s needed each day I feel like that direction will be enough to carry me through most days.</p>
<p>Now to prepare for week 2: Pangolins.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video Games - 2023 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023"/>
        <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Speed reviews of the games I played in 2023.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have re-written this blog post 3 times.</p>
<p>I thought it would be easy, thought I could laugh in the face of game journalism. But instead I’ve spent the last 2 weeks being rather critical of game journalism and thinking about how it can even be possible to review games if you don’t finish them or physically have the time to play them to the end.</p>
<p>I would be a hypocrite to give a review for games I didn’t finish but also not finishing a game is generally a sign that I wasn’t really feeling it, which is a review in and of itself.</p>
<p>So I think the best way to approach this isn’t to say these are my reviews of games, but these are some games I loved and some I didn’t love so much in 2023 and that’s just one person's experience with them.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-good">The good<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023#the-good" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The good" title="Direct link to The good">​</a></h2>
<p>This was a banger year for AAA game releases this year. Some long awaited games dropped and they even managed to live up to expectations.</p>
<p>The first AAA game of the year I completed was a hold over. I didn’t get far in <strong>Elden Ring</strong> in 2022 when we bought it, but something in early 2023 brought us back to it and completely hooked us. The early game that didn’t click with me started to make sense, I finally got a grasp on the controls and small bits of the lore felt like the best reward you could find. It also helped that I felt like I started to get really good at it and would spend a lot of my time helping other people kill bosses in their worlds.</p>
<p>My time with <strong>Tears of the Kingdom</strong> was greatly enjoyed, but I still haven’t reached the end. The world is sprawling and there’s a new quest waiting for you under every rock. It was cool to get a voice acted Zelda and the powers you’re gifted at the start of the game were a lot of fun, maybe even revolutionary for games going forward. It genuinely felt like a fresh way to engage with an open world. But I’ll be honest, I didn’t go about the world crafting masterpieces out of tree logs. I’m pretty sure I under-used the crafting feature compared to other people. So while I had many moments of delight and I’m sure what was done here is going to influence game development for the next 5 years, it wasn’t my top game of the year.</p>
<p>Fire <strong>Emblem Engage</strong> had its moments but it didn’t click for me. I didn’t care for the main characters but I did love some of the side characters and there were some honest moments in the writing that got me to laugh out loud. But it became another game where I didn’t make it to the credits.</p>
<p><strong>Diablo 4</strong> – I had never played a Diablo game before but my girlfriend has a fondness for them and the promise of couch co-op is all it takes to get me to be excited about a game. This game has some of the goriest cutscenes I’ve ever seen and the story is very dark. But the game play is a nice level of mindless and constant which makes it a great game for melting the hours away while feeling powerful.</p>
<p><strong>Baldur’s Gate 3</strong> was mind blowing for the first 50 hours or so, and then started to close up for me. I loved act 1 and 2 but then act 3 arrived and things began to feel too directed. Which makes sense, the plot lines do need to start wrapping up. But having started 3 new runs of the game in the first few weeks out of excitement, when I did have the credits roll for the first time, I honestly had no feelings of wanting to continue my other playthrough. Everything kind of fell flat.</p>
<p>There is a new epilogue that adds a lot more dialogue between characters at the end which people are hoping improves the ending but I’m not sure when I’ll have time to drop another 70 hours on playing BG3 again just to experience it.</p>
<p>The last AAA game of the year I played was <strong>Mario Wonder</strong>. I’ve loved most Mario platformers and this one has a few new developments which keep things fresh. This is possibly the easiest platformer that’s come out in a while? There are some very difficult levels that are mostly optional and very fun and stressful. But most of the regular levels never took more than one attempt when playing with two people.</p>
<p>Now onto some indie darlings.</p>
<p>Teenage dinosaurs facing the end of the world. <a href="https://goodbyevolcanohigh.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Goodbye Volcano High</a> is one of the most ambitious musical VNs I’ve ever experienced. <del>I think I have about 1 hour left and I’m dragging my feet on it because I know the end will make me sad.</del> (Finished this hours before midnight on New Years Eve!) It has a lot of interesting stuff going on mechanic wise, small little interactions that keep you physically invested in controlling the character in small ways. The music was the big selling point for me though, I’ve been listening to the <a href="https://dabuaudio.bandcamp.com/album/goodbye-volcano-high-original-game-soundtrack" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the original sound track</a> on repeat for weeks.</p>
<p><a href="https://nuts.game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NUTS!</a> I’m not exclaiming this loudly, the title is all in the cap. But the exclamation point was added by me! This game was a gem to find. A natural surveillance game where you set up cameras in a forest to watch squirrels run around in the night. A game targeted specifically at me! I found this game rather scary (you are alone in the woods and this is a big fear of mine in the real world). It’s really not scary but has some minor suspense floating about. This game is available on so many systems now, please play this game so people make more squirrel games.</p>
<p>Next up, a game about fate, tarot cards, witches living in space: <a href="https://www.cosmicwheelsisterhood.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Cosmic Wheel Sisterhood</a>. I loved the art for this as soon as I saw it, and the game idea instantly hooked me. I finished this and instantly started playing it again. One of the most unique games I’ve played in a long time.</p>
<p>A game I played for the first time this year that’s been on the top of a lot of peoples charts was <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/slay_the_spire" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Slay the Spire</a>. This was a lot of fun and it’s cool to see the game that likely launched the wave of card based combat that is so prevalent right now. I got through the flow only once and I can see there is much more to the game that I would enjoy but there are too many games to keep playing this one over and over.</p>
<p>The game I had hesitated to play after hearing about it for months was <strong>Vampire Survivors</strong>. And the only reason I gave it a shot was because I had a 3 hour flight to fill and it can be played for free in offline mode on a phone. This game absolutely slaps and is a classic version of “more than meets the eye”. Just a little weird game that took off overnight, can be bought for 3$ and is super addictive.</p>
<p>And now for the only AAAA on the list (and likely in existence): <strong>Genshin Impact</strong>. I come and go with Genshin but I’ve played for nearly 3 years straight at this point. While its basic gameplay mechanics aren’t super impressive and I don’t recommend this game to most people due to it being a gatha game, it does keep me coming back. There is something very captivating about watching the evolution of this game, its place in the world, the huge projects Hoyoverse undertakes, and the ridiculous crossovers. I can’t look away from it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-meh">The meh<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023#the-meh" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The meh" title="Direct link to The meh">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Dredge</strong> was an early release for the year and one I had on my rader from its demo release in 2022.I was pretty hype for this one, it does a lot of things I love: Weird occult magic in a small isolated town with a bunch of scary underwater creatures. Unfortunately the game fell flat in a lot of areas for me, there were things in the demo I was hoping to see more of but some of those parts of the game didn’t feature as much in the full game (ferrying questionable stuff, struggle to stay alive, development of NPC stories). There have been some expansion since I finished it so I am a little curious to see if the new content would change my opinion but I don’t have the urge to return to it just yet.</p>
<p>The first game I finished for the year was <strong>Spirifarer</strong>, a very beloved indie game that I enjoyed the first 10 hours of but then fell into a repetitive slump. I didn’t love the main story arc and rushed the ending just to get things over with.</p>
<p><strong>Hi-Fi Rush</strong> was a surprise drop. I loved the art style and the fact that it was a rhythm combat game. The story was even decently fun with some good over the top characters. But I fell off of it after about 5-10 hours. There ended up being a bunch of powerup management and that’s something that often turns me off games pretty quickly. Basic concept = lots of fun, developed concept = too much for me.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="analogue-pocket">Analogue Pocket<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023#analogue-pocket" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Analogue Pocket" title="Direct link to Analogue Pocket">​</a></h2>
<p>This post has already gotten too long and I haven’t even managed to mention all the GameBoy games I’ve been playing on our new <a href="https://www.analogue.co/pocket" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Analogue Pocket</a>. So I’ll just say GameBoy games are still great, almost shockingly so. My current obsession is playing the French version of Pokemon Fire Red, a game I think I’ve played 3 times in my life already. And I’m now eyeing up games easily over 10 years old for the start of the new year.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="kylies-state-of-the-game">Kylie’s State of the Game<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2023#kylies-state-of-the-game" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Kylie’s State of the Game" title="Direct link to Kylie’s State of the Game">​</a></h2>
<p>While most games I played ended up in my “good” category for the year, it’s a little strange to say that there wasn’t a game that surpassed my current top three. (I’m counting Elden Ring as a last year game as that’s when it came out and I finished it before almost all the other games I played this year so it feels like forever ago, I honestly thought it was a year ago).</p>
<p>Elden Ring – Hades – Inscryption</p>
<p>Everything I play is compared to those games right now. If I see even just a screencap of those games I want to go and play them again. NUTS came close but it was a pretty small indie project that we won’t see much more of. Baldur’s Gate 3 is technically impressive with it’s huge branching choice system but stumbled at the end and having experienced many bugs in my playthrough (a major one even ruined a dramatic boss fight and story beat) it just can’t stand up to my current top three.</p>
<p>With all these big games dropping this year I’m not sure what to expect for 2024. I’m sure there will be some more stealth drops that will catch the gaming world off guard, but I don’t have anything that I’m waiting for beyond the Elden Ring expansion. So maybe I’ll have time to catch up on some older backlogs for once.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microjournaling aka hobby management]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How I managed a year of hobbies.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This end of year post is rather different from the reviews I’ve been writing. It’s more of a personal review of a journaling method I’ve been using this year to help manage multiple hobbies. If you are extremely minimalist while also loving to plan your life month by month, it could work for you too. But at the moment it’s extremely tailored to me of my kind-of hyper organised lifestyle.</p>
<p>This approach came about after multiple chats with my therapist of me complaining about how I have no time for hobbies and when I commit to one it feels like I lose the ability to stay interested in the rest. I often hyper focus on whatever activity currently has me in its grips. The other focus of this method was to help balance executive dysfunction when it comes to those “I would rather die” tasks. Things like phoning the doctor, filing medical papers, or chores that have been put off for months.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="origin">Origin<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling#origin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Origin" title="Direct link to Origin">​</a></h2>
<p>Even while being someone who loves to make a to-do list, I haven’t been a journaler since my early teens. Unless we still count LiveJournal, then my early 20s. Once I was done with school the habit died off even more.</p>
<p>The bullet journal fad came and went (still here?) and while I was enamoured with the accessories, washi tape, nice journals, nice pens. It wasn’t enough to get me to commit to keeping a journal.</p>
<p>But then I started therapy and I started to have more things to write down. I loved when my therapist would give me homework or a suggestion on an activity or emotion to chart. I liked being able to look back on progress while reminding myself that therapy was changing aspects of my life.</p>
<p>This never became anything huge but it meant I finally used some pages in my nice notebooks.</p>
<p>And then there was the pandemic. I was already unemployed when the lockdown part of the pandemic hit Montreal, and like many people I fell into a bit of a malaise. My regular hobbies couldn’t hold my attention, the world was falling apart and I spent hours doom scrolling. This became another thing to come up in therapy and the main suggestion I got was “even if you don’t feel like doing X will be relaxing, try doing X for 10 minutes”. The idea behind it was to give a hobby an honest try for a very small time commitment. If it wasn’t working I could move on to something else pretty quickly. But if it felt good then I was likely to stick with it for much longer (This is very familiar to how you approach building a regular practice!).</p>
<p>With that advice I made it through the major lockdown and a major life change, touching my hobbies from time to time but mostly letting them fall to the side. At the end of 2022 I felt like things had settled enough that I could give my hobbies another try. But I was ambitious, I didn’t want to get back into one hobby, I wanted to get back to most of them: drawing, reading, website development, and video games.</p>
<p>(Video games were the most sturdy hobby, that one never really fell off. The problem with it was that it has the most potential to over take my time and push the other hobbies out.)</p>
<p>And so with my previous experiences of to-do lists and methods of approaching hobbies, I made myself a single page journal.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of my journaling process. One page is creative goal for the month while the 2nd page is a list of tasks for each month." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/micro-journal1-729c0d5f54bd74f59db6de5e4b8894b7.jpg" width="3000" height="2349" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-page">The page<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling#the-page" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The page" title="Direct link to The page">​</a></h2>
<p>Single page maybe isn’t accurate. I used a single page to plan my hobbies over the course of the year, and one more page for dealing with responsibilities.</p>
<p>When I look at this I feel like I’ve taken bullet journaling to the next level. An approach that was already pretty minimal and now I reduced it even further.</p>
<p>For each month I would prioritise a little bit of each hobby: 1 book, 1 video game, 1 art course, 1 blog post, 1 website project, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of my journaling process. The first page with my hobby goals on it." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/micro-journal2-61da2d6acf3587e0ffb53b34d6ed74c2.jpg" width="1827" height="2093" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>My idea behind this was that if I finished my game of the month, I would have to check off the other hobbies before returning to another new video game. This helped me to balance my free time between hobbies instead of just going to the easiest choice with my free time.</p>
<p>The one I do feel like I struggled with was reading. This is a hobby that can suck me in or turn me away. If I read a book I enjoy I’ll start another one quickly and then can often get a streak going. But if I read something less exciting it’s hard to get me to pick up a book for a few months. It was also a challenge because I was trying not to buy every book. I wanted to rely more on the library system. But this made it almost impossible to stick with my pre-planned reading list because most were new releases and the waiting list at the library for those could be months long.</p>
<p>Note for myself to take into next year: Just buy a book if I feel like reading it (if I’m still employed anyway). I buy most books digitally these days so it’s not like I need to worry about them taking up space.</p>
<p>Overall I loved this page. I loved checking things off, I loved being able to look at it to help me choose what hobby to work on, removing the indecisions of what exactly that hobby would be. If I wanted to read in August I’d check this page and I would prioritise reading what I had chosen way back in January.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="tasks">Tasks<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling#tasks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Tasks" title="Direct link to Tasks">​</a></h2>
<p>On the page next to this one I broke it down by months once again. But this time with a to-do list for every month. This one wasn’t filled out at the start of the year like the previous page. It was filled up as responsibilities would arise.</p>
<p>The main goal of this page was to 1 - keep myself focused on the more immediate responsibilities and 2 - stop me from feeling overwhelmed by responsibility.</p>
<p>It’s easy to make a big list for trying to stay on top of everything in life, but that list could potentially be endless. So these lists had to be the things I didn’t want to do but really needed to. Also I tried to limit every month to 5 things. You can do 5 things in a month.</p>
<p>Sometimes this helped to get those big things done early in the month. A quick checkoff to feel good about myself and then coast on free time for the rest. Some of the items you can see really dragged. Getting carried over to multiple months because I never got around to it (the list isn’t magical, lol).</p>
<p>There is still one major outstanding task I didn’t complete: buying renters insurance. It’s something I really should do but it has multiple steps and involves phoning a company. A herculean task. But I keep copying it over, it keeps being one of my 5 things. Someday it will get done.</p>
<p>Really this to-do list approach was about being kind to myself. While it was an act to focus on what I needed to get done, it helped me to know when I could turn off the guilt of not being responsible and just enjoy my time. And by limiting how many goals I would have for a month it rarely meant I had a month that would feel overwhelming.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="and-thats-microjournaling">And that’s microjournaling<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling#and-thats-microjournaling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to And that’s microjournaling" title="Direct link to And that’s microjournaling">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m calling this microjournaling as it’s the smallest form of journaling I’ve tried. Smaller than a bullet?? It takes up one open page of a notebook and nothing else. It takes minimal effort to put together and works more as a reference or guide for making choices. I’m honestly super excited to fill out my page for next year. The only one I can usually fill in at the start is books because I have a huge backlog. For video games I check release dates and plan around those. The rest often get filled in as I find things I want to work on.</p>
<p>But a lot is still up to chance and where my interest takes me. It probably looks super rigid when shown like this, but I still felt like I had freedom to pursue my interests while feeling focused.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books - 2023 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Favourite books of 2023]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to set myself much loftier goals for books read during the year. But I also used to buy many more physical books. These days I’ve prioritised reading on a Kobo due to ease and space. I’ve moved 7 times in the last 12 years, books make up for a lot of weight. I’ve even started to take my books to one of those free micro libraries. Boxes on the side of the street where you can take or leave books. At least the ones I don’t see myself ever re-reading. It’s helped free up space for… newer books.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Cover images of Iron Widow, Some Desperate Glory, and The Mountain in the Sea" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/2023-topbooks-fb9a233b937727689c8bb823ca7f07a3.jpg" width="1500" height="700" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-challenge">The challenge<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023#the-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The challenge" title="Direct link to The challenge">​</a></h2>
<p>GoodReads always wants you to give yourself a challenge to read, to state how many books you’ll read in the following year. Knowing my reading habit was on the decline I haven’t been setting this very high. I just had 12 this year (and I’m still one short but suspect I’ll read 1 or 2 over winter break).</p>
<p>This year I really wanted to read the recent faves. Books that were making the lists of most anticipated or best of the year. After years of playing catchup I wanted to see if I could keep up with recent releases.</p>
<p>The answer is no, I couldn’t keep up. But also, since Twitter is dying and that’s where I get a lot of my book news and commentary, reading the hits of 2023 didn’t get me much extra engagement. I would have loved to hear other people’s thoughts on these books as they came out but when you spend less time on social media you end up less social. Go figure.</p>
<p>I don’t want to review all the books I read, I put small reviews up on <a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/profile/lautir" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">StoryGraph</a> (the non-Amazon version of GoodRead) and also <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/2315520-kylie" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoodReads</a>. Here I’m just going to go over my top 3 for the year.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="some-desperate-glory-by-emily-tesh"><a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/c6402cfc-fff1-4b40-a30b-7ebe32871b68" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Some Desperate Glory by Emily Tesh</a><a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023#some-desperate-glory-by-emily-tesh" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to some-desperate-glory-by-emily-tesh" title="Direct link to some-desperate-glory-by-emily-tesh">​</a></h2>
<p>This book has been hitting many of the top sci-fi charts for the year. SDG starts out with your pretty typical sci-fi setup. A group of rebel humans fight and prepare for war against an alien race that destroyed their planet. Their sworn revenge keeps them going with small numbers and ageing technology.</p>
<p>It has strong Battlestar Galactica vibes. Military space opera. Not every kid in training gets to join the combat ranks, they are competing for placements. Some are confined to being breeding stock so that the resistance can keep their population alive.</p>
<p>The main character has extremely traditional views (very strong gender rules are enforced, most people on the station are white, and everyone who isn’t human is bad). Her world is turned upside down after an alien is captured and held prisoner, followed by her brother going AWOL. Setting off the chain of events of Kyr (our protagonist) having her eyes opened to the galaxy and what exists beyond her limited space station.</p>
<p>About a third of the way in, the book does a pretty big twist. So if the opening feels a little too basic (it kind of did for me), hold out till then.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="iron-widow-by-xiran-jay-zhao"><a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/8f403954-2950-4903-bdc3-cecb460279e2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Iron Widow by Xiran Jay Zhao</a><a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023#iron-widow-by-xiran-jay-zhao" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to iron-widow-by-xiran-jay-zhao" title="Direct link to iron-widow-by-xiran-jay-zhao">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s hard to beat the opening description line of Iron Widow on StoryGraph.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Pacific Rim meets The Handmaid’s Tale in this blend of Chinese history and mecha science fiction for YA readers.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Iron Widow goes hard. A leading character who wants more for herself. A better life, a better system of life. Giant robots powered by sucking the life out of a pair of drivers, tasked with defending civilization from a mysterious powerful threat.</p>
<p>We got death, violence, forced addiction, abuse of all sorts. Quickly followed by a love triangle, political manoeuvring and big plays for power. Everything plays out between gruesome fights and beautiful facades of the lives of pilots. Nowhere feels safe during the story. Even the ending doesn’t let you relax. So it’s a good thing that book 2 is on the way.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-mountain-in-the-sea-by-ray-nayler"><a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/ae637112-1291-493a-bc06-c1d313ae7d83" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Mountain in the Sea by Ray Nayler</a><a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023#the-mountain-in-the-sea-by-ray-nayler" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to the-mountain-in-the-sea-by-ray-nayler" title="Direct link to the-mountain-in-the-sea-by-ray-nayler">​</a></h2>
<p>This book caught my attention with this blurb before it was released.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Rumors begin to spread of a species of hyperintelligent, dangerous octopus that may have developed its own language and culture. Marine biologist Dr. Ha Nguyen, who has spent her life researching cephalopod intelligence, will do anything for the chance to study them.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If attending squid classes this year, my underwater themed D&amp;D campaign, and my collection of aquatic art hasn’t given it away, I’m in my cephalopod era. Which is how this and a few other ocean themed books ended up on my reading list. In my initial review I included this list of similar media:</p>
<p>You will like this if you enjoyed things like:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Arrival</li>
<li>Work by Becky Chambers</li>
<li>The world building of Malka Older</li>
</ul>
<p>The major themes of Mountain are language (Arrival) and ‘what is consciousness’ (I feel like Becky Chambers touched on this a bit though there are many others who do as well.). But the reason I included Becky Chambers here is that Ray has a strong human element in their sci-fi like Chambers does. A lot of time is spent thinking about how people exist with new technology and how it shapes life.</p>
<p>In Ray’s story, we are seeing 3 different types of life intersect. The humans, the very first near human passing android, and a group of octopuses. I’ve always had a love for androids living with or as humans in stories, this novel places androids right at the start of that journey. No one else is really writing about the development of octopus societies but that could change in the next few decades as we continue to learn more about them (fingers crossed).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="next-year">Next year<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2023#next-year" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next year" title="Direct link to Next year">​</a></h2>
<p>I don’t have a strong focus for what to read next year yet. I have a few things I didn’t get to this year which I definitely want to get to. With my second goal being to read some of the physical books I’ve started to collect. But also maybe revisit some favourite writers from a few years ago who’ve I’ve ignored while trying to branch out and read the new folks rising up. Got a lot of Ann Leckie to catch up on…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="books" term="books"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[21 Draw - A year in review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My review of 21Draw and its offerings.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I paid around 80$ for a year subscription to 21 Draw, and it came with a free give away subscription which I was able to give to a friend. I had tried a few online learning programs over the years, more so when I was unemployed, but none with a year long commitment. I didn’t have any big plans for the year, I was going in with a kind of consistent job, a life still lived under semi-lockdown, and a longing to return to hobbies I’d struggled to get back into. I wasn’t sure how this was going to go but I had hoped that putting some money down would help motivate me, setting myself a goal of doing 1 course per month.</p>
<p>In the end, I finished 20 of the 24 courses I started.</p>
<p>There’s no way I could review all of them so I’m going to highlight my favourites in case anyone else wants to give 21Draw a chance.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="what-makes-a-good-course">What makes a good course<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#what-makes-a-good-course" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What makes a good course" title="Direct link to What makes a good course">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a few key points that make me view a course positively:</p>
<ul>
<li>Homework assignments feel worth my time and are present (I’m not building my 10th moodboard)</li>
<li>Lessons are short and have a take away (1 hour of watching someone paint isn’t my jam)</li>
<li>Something new is introduced</li>
</ul>
<p>I was a little surprised at how many of the courses didn’t have any homework and how lots of the illustrations were just watchings someone else work. You can definitely learn a lot from watching someone else work but if they aren’t well set up to show you the settings, brushes and techniques they are using, the take-aways are limited.</p>
<p>I also grew tired of how many courses started with the bare minimum of “this is how you use procreate”. It’s good the first time around, or when an artist explains a more complex or less used feature. But I think 21Draw could benefit from a series of “intro to software” lesson where the basics are covered in a stand alone course and then each artist doesn’t need to repeat the same info in the lessons.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="top-5-courses">Top 5 courses<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#top-5-courses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Top 5 courses" title="Direct link to Top 5 courses">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="storytelling-with-illustration"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Storytelling with illustration</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#storytelling-with-illustration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to storytelling-with-illustration" title="Direct link to storytelling-with-illustration">​</a></h3>
<p>Great at introducing ways to change the feel and story of the scene by using things like perspective, foreground background, and colour.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="how-to-stylize-characters"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How to Stylize Characters</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#how-to-stylize-characters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to how-to-stylize-characters" title="Direct link to how-to-stylize-characters">​</a></h3>
<p>I wasn’t familiar with the process of starting from silhouettes before and this has very much changed my way of thinking about character and creature design. And now that I’ve seen it here I’m starting to see it everywhere from professional concept artists I watch. Just some really great, instantly applicable tricks to make your piece more interesting.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="designing-fun-animal-characters"><a href="https://wwww.kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Designing fun animal characters</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#designing-fun-animal-characters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to designing-fun-animal-characters" title="Direct link to designing-fun-animal-characters">​</a></h3>
<p>While this introduces a rather simple process for drawing cute characters, the base is really helpful for starting something new. Not only that, its limitations force you to become more creative with it.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="landscapes"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/landscapes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Landscapes</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#landscapes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to landscapes" title="Direct link to landscapes">​</a></h3>
<p>I knew nothing about landscapes before this course and now it’s become one of my most common art types of the year. I loved working in greyscale and the slow refinement process that’s introduced really helps make landscapes less intimidating.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="mastering-lighting"><a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mastering lighting</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#mastering-lighting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to mastering-lighting" title="Direct link to mastering-lighting">​</a></h3>
<p>I thought I had a pretty good grasp of light but this course taught me I knew nothing. Covers the terminology for different kinds of light and shadows while showing how to incorporate them into a piece. I had no idea what Mask layers were for before this.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="intro-to-animation"><a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intro to animation</a>:<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#intro-to-animation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to intro-to-animation" title="Direct link to intro-to-animation">​</a></h3>
<p>After watching multiple intro to animation videos this year I feel like I can confidently say that this one does a good job of covering the main concepts of 2d animation. The assignments were good and I felt like I took away a lot of new knowledge from this one.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="The 4 pieces from the light lesson" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Lighting-studies-d2f864afb8a5348525e6633403d09a44.jpg" width="9921" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="fav-art-pieces-of-the-year">Fav art pieces of the year<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#fav-art-pieces-of-the-year" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fav art pieces of the year" title="Direct link to Fav art pieces of the year">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Collage of my fave art pieces for the year." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/2023-art-recap-d712dbbff165b49eb44e137289cca18a.jpg" width="3000" height="1500" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="final-feelings-on-21draw">Final feelings on 21Draw<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/21draw-review#final-feelings-on-21draw" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final feelings on 21Draw" title="Direct link to Final feelings on 21Draw">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m extremely happy with my 21Draw purchase. There was certainly a variety of quality when it came to the courses. It felt like some had more support than others when being made. And if you take a lot of intro level courses you end up hearing the same intro level content on repeat. It’s a gamble I was willing to take, with the decent sized catalogue of courses there was always something new to try if there was a course that wasn’t working for me.</p>
<p>I won’t be renewing my subscription for a 2nd year as I think there’s only 10 courses left that I haven’t checked out. I’m eyeing up the learning platform <a href="https://www.domestika.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Domestika</a> for my 2024 learning. I do plan to keep an eye on 21Draw releases over the next year, and if they get a few more interesting ones I could see signing up again in the future for the next content.</p>
<p>However, one major thing has stood out while doing this year in review. I have much fewer completed pieces than I would like.</p>
<p>This is mostly my fault, I didn’t do all the assigned homeworks and baulked at having to do 1 full illustration for a course instead of smaller pieces or homeworks. So while Domestika looks really fun, I’m also considering doing a few months of focused practice instead of focused learning.</p>
<p>21Draw was a great way to re-familiarize myself with the basics and also many of the steps of the process I never learned. But when a course is 7 hours long and it’s mostly just watching someone else work, that 7 hours I don’t spend drawing myself.</p>
<p>I think for January I’m going to try to follow a practice schedule, specifically the one Jacob Drawfee goes over in this Drawclass: Jacob's No Pressure Guide to Learning How to Enjoy Art Practice.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BeP3T511C-w?si=u-RLawqUyXpKyJga" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>
<p>It boils down to trying to draw 5 days out of the week, with a specific focus for the week and what to do each day. I’d love to say I’ll commit to a year of it but that feels rather intimidating at the moment. Especially with a few projects and volunteer programs in the works for 2024. So we’ll see how far I can get. And if each week might make for a worthy blog post.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[November Wrap Up]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up"/>
        <updated>2023-11-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October ended up being one of my busiest months of the year, which led to only sporadic 21 Draw lessons between travelling and playing Baldur’s Gate 3.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>October ended up being one of my busiest months of the year, which led to only sporadic 21 Draw lessons between travelling and playing Baldur’s Gate 3.</p>
<p>In December I plan to do a few end of year posts which means I want to try to cover the last 2 months of art practice in this post. So buckle in for some random courses and projects from the last 2 months.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="21-draw---pets">21 Draw - Pets<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up#21-draw---pets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 21 Draw - Pets" title="Direct link to 21 Draw - Pets">​</a></h2>
<p>Multiple new courses have launched on 21 Draw during my year of taking classes which has been very exciting. If a little disruptive to my early plans of having pre-chosen which courses I wanted to focus on. One of these was a course on creating cartoon versions of pets.</p>
<p>I don’t have a cat or dog but I have a friend who sends me lots of photos of her cats so I had a lot of material to work with as reference. I didn’t finish this course as I found things start to get pretty repetitive when the artist is covering basic line-art and painting techniques. But the more central part of the program, breaking animals down into basic shapes and ways to portray age and personality with some design choices were helpful.</p>
<p>I ended up only working on the sketch phases with the references I had. I do love drawing animals but doing simplifications or cartoonification is definitely a weakness of mine. I struggle to choose what details aren’t important and can be left out. And I struggle to make eyes larger for soften personalities instead of trying to replicate sizes to proper anatomical proportions.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sketches of Albert and Leon" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Pet-sketches-aa97c4eec2022bc36ec7178798d2e5da.jpg" width="2048" height="2048" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="21-draw---colour-theory--intermediate-procreate">21 Draw - Colour Theory &amp; Intermediate Procreate<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up#21-draw---colour-theory--intermediate-procreate" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 21 Draw - Colour Theory &amp; Intermediate Procreate" title="Direct link to 21 Draw - Colour Theory &amp; Intermediate Procreate">​</a></h2>
<p>I started and nearly finished it (I’ll probably wrap it up next week), a short course of colour theory. A few of the longer digital painting lessons touched on colour theory so a lot of this was repeat information to me but it had a few gems still. Colour theory is something I over think, or that there is some mystical secret behind. But I feel like it really comes down to understanding the colour wheel and having a good eye for colour. I’ve been forcing myself to work with palettes a little more in my last few pieces as well as to use the Procreate colour selector to check complementary and tertiary colours for my main colour themes.</p>
<p>This had a few pieces of homework but none of them interested me so I didn’t do them. I probably should have for the practice but I felt like I had multiple courses on the go at this point and was struggling to focus on putting Apple pencil to tablet.</p>
<p>I’m not super confident in my colour selection of pieces, I probably go way too saturated most of the time. And then jump around to whatever colour I like instead of taking the time to see if colours work well together.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/schmoedraws/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simone Grünewald</a>’s intermediate Procreate lesson has been pretty good but it’s hard to focus on a 5 hour course with no homework assignments. The main thing this course did for me was convince me to buy <a href="https://maxpacks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Max Ulichney’s Watercolor Brushes for Procreate</a>. Simone used these for nearly her whole painting process and I really came around to how they looked and behaved during the main hours I watched her paint.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="dd-maps">D&amp;D Maps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up#dd-maps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to D&amp;D Maps" title="Direct link to D&amp;D Maps">​</a></h2>
<p>These pieces were small projects during the year I didn’t post about as they contain spoilers for the D&amp;D campaign I’m running. They’re maps that are meant to convey locations of places easily to players instead of a battle map. I’ll often find battle maps online for my needs but for more unique locations I want to be able to communicate the area I’ve created and find that this can be more reliably done with images. Hence spending way too much time on these maps that the players may never fully see.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Exploration grid map of a sunken island city" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Ruins-map-8572cdf1902a2b3c8524888437daf1d4.jpg" width="1408" height="1408" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Layer map of a library carved into an underwater stalagmite." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Library-outpost-five-a77d0fe545532627efe0585b0583c161.jpg" width="2500" height="2500" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="altar-stone-projects">Altar Stone Projects<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up#altar-stone-projects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Altar Stone Projects" title="Direct link to Altar Stone Projects">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s been a while since we launched a new song (see October being busy) but I’ve been picking away at putting together scenes for future music.</p>
<p>One project started with a fish sheet.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="A sheet of a variety of pink fish." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Fish-sheet-b91cc4a190a4cf1c945ab06324a920fd.jpg" width="2500" height="2500" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I love seeing other artists' sheets of creatures. There’s often so much variety to each creature and everyone interprets them all a little differently. My fish sheet is all fictional creatures as I wanted to build up a repertoire of basic fish to have around in the D&amp;D campaign. So I spent a lot of time looking at fish and then smashing together my favourite bits of real fish to make up these fake fish.</p>
<p>Then I started to animate them.</p>
<p>Not all of them, but so far I’ve created simple animation loops for at least 6 of them. Then I made them a place to swim.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="An underwater scene of rocks, sea weed, and a dome in the distance." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Underwater-arch-a30bf84ca1be7ed740c1c5cfe5fdabc4.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I’ve put together this full animated scene already but it’s not online yet, so you’ll have to wait to see the completed piece.</p>
<p>Next up was a player request. I introduced a giant awoken octopus as a smith in my underwater city. People thought he was pretty cool and asked if he had a themed song (he did not). But my girlfriend went ahead and tried a few things to put together something that could capture a forge vibe.</p>
<p>For this piece I really wanted to try out the MaxU watercolour brushes I mentioned above. They seem well fitted for background work and I wanted something more gritty and textual than my previous background pieces. This did mean it took much longer as I had both a learning process to get through and many layers to work with to get the right blend of colours and textures from the brushes.</p>
<p>I’m not super satisfied with the final product, I know what areas I want to touch up, but I’m leaving them for the animation edits so that I can play with lighting more dynamically instead of having it painted on directly. Hilariously enough, the large octopus going in front of this will cover most of the background anyway.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="A scene of a large medieval looking furnace in a forge." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Forge-bg-e3bea4e679984c989a3111773dc1e1a0.jpg" width="5760" height="3240" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/catch-up#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I'm hoping to squeeze in one more 21 Draw course between November and December. Then my subscription will come to an end. I'm already making plans for 2024 and what I want to focus on but we'll see how well those plans hold up. After a year of trying out a lot of different stuff, I can see myself ending back up at figure drawing lessons once again.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
        <category label="altar stone" term="altar stone"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting into animation]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation"/>
        <updated>2023-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few months ago my girlfriend asked if I could draw a piece of art to be the image of a YouTube video for her music. She was composing a fight track for a D&D campaign I run and since I use Sync-Tube to sync music with my players during a game, uploading the track to YouTube was the easiest way to share it. But this meant having a visual aspect to the music as well.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago my girlfriend asked if I could draw a piece of art to be the image of a YouTube video for her music. She was composing a fight track for a D&amp;D campaign I run and since I use Sync-Tube to sync music with my players during a game, uploading the track to YouTube was the easiest way to share it. But this meant having a visual aspect to the music as well.</p>
<p>An idea came to mind pretty quickly for this and I was able to put it almost all tonight in an evening. A large octopus with a sword fight with silhouettes of the characters from the campaign:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="A giant pink octopus holding a sword, facing off 5 silhouettes of adventurers." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/octo-fight1-e9bfb0e0ab5de4368895a702abd9c8d4.jpg" width="2986" height="2242" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Before we got around to uploading the song, she got the idea to try animating a part of it so it wasn’t just a static image for 1 hour. I cut out the sword as a separate layer, she put both pieces into PowerPoint and ta-da, we got a spinning sword:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mE8iykMUzuk?si=TsYqWsZYlsXYJqLc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>
<p>With the publication of this first video, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Project Altar Stone</a> was launched, and so began my focus on 2D animation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="from-powerpoint-to-toonsquid">From PowerPoint to ToonSquid<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation#from-powerpoint-to-toonsquid" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to From PowerPoint to ToonSquid" title="Direct link to From PowerPoint to ToonSquid">​</a></h2>
<p>As mentioned, my girlfriend animated the first video in PowerPoint and this worked surprisingly well. But PowerPoint has its limitations (you can only animate one thing at a time) and I already had ideas for how the next video could go. I have some video editing experience with a program called Camtasia so this is what I brought the next song project into.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Camtasia was rather limited on the animation front as it’s more designed for traditional video editing (doing green screens, layovers, highlighting mouse movements). I was using it to make tutorial videos at a previous job. But since I had a paid version of this software I was hoping to make it work. After some Googling I learned that my version was a few updates behind and if I wanted to find tutorials or troubleshoot issues I would almost always be finding ones that reference the new version.</p>
<p>And so the hunt for 2D animation software began.</p>
<p>Since I do almost all my digital art on an iPad these days, that’s where the search started. It’s pretty easy to find a top 10 best animation apps list, but still hard to choose one when you don’t really know what features of an app you want are. So I read some guides, watched some videos and eventually settled on a rather recent new program <a href="https://toonsquid.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ToonSquid</a>.</p>
<p>ToonSquid has a few short tutorials on YouTube, keywords I understood (keyframes, onions layers) and a rather impressive intro demo video. And possibly it’s biggest selling point, it was a one time purchase instead of a subscription model! So with that research phase done, it was on to video number 2.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="learning-the-tools-of-the-trade">Learning the tools of the trade<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation#learning-the-tools-of-the-trade" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning the tools of the trade" title="Direct link to Learning the tools of the trade">​</a></h2>
<p>With ToonSquid came a lot of learning, watching tutorial videos, experimenting with tools, etc. Our second video came from both of us learning how to use ToonSquid. Definitely had some struggles so this process felt a little messy but resulted in us learning some best practices to take forward into the next one.</p>
<p>Even with those learning hiccups, I’m pretty happy with how the video came out with two major objects being animated at once. And it was a good challenge for me to learn to draw and design a fantasy submarine, something I felt pretty scared to do.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OYB_MDRmDq4?si=kDrBCzfaOKHnlj_0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>
<p>Video three is rather simple from an animation perspective, but was a big challenge for me as I set myself the goal of drawing an alleyway for a world I didn’t have a great visual grasp of. Did a lot of Pinterest searching for ‘fantasy market’ and ‘fantasy alleyway’ to get ideas. Then it was time to get familiar with the perspective tools Procreate has to offer. These ended up great for blocking in the basic shapes and helping to get the lines of the boxes and door at the right angle.</p>
<p>Other things I learned in this one was how to make repeating pattern blocks, which is how I made the cobblestone road. This took some precise copy and pasting which I didn’t love as it was easy to mess up the seam lines. But it was cool to learn the basic approach for making repeating patterns.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yRvnEvGGnhs?si=J2zNuo_ocYuT0nrI" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>
<p>(There is a second version of this video with more animations but it’s a secret until a specific D&amp;D session.)</p>
<p>Video three is a return to combat which meant revisiting our very first scene. Coming at this with the knowledge learned from the first three videos made this more complex and also easier. I knew exactly what I needed to be separate layers which would give me lots of options to play with when moving over to ToonSquid. This did result in me hitting the Procreate layer limit for the first time ever, oops. My big mistake in this one is that I did too much shading on the tentacles which completely falls apart once things start moving. Still need to remind myself to not think of these images as static.</p>
<p>Thanks to all the layers, this is our most active video yet. 8 different tentacles moving at once, the octopus mantle moves a bit, and even got the octopus eyes moving about.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UY0mnrQdfAw?si=0lEylxCRnSRHch1A" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="back-to-21-draw">Back to 21 Draw<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation#back-to-21-draw" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Back to 21 Draw" title="Direct link to Back to 21 Draw">​</a></h2>
<p>When I started going through the 21 Draw course offerings I hadn’t really considered taking the intro to 2D animation one, but once this project started to take off I added it to my queue. It had a lot of the foundational stuff that was covered by the same teacher in his other courses and that I’ve blogged about before. But he spent more time on the 12 Principles of Animation from Disney and ran through what seems like some of the classic beginner animation challenges.</p>
<p>I enjoy the practice of starting off learning to animate with a flour sack. For the assignment he gave us making the sack jump:</p>
<img src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Sack-jump-47f3d2fc42c0f5ffd907fe1821d68614.gif" width="400">
<p>Then we ran through a longer thumbnailing exercise of laying out the key frames of a longer animation. Rabbit character picks up a piece of paper and then <del>something happens</del> left up for the learner to decide:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="rabbit image" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rabbit-animation-6500f2cdd69cd358b762aeff4fc35179.jpg" width="2048" height="2048" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="whats-next">What’s next<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/2d-animation#whats-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What’s next" title="Direct link to What’s next">​</a></h2>
<p>While the idea of doing a large flip book project is very daunting, it’s something that now feels doable. I was complaining previously about sometimes only having 20 minutes to get some drawing time in and while working on animations 20 minutes felt like a decent amount of time to get a frame or two done. Sure if I think about how little a single frame is seen it can make that kind of work feel less rewarding, but seeing a small animation play out has been a lot of fun.</p>
<p>I’m now in the brainstorming phase for future song animations while spending time on YouTube looking for more intro to 2D animation tutorials. Now trying to balance working on animation while still trying to do one or two 21 Draw courses every month.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
        <category label="altar stone" term="altar stone"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Light]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After getting through a large portion of the beginner level courses on 21 Draw, I finally felt like I could start dipping into the intermediate level courses. Starting with Aveline Stokart’s ‘Mastering Lighting and Shading’.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After getting through a large portion of the beginner level courses on 21 Draw, I finally felt like I could start dipping into the intermediate level courses. Starting with <a href="https://www.avelinestokart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aveline Stokart’s</a> ‘Mastering Lighting and Shading’.</p>
<p>This is one of 21 Draws top highlighted courses, a large portion of it is even available for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdMxg3lVGGI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">free on YouTube</a>. Now that I’ve completed the whole thing it definitely deserves the top slot on the website and I would highly recommend it for anyone who wants to get more creative with lighting in their illustrations.</p>
<p>It starts by walking you through the basics of light and shadows on simple shapes. I always forget the specific names for different types of light and shadows so this was good for me, even if I’ve forgotten half of the names already. Then we did some studies of movie scenes to grasp light in action and after that Aveline provides a sketch that you then use to create 4 different lighting scenarios which is where the real takeaways come from.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="learning-to-see-light">Learning to see light<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#learning-to-see-light" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning to see light" title="Direct link to Learning to see light">​</a></h2>
<p>One of the exercises that Aveline gives is to study movie shots. This has come up before in other courses for studying composition and colours, but her approach was all about understanding how light was being used in the scene. Be it to highlight something specific in the scene to draw the eye or set the tone.</p>
<p>I chose this Black Swan shot for my study because I wanted something simple to get through the exercises quickly.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="A screenshot from the movie Black Swan next to a digital painting copy." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/black-swan-study-f8b90c4ceb435c4f03fdd94214dba2a5.jpg" width="2048" height="774" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I don’t like it when I look at it in full size as the colours are all off, but every time I see this in thumbnail form on the Procreate project selection screen it looks pretty good!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-base">The base<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#the-base" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The base" title="Direct link to The base">​</a></h2>
<p>The base sketch is a girl with a small dragon. We filled in the flats, gave it a simple background and filled in some details like the cookie box and her shirt.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character in a park on a sunny day." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/base-light-colors-0553906978d28f1cc829c04ace833598.jpg" width="2480" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="scenario-1-sunny-day">Scenario 1: Sunny day<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#scenario-1-sunny-day" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Scenario 1: Sunny day" title="Direct link to Scenario 1: Sunny day">​</a></h2>
<p>The first lighting scenario was a bright sunny day with the light coming through between the tree branches. It was in this first explainer video that I learned how many layers it takes to do light well. I think Aveline used over 10 different layers to pull off this look. That’s layers for bounce light, ambient light, specular light, general highlights, and on and on.</p>
<p>I’d never worked with Mask layers before so this was an interesting one to see right from the start. And makes a lot of sense given a lesson I picked up from a different course: Lighting is more about erasing than painting. You carve out the areas being hit by light. I’ve done that in the past to create minor vignette effects but to see it used to create the main light regions in an illustration was something else!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character in a park on a sunny day." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Sunny_Day-e61fbf9d770943c779e5e639e393a200.jpg" width="2480" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="scenario-2-night---glow">Scenario 2: Night - Glow<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#scenario-2-night---glow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Scenario 2: Night - Glow" title="Direct link to Scenario 2: Night - Glow">​</a></h2>
<p>In the second challenge the bright day is completely flipped for a dark night. The lighting layers are all deleted, we keep the base colours around, and start again.</p>
<p>I generally find glows really fun to work with in digital art. There are lots of options to play with and room for experimentation. In this scene it’s the little dragon giving off the glow so we have the direction of the light change from the first scene. The light is also more tinted then the light of the sun so the whole scene feels drastically shifted away from the vibrant day.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character outside in the dark with a glowing dragon." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Magic_Night-77a7089dbc5a9a09304bb916a8d3297e.jpg" width="2480" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="scenario-3-indoors---overcast">Scenario 3: Indoors - Overcast<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#scenario-3-indoors---overcast" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Scenario 3: Indoors - Overcast" title="Direct link to Scenario 3: Indoors - Overcast">​</a></h2>
<p>For scenes 3 and 4 we’ve moved inside. So quickly through a new background together; walls and some hanging art.</p>
<p>Same approach, delete all the previous lighting layers, choose a new ambient base colour and start adding layers. I think I went a little too dark on this one, it’s pretty easy to over shoot a colour and a good opacity level.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character inside on an overcast day." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Overcast-88cc45857901c5e6e10869c8d22caabc.jpg" width="2480" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="scenario-4-indoors---sunset">Scenario 4: Indoors - Sunset<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#scenario-4-indoors---sunset" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Scenario 4: Indoors - Sunset" title="Direct link to Scenario 4: Indoors - Sunset">​</a></h2>
<p>Now going to warm colours for a sunset vibe that’s much more intense then the overcast day in the previous one. Both of these scenarios moved to a more backlit character and I may have lost details in the girl's face. One of the other important tips, which I still struggled to execute, is when it’s okay to cheat.</p>
<p>You can live by the realistic movements of light and shadows but if you want to balance your piece and have the important parts pop, it’s good to “cheat” by adding highlights to locations that need it to stand out. You still follow the rules of the scene, where the lights are coming from, colour, etc. But if it means putting a bit of highlight on a dark face to make a face more visible, it’s usually the right call.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character inside while the sun sets." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Sunset-4c7044000579967a4a9f5dee3679bf0e.jpg" width="2480" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/learning-light#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Before this course I didn’t think about light too much. I always have a mental map of where light is coming from when shading a character and thought was enough. And sure it was fine for rather flat character work, but going through all the steps to add even baseline lighting to these scenes has reinforced how much heavy lifting lighting does to create a scene and vibe. I feel less afraid to tackle a whole illustration now, and maybe take a few more daring approaches to lighting characters in the future.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="All 4 light studies." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Lighting-studies-d2f864afb8a5348525e6633403d09a44.jpg" width="9921" height="2480" class="img_wQsy"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning landscapes]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes"/>
        <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While this is one of the most popular courses on 21 Draw I didn’t prioritise it. My interests had always been more around character design and creatures. But after branching out in a few other courses, I thought it would be time to keep trying to step out of my comfort zone.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While this is one of the most popular courses on 21 Draw I didn’t prioritise it. My interests had always been more around character design and creatures. But after branching out in a few other courses, I thought it would be time to keep trying to step out of my comfort zone.</p>
<p>This course is taught by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI2LeV6oDbGd8LJ8iUneSZA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Philip Sue</a> and it looks like he has a lot of step by step process videos on his YouTube which likely cover a lot of the things covered in this course.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="greyscales">Greyscales<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes#greyscales" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Greyscales" title="Direct link to Greyscales">​</a></h2>
<p>Just like in a lot of the other courses I’ve taken so far, this one started out with silhouettes. It was a pretty free form first exercise, work with the 5 tones to compose a background, midground, and foreground. The assignment pushed you to make five different pieces which was a good stretch and quickly where I started to diverge a little too much from the guidelines.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Figuring out compositions with greyscale work" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Landscape-thumbnails-02ac4464f666db17b5e172ef3abd4961.jpg" width="1408" height="939" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>My first few landscapes felt reasonable, but then I started to get ideas for D&amp;D game locations. These started off problematic as I was too “zoomed in” to follow lots of the advice that was being provided for landscapes. They could probably work as general illustrations but there wasn’t enough distance between the features to really follow the next steps. Which is what pushed me to continue with only 2 pieces instead of 3 like the course suggested.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="colours">Colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes#colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Colours" title="Direct link to Colours">​</a></h2>
<p>THe courses provided some palettes to try out but I didn’t want to screenshot the video and then pull the colours into Clip Studio so I looked up some other palettes on Pinterest. These weren’t as curated so it was actually more time confusing and not super rewarding. The orange, desert-y one was from the instructor while my green ring ended up being mostly eye balled. But I was at least happy to have 2 very different colourscapes to work with.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Laying down base colours over the grey thumbnails" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Landscapes-lighting-v1-efd02817f14d460ea0b04f57dba4aaba.jpg" width="1408" height="1033" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>There was a step for experimenting with colours and lighting, and I would have loved to have access to Procreate's Gradient Maps for that, but in Clip I played around with colours layers and some manual re-painting. I had always thought I had a pretty good natural grasp of lighting but on trying to get more creative with it in these scenes I started to question that. Good thing there’s a whole class on lighting that I can still take.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="detailing">Detailing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes#detailing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Detailing" title="Direct link to Detailing">​</a></h2>
<p>After composition and colours comes making the thumbnail huge and getting into the details.</p>
<p>The first one, my desert, thankfully doesn’t have many details going on. Touched up the lighting, added some extra rocks and made a very simple stream. I probably spent just as much time looking for nice cloud brushes. It definitely took a while to get used to the movements of painting and erasing over and over again to try to create the right shapes in the mountains, and I still don’t feel like I nailed that, but I feel like I’m getting closer at least. I re-painted a few of them a few times, trying out different brushes and techniques. Most of them ended up smoothing things out too much and losing the rock-like texture of large sweeping strokes. Which feels like the largest challenge of painting like this, you kind of want to work minimally as more strokes or colours ends up washing out the sharp lines and features.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Final version of my desert" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Desert-landscape-3567c2c3d6fb15aeae01f2098ddd4436.jpg" width="4286" height="2997" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I’m pretty happy with how this came out in the end. There are definitely areas I can see improvements for already, but it feels “big” which is what I wanted to learn to do in this course.</p>
<p>For my green pieces I felt like I had fallen into my “too zoomed in” habit here a bit too. I ended up spending a lot of time on detailing the big stone ring, and adding plant textures with plant brushes. All the while I should have been working further out to a point of not seeing any of these details.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Final version of my forest ring" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Ring-landscape-70cd300ec10f30ba7e7d3ea289897bb0.jpg" width="4562" height="2983" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I also struggled with the colour balance a bit more here. I wanted the sun to be rising behind the mountains which made for minimal light hitting the side we could actually see. And some of the mountains felt like they started to disappear, which I guess makes sense if the light is so bright behind them, but I ended up darkening up a lot of features so that the lines between layers of distance still made sense.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="final-review">Final review<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/landscapes#final-review" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final review" title="Direct link to Final review">​</a></h2>
<p>Overall I found this course had the perfect balance of lesson + homework. It had some great foundational takeaways and you could instantly apply what was being taught. I struggled a little bit with the program being Photoshop in the course, but nearly all the features also exist in Clip Studio so it was just a matter of figuring out the right tool or button to accomplish the task. The course managed to really break down how to approach landscapes and now I no longer feel intimidated by them. Will definitely draw more in the future.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixed Media Monsters]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters"/>
        <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mixed media course on 21 Draw launched a little over a month ago now. It’s their first mixed media course which was enough to make me want to give it a try. And it focused on strange creatures so it had a lot going for it in my eyes. It ended up being one of the more detailed courses I’ve taken so far.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The mixed media course on 21 Draw launched a little over a month ago now. It’s their first mixed media course which was enough to make me want to give it a try. And it focused on strange creatures so it had a lot going for it in my eyes. It ended up being one of the more detailed courses I’ve taken so far.</p>
<p>The course is hosted by <a href="https://www.evaboneva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eva Toorenent</a>, an artist with a very unique approach to mixing watercolours with digital colouring. I’ve never done any serious watercolour practice before so I was excited at the possibility of learning a new medium.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="inspiration">Inspiration<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters#inspiration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Inspiration" title="Direct link to Inspiration">​</a></h2>
<p>The first assignment of the course was 2 questions. I find these things rather cheesy and would usually skip them, but as I said in my previous blog post, doing these courses is my attempt to slow down and do the work.</p>
<p><strong>Question 1: What gets you excited/happy? What can you talk about for hours? (5 sentences)</strong></p>
<p>This is a kind of ironic one because I recently told my girlfriend “I don’t feel joy” and I kind of mean it but in a way that I just don’t get super excited about things. I can feel joy or happiness in the moment, I look forward to things in the future, but I rarely feel really <em>excited</em> about it.</p>
<p>The biggest one is probably playing D&amp;D. It’s a solid combo of creativity, fast thinking and social time. It’s probably also one of the few things I could talk about for hours.</p>
<p>I have a lot of practice talking about myself thanks to over 100 hours of therapy but I can’t say that that’s a topic that I’m excited about. I also get very excited to eat take-out but couldn’t talk about that for hours unless we’re looking for recommendations.</p>
<p>It’s funny because I do love to read, watch tv, play video games, and just consume media in general but I don’t go out of my way to talk about it for more than a few minutes. I’ve always been a big Solo Enjoyer.</p>
<p><strong>Question 2: What do you do to get inspired? (5 things)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Read blogs / adventures written by other DMs (D&amp;D)</li>
<li>Stare out the window (in hopes of seeing animals)</li>
<li>Listen to podcasts</li>
<li>Look at my previous projects</li>
<li>Talk about ideas with other people</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Question 3: 3 artists that inspire your work</strong>
I quickly knew this wasn’t a question I was prepared to answer. Which made me wonder if maybe it’s a reason why I feel all over the place with style. I don’t have any artists I follow really closely or ones I’ve done a deep dive on their methods. But I do have a Twitter list with 100 artists whose art I like. I can’t say they all inspire my art. So it took a long time to find some answers to this:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/frandaredoodles" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fran Dare</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Fran used to run #drowgust over on Twitter every year, it was one of the first art month challenges that I managed to complete. They draw an endless amount of drow (and so was I a few years ago) and I really loved their greyscale approach to traditional pieces. They are probably a big reason why I own so many grey markers.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Drawfee" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Drawfee team</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Drawfee is a show that’s been around online for ages but I only started watching it last year. They are digital art focused, which is often how I work. They mostly draw characters or silly scenes, which is basically where I want to get comfortable with my drawings. But since they do speedraws every now and then you can watch their process, hear about how they troubleshoot an image and see them push their own artistic boundaries. Watching their episodes every week is definitely one of the big reasons why I made this year an art focused year.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>???</li>
</ol>
<p>Honestly couldn’t come up with anyone else. Back in the days of DeviantArt and blogs it was much easier to follow artists and learn about their process. I’m not a huge fan of historical artists so I’m not off reading about the progression of the Old Masters. A decent take away from this question is that I probably want to find some time to do research on artists, see who has good YouTube content, see if anyone is blogging about their work. Learn more about other people's approaches to find new directions to take my own practice.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="inspiration-and-reference-material">Inspiration and reference material<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters#inspiration-and-reference-material" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Inspiration and reference material" title="Direct link to Inspiration and reference material">​</a></h2>
<p>Like most of the courses this one tasks you with creating a moodboard and even a playlist. Since the mood boards were focused on one for real animals and one for monsters I spent some time building these up with images I like. I didn’t bother to make a playlist as I find this very time consuming and not super helpful to my own process.</p>
<p>It was around this point that I realised how many different assignments there were going to be in this course. There was a blob challenge, which I did. But she says don’t even bother to do this unless you know you are then going to work on a larger piece after. And in my case, I almost never have that much time on my hands to spend 20 minutes doing a blob challenge. Followed by a requested <strong>five</strong> pages of sketches to get ideas down. Then on top of that, choosing 3-5 and giving those characters a story related phrase to say.</p>
<p>I understand that this is a course very closely following a particular artist's approach to their work but at this point the course was losing focus for me. Wasn’t jiving with the process. I wanted to get to the technical takeaways. I know this comes a lot from my own impatience, but it’s also clear that these are approaches for people who can spend 2-5 hours doing creative projects. I don’t have that kind of time so I need to find my own approach.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="warm-up">Warm-up<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters#warm-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Warm-up" title="Direct link to Warm-up">​</a></h2>
<p>I did the blob challenge twice. The first time when I had limited time and the second time on a rare quiet morning. I still really do enjoy this challenge, even though I often feel head empty when I first see the shapes. I'm usually pretty pleased with one of them by the end of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Draw a creature in the blog exercise" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Blob-exercise-0d9f98a72d749c0506d9ea6360bda430.jpg" width="2000" height="1589" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Then I went to my Pinterest boards and started sketching. At first I would take one idea from each monster while scrolling. Other times I would attempt to reacted a whole creature if it felt like a good challenge. Then I stared to take single pieces and try to build up something larger just using my own ideas. Then I just drew some jellyfish.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Some of my practice sketches" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/mm-sketches-59e14192d886918c4d959a73ceeddf56.jpg" width="2500" height="1409" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I chose the moth guy to be the piece of this course. Simple enough that I felt confident I could recreate it in a new sketch. But before that I had to drop 150$ on watercolour supplies. Just had too.</p>
<p>I had tried using the Aquarelle Watercolour Pencils I already owned but found I still struggled with understanding the right way to use these. I probably could have looked up some tutorials online but other then a new sketchbook I hadn't bought any new art materials since started these classes 6 months ago. Felt like a reasonable time to put some money into the hobby, especially if it was going to help motivate me in a course.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="final-project">Final project<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters#final-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final project" title="Direct link to Final project">​</a></h2>
<p>Moth guy, who I started to call Mothmon because I felt he had Digimon design energy, got researched and then painted. Snapped a photo and then brought the painting into Procreate.</p>
<img src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Mothmon-paints-356c34b1679ee72cee650d2b7a43b3e6.png" width="400">
<p>It's here that Eva's mix media technique really starts to shine. She's all about doing small adjustments and touch ups or additions that blend in with the existing piece. With the goal of making everything look like it could still be a traditional art piece. And choosing when to push past that line with some stronger digital techniques.</p>
<p>This is a very slow process, and I worked very zoomed in on the screen to try to keep the touchups subtle. But once I zoomed out and did a before and after comparison I started to feel pretty happy about how everything was coming together.</p>
<img src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Mothmon-swap-9c40e47247a7d79038a8294bb56bd6b0.gif" width="400">
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="post-course-extracurriculars">Post course extracurriculars<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/mixed-media-monsters#post-course-extracurriculars" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Post course extracurriculars" title="Direct link to Post course extracurriculars">​</a></h2>
<p>I put a few hours into touching up Mothmon before decided to call it quits on the piece. The most time I've put into a work for a while. Since I was still riding the excitement of a new art supply purchase I returned to the new watercolours the next weekend to keep practicing how to use them.</p>
<p>Maybe it was because this course was still fresh in my mind, but I stumbled across an illustrator who I found wildly inspiring just after finishing the Mothmon piece. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/josephine__draws/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Josephine__Draws</a> on Instagram. They do gorgeous monochrome pieces, mostly focused on animals, bones, and shells. They work with very strong lines while mixing in watercolour elements. The kind of stuff that makes me want to pick up a pencil and draw whenever I see it.</p>
<p>They sadly don't have much of an online presence beyond their Instagram page so I'm going to have to survive on their short looping videos.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The basics of illustrations]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration"/>
        <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I put off a lot of the full illustration classes, to me they feel like putting together all the bits you’ve learned to try to make something more comprehensive. I had also hoped they would be more digital tool focused than traditional drawing tips but one like Laia Lopez’s are pretty basic on the technical aspects if you’re already familiar with the basics of the program you’re using. This course was titled 'Digital illustration for beginners' so maybe it's just time that I start taking the courses marked 'Intermediate' instead.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I put off a lot of the full illustration classes, to me they feel like putting together all the bits you’ve learned to try to make something more comprehensive. I had also hoped they would be more digital tool focused than traditional drawing tips but one like Laia Lopez’s are pretty basic on the technical aspects if you’re already familiar with the basics of the program you’re using. This course was titled 'Digital illustration for beginners' so maybe it's just time that I start taking the courses marked 'Intermediate' instead.</p>
<p>I enjoyed the exercises she proposed but I don’t feel like they prepared me for working on a full illustration.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="eyes">Eyes<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration#eyes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Eyes" title="Direct link to Eyes">​</a></h2>
<p>This was an exercise I doubted because I’ve done a lot of practice eyes since I started taking these courses. But this one did make me feel like I spotted a few things that make eyes more expressive with just a few lines. What I'd really like to be able to do is simplify my approach to eyes as I think my big issue is I use too many eyes and then lose details.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Eyes practice sheet." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/eyes-sheet-22d6c9aea72e5e7e7548aee801ef333f.jpg" width="1083" height="1374" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="expressions">Expressions<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration#expressions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Expressions" title="Direct link to Expressions">​</a></h2>
<p>This program provided a classic expression sheet which was nice to use. I hadn’t planned on doing all three rows because while I worked on it I realised I don’t have characters other than Skil that I draw regularly. Which makes this exercise more difficult.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Expression sheet" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/expression-sheet-aab0aff0dccd6ac733fa466f388e641c.jpg" width="2000" height="1537" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>For row two I just wanted to draw someone with hair buns, it’s very clear I have no grasp on that face or character so it’s basic while also being all over the place. For the 3rd row I decided to go with the character from one of my earlier lessons, Queza, who is rather squid-like so I didn’t want to use her at first. But in the end it was nice to play around with a less human face.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="clothing-and-posing">Clothing and posing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration#clothing-and-posing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Clothing and posing" title="Direct link to Clothing and posing">​</a></h2>
<p>Clothing has always been a weakness of mine, not because of folds and understanding fabric but because I don’t have much creativity for designing outfits. I’ll usually got with simple outfits, not too many layers. Or the classic cheat of; if I’m comfortable with the figure I’ve draw I’ll put them in something fitting, if I’m not comfortable with the proportions/figure I’ll hide the body under something baggier.</p>
<p>For this homework I used an image from <a href="https://www.etsy.com/ca/listing/1091751570/solid-array-wrap-wrap-vest-scarf-belted" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Modern Wizard Apparel's Esty shop</a>. I recently ordered a few pieces from there and love them, so you can take this as an endorsement.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Clothing practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Illustration-homework-clothing-a1eb8fe0066d097a9a7b474dac0a7b6a.jpg" width="2000" height="1585" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>For the posing homework, there was the fun suggestion have having three random curved lines and building a pose around that. I asked my girlfriend to draw three line and then had to deal with a terrifying N-like shape. I struggled with that one for a pretty long time but I’m pretty happy with the dive pose I ended up on.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Pose practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Illustration-homework-2-2d1c5c454cdcde0eb47713dc74962399.jpg" width="2000" height="1538" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-project">The project<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration#the-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The project" title="Direct link to The project">​</a></h2>
<p>So one of my biggest weaknesses as a creative is that I’m extremely impatient. One of the reasons I enjoy writing is because I can go really fast and feel good about having just written something down. When it comes to more physical hobbies like drawing or piano, I’m too impatient to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Practice</li>
<li>Take my time when it’s needed</li>
</ol>
<p>I’m forcing the practice by taking all these courses. Just really trying to let myself be messy with art and try new things. Which is why I often do all the homework assignments. But for point 2, when it comes to “putting something together at the end of the course” I tend to just… not. This is partially because I just want to jump into something new and partially because I know it will take me hours of work to make anything I’m really happy with. And these days I just don’t know where I’ll find hours of free time to put into a larger project.</p>
<p>I did the thumbnailing part of the course, the first step of starting an illustration. Even came up with a few ideas I liked:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Illustration thumbnails for a Queza piece" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/queza-thumbnails-4b7f4b2f3dc87b5e03165c71b51cc377.jpg" width="1258" height="1281" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>But the thought of having to commit to one just didn’t appeal to me. I put some time into trying to start one of them as a more serious piece, got distracted looking up fish brushes for Clip Studio, didn’t know how to design the 2nd character, and then gave up. A whole illustration just feels a little out of my reach still. Partially because I didn’t find that this course to provided too much in terms of foundational steps or approaches to things like backgrounds or styling. A bit of “and then draw a background”, which isn’t where I’m at yet. This is about as much progress as this piece will ever see:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Queza and a fish tank" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Queza-illu-3c547db16b4c2377806c1cf85c20d339.jpg" width="2000" height="2000" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-illustrations">The illustrations<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/digital-illustration#the-illustrations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The illustrations" title="Direct link to The illustrations">​</a></h2>
<p>I gave illustration another shot when I went camping for a few days. This time I wanted to focus more on the steps and not coming up with a scene on my own so I used <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/697495061015057710" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this image as a reference</a>. There’s a fair bit of photography on these cormorant fishermen which are extremely beautiful. And it's a testament to how terrible the internet is these days that I can't verify who the exact photographer of the image I linked is. A curse I blame Pinterest for. A possible source (and some history behind the fishing practice), can be read about here: <a href="https://mymodernmet.com/peter-yan-travel-photography-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Interview: Travel Photographer Highlights China’s Traditional Cormorant Fishing</a>.</p>
<p>This one felt a little promising at the start, felt like I was capturing the pose in the sketch and I liked how the background looked when I just laid down 4 different colours for the major shapes/features. That feeling didn’t last too long once I got into the inking.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Side by side comparison" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Fisherman-progress-shot1-76a3b9dd28701178263a9e02837c687b.png" width="1479" height="908" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>It’s still hard for me to find time to focus on art fully, all I was really getting (on my vacation week!) was 20 minutes when I got into bed. I feel different about it every time I open it up, and have a running list of things I want to improve. But I’m already at the point of “even if I finish this I’m not going to be happy with it” so I’m ready to toss it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Final fisherman progress shot" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Fisherman-wip-d39f451b6dbbe4fd74b91607ec426508.jpg" width="2000" height="2000" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I know pushing through is probably what’s going to help me learn and become more comfortable with larger works but doing full colour, large digital illustrations isn’t really my end goal when it comes to art so I’m less invested in improving in that area right now.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drawing cute creatures with beans]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After feeling pretty disappointed by the first creature course, I was excited after watching the introduction to ‘Designing Fun Animal Characters’ by Rodgon. His approach made sense to me right from the start.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After feeling pretty disappointed by the first creature course, I was excited after watching the introduction to ‘Designing Fun Animal Characters’ by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/rodgontheartist/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rodgon</a>. His approach made sense to me right from the start.</p>
<ol>
<li>Figure out the stand out physical features of a creature</li>
<li>Work from a simple base</li>
<li>Put those stand out features on the simple base</li>
</ol>
<p>After enjoying my tiny goat lesson from earlier in the year, I was hype to get back to drawing animals again.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="creature-features">Creature features<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach#creature-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Creature features" title="Direct link to Creature features">​</a></h2>
<p>Did a few random animal sketches to warm up. Asking my girlfriend to name an animal, I would Google it, and then try to draw it. Resulted in some basic little guys but the animals happened to not have the easiest features to capture.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Some random creatures as warm ups." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/animal-sketches1-e5331a044cdc0df0d2af323590b467e9.jpg" width="1000" height="1510" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="the-bean-approach">The bean approach<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach#the-bean-approach" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The bean approach" title="Direct link to The bean approach">​</a></h2>
<p>After spending some time looking at animals and trying to figure out what makes them stand out, it was time to get to the base of our future creatures; the bean bag. Or as I took to referring to it; the beans.</p>
<p>The exercise started off pretty simple, make some bean shapes and then draw contour lines around them to understand the 3D shape of the bean bag aka future creature. This is to help add the feature after and to just have a better grasp of the space being occupied by the bean.</p>
<p>I was pretty happy with my lined beans by the end of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="My lined beans floating in space." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/blank-beans-4ab20aee86a5db5dc5fb59649211dd15.jpg" width="1500" height="1498" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Next we moved on to adding the features. I tried to get as many random animal references as possible. Which resulted with me pulling cards out of this box’s ‘Biology’ section to get an animal at random. Some beans turned out better than others. But even the messy ones helped me realize how I’d approach that animal differently on a second go.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Some beans that kind of look like creatures." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/IMG_0124-fab13fe1a01cd7c50c986d6ca339acba.jpg" width="1506" height="1460" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="technicalities-of-technology">Technicalities of technology<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach#technicalities-of-technology" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Technicalities of technology" title="Direct link to Technicalities of technology">​</a></h2>
<p>The rest of the course was more focused on important information you’d want to know if you were to pursue digital art professionally. Rodgon went over file sizes, what they mean, when to save as certain file types and what to be aware of when designing for specific requests.</p>
<p>He spent a long time showing us his inking process in Adobe Illustrator which was rather eye opening to me. I’d only ever opened the program once or twice before and had no idea how to use it. Seeing how the inking is so different from other digital art programs was pretty inspiring. Looked like a fun way to approach the task. So it’s a shame I don’t ever see myself forking over the money to Adobe to try it out for myself.</p>
<p>Overall it was interesting to see a full piece come together that’s pretty different from the other lessons I’d followed so far that also included one piece going from sketches to completion. And I like how Rodgon shares super practical tips and approaches. Looking forward to drawing many bean shapes in my future.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="a-non-art-course-interlude">A non art course interlude<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/bean-approach#a-non-art-course-interlude" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A non art course interlude" title="Direct link to A non art course interlude">​</a></h2>
<p>So on top of trying to do 1-2 art courses a month, I have also signed up for a 5 week program on cephalopods. This is a weekly lecture through Atlas Obscura which I just thought would be fun. I also thought it would be helpful to learn more ocean creature facts for my Underwater D&amp;D campaign. Which has already started to pay off.</p>
<p>Instead of taking notes during the course I tried to focus on sketching some of the creatures the teacher shared. So these are my sketches from lesson one.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Cuttle fish, squids, and octopuses." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/squid-class1-e26318b4daff79f235d7bf67826a2564.jpg" width="1000" height="923" class="img_wQsy"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Storytelling with illustrations]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations"/>
        <updated>2023-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I managed to finished a a course at the start of May before Tears of the Kingdom came out, ‘Telling a Story Through Illustration’.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I managed to finished a a course at the start of May before Tears of the Kingdom came out, <a href="https://www.21-draw.com/my-course/?id=46594" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">‘Telling a Story Through Illustration’</a>.</p>
<p>I was a little intimidated by this course because the idea of doing full illustrations still feels very challenging to me. Make a scene, draw a background, manage areas of focus and lighting. All the parts of drawing in one. Which I feel like I’ll never be ready for!</p>
<p>Thankfully this was another Tony Bancroft course and I’ve come to love his approach and his assignments. As a classically trained animator he’s focused on foundational aspects which is exactly what I still want to focus on.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="frame-and-composition">Frame and composition<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations#frame-and-composition" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Frame and composition" title="Direct link to Frame and composition">​</a></h2>
<p>The courses started off by talking about the frame (the area in which your art piece will exist) and composition. In my High School art classes composition was what the art teacher praised me for most. I didn’t really understand what it meant back then, but I now think it means I had a pretty natural grasp of the use of space. This section had the mini assignment of creating different kinds of traditional compositions using only basic shapes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Quarters, thirds, split, and other composition types" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Composition-1-4566738bb8202092e92d3de8b800a1d6.jpg" width="3960" height="2518" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="horizon-lines-and-your-point-of-view">Horizon lines and your point of view<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations#horizon-lines-and-your-point-of-view" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Horizon lines and your point of view" title="Direct link to Horizon lines and your point of view">​</a></h2>
<p>The next section covered different ways to layout a scene. Horizon lines are that line in an image that’s usually the split between the ground and the sky. Tony shared examples on how different horizon line placements can dramatically change what’s in focus in the scene or how they can be used to shift perspective.</p>
<p>In my two practice runs I tried a very high horizon line to have more space to work with a landscape. While in the second I tried a low and angled horizon line to show the size differences between the mouse and the cat while trying to create more dynamics with a tilted line.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Adding details to Style A" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Composition-2-b23b7bbd3407a1085032d0dfeea9491e.jpg" width="4000" height="1275" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>The other assignment for this section was to Push You Point of View. Which means to move away from a flat scene where everything might have equal prominence to one that creates more depth by using a different point of view. The challenge provided was to draw a young girl looking up at a bird singing in a tree.</p>
<ol>
<li>Low POV looking up at the bird</li>
<li>High POV from the bird angled down</li>
<li>Flat POV where neither is in more focus</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Point of view practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/POV-1-c2adbc833c1a76e566e893464addfed0.jpg" width="2635" height="3500" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I really liked this as an exercise as I rarely push for different angles in my pieces but these quick sketches very easily show that the first two images are way more interesting composition wise than the last one.</p>
<h1>Depth, lines, overlap</h1>
<p>The rest of the course covered a few more tricks for creating a good composition.</p>
<p>Depth: Work with foreground, middle, and background
Lines of action: Use the lines of everything in the scene to point towards your focus area
Overlap: Overlap objects to create more depth and a more natural look</p>
<p>My first attempt at a scene using these tips, followed by pushing it with an up angle and down angle approach:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Adventurers in a dungeon" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/POV-2-80ea4e83a38d38cab99276eeab8a4e76.png" width="3037" height="3375" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>And then a new piece to try to capture all the different parts of the course. I maybe only managed to get in directional lines and different depth levels. Directional lines were my main focus as I didn’t use them as much in previous home works. And I find all the final “now put it all together and draw something” assignments to easily feel overwhelming, it’s difficult to think of something that feels like all the rules can be used. But the pros make it all look easy to bring the pieces together so I know it’s possible, but my brain doesn’t think in those processes just yet.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Mermaid for MerMay" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Composition-3-0ceb635b9291c2897d8f89e8b781e691.jpg" width="2524" height="1730" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="next-course">Next course<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/storytelling-illustrations#next-course" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next course" title="Direct link to Next course">​</a></h2>
<p>I complained about the creature design course last time, but forgot to share that I did do the first assignment from it: drawing the skeletal and muscular structure of a creature.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Deer anatomy exercise" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Deer-anatomy-673af1ea3ee78fb252319d4f30508daa.jpg" width="3000" height="1841" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>This was kind of fun and I can see it being helpful for doing more serious creature design. There’s lots of different animal anatomy out there to learn! But instead I’m going on to the ‘Designing Fun Animal Characters’ course to instead learn the much more simplified approach to creatures.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[April Art Projects]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters"/>
        <updated>2023-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April I went through the course ‘How to Stylize Characters’.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In April I went through the course <a href="https://www.21-draw.com/my-course/?id=42788" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">‘How to Stylize Characters’</a>.</p>
<p>I wasn’t sure what to expect from this course. “Style” is a very nebulous thing, one that I’ve been told over and over again will develop with time and mastery of the basics. The course ended up focusing more on how you can work in different styles by taking different approaches and really iterating on your ideas.</p>
<p>The teacher broke down each part of the course with very well focused assignments and practical steps. With the idea being to draw the same character to match two different use cases. He was working on developing a Frankenstein’s Monster character while I made the mistake of choosing one of my own D&amp;D characters who I’ve iterated on a few times already. I say this was a mistake as choosing a fresh character would have given me more freedom to experiment instead of feeling locked in a previously established character design. But even with that mistake on my side I felt like I was able to learn a lot from the assignments.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="start-with-the-basics">Start with the basics<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters#start-with-the-basics" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Start with the basics" title="Direct link to Start with the basics">​</a></h2>
<p>I went with the same use cases (aka briefs) that tee instructure went with as the two styles I’d aim for:</p>
<ul>
<li>A 2D childrens cartoon vibe</li>
<li>A 3D more grown up cartoon vibe</li>
</ul>
<p>Step one was to do silhouettes. This built on the silhouettes covered in the previous courses, where you want to make sure your main character features are able to stand out even when working with a pure black silhouette. For the 2D version the focus was on working with basic shapes; circles, squares, triangles, etc. Then doing some simple shaping on those. For the 3D version the approach was more freehand, blocking out shapes with fewer restrictions and more details.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Style A silhouettes" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/style-a-blocks-dab87bb4456cb3e5046ecf2256761d9d.jpg" width="1316" height="1066" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>This process was really challenging for me, I felt like I struggled to bring anything unique to each new form. Hell, barely felt like I could make a decent looking basic shape, they all looked so awkward! But with a bit of extra refinement in shape, I was able to settle on 3 to take to the next step.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Adding details to Style A" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/style-a-edits-62335bb445e5486d1e6c1bd4180ae339.jpg" width="1169" height="826" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="onto-style-b">Onto Style B<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters#onto-style-b" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Onto Style B" title="Direct link to Onto Style B">​</a></h2>
<p>With Style B being more free to freehand sketch I ended up falling into old patterns for this character. It was at this point that I felt like I had made a misstep in not choosing a fresh character to work with and didn't go much further with the exercise.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Style B sketches" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/style-b-drafts-af6fcde0170677ea8c254e357e33bae5.jpg" width="1248" height="868" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>While I didn't take either of the styles to completion, this was probably one of my favourite courses so far. The differences between approaches felt unique, the process that was shown to iterate through designs, and how to mix and match pieces you liked all just made sense when seeing them in practice.</p>
<p>I can definitely see sitting down to go through this whole course again with a different character in mind.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="on-to-the-next-one">On to the next one<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/stylized-characters#on-to-the-next-one" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to On to the next one" title="Direct link to On to the next one">​</a></h2>
<p>After this course I was very excited to start <a href="https://www.21-draw.com/my-course/?id=2664" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">‘Creature Design’</a> because I have a list of creatures I want to sketch out for my underwater D&amp;D campaign. However, this course ended up being more like ‘doing an illustration with a creature’ and less about how to strategically approach designing your own creatures. I gave it a shot by sitting through 1 of it’s 8 hours but felt like it wasn’t worth my time.</p>
<p>Feeling a little deflated by my first ‘DNF’ I didn’t touch anything for a few weeks. I've now found another course that's getting me excited to sit down and sketch so hoping to get back to more regular practice!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding character to characters]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/expressive-design</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/expressive-design"/>
        <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a month focused more on digital art practices I decided to go with more challenging courses for April. Not challenging on a technical level, but challenging because this has always been something I've felt my own drawings have lacked; energy and expression.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a month focused more on digital art practices I decided to go with more challenging courses for April. Not challenging on a technical level, but challenging because this has always been something I've felt my own drawings have lacked; energy and expression.</p>
<p>One of the March courses touched on this a little, going into the importance of silhouette and body language. I felt like that course had a lot of practical advice that was easy to start bringing in to my sketches. So I wanted to find a course that would keep elaborating on these approaches. Ending up on one titled <a href="https://www.21-draw.com/my-course/?id=4457&amp;lesson_id=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"How to Bring You Characters to Life."</a></p>
<p>I wasn't sure what to expect from the course as I knew it would be different from the typical, here's how to understand anatomy that lots of art classes start with. Thankfully the instructor started by breaking down the main parts of a character that add life to an image.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="hands-and-eyes">Hands and Eyes<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/expressive-design#hands-and-eyes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hands and Eyes" title="Direct link to Hands and Eyes">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Practicing different kinds of eyes" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Eyes-emote-e1bf635552f531012dcc1dda560bdaa0.png" width="1639" height="1632" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>First came eyes, putting them on faces, playing around with eye brows. I think the big take away from this was just acknowledging how alive a shape can become with very simple eyes thrown on it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Dreaded hands" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hands-emote-89843a02237c2e3d3c6a1cfbd81623b7.jpg" width="3072" height="1887" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Like many artists, I struggle with hands. Found a good reference sheet of hand photos to use for these sketches and I'm actually pretty happy with most of them. Sure they aren't clean but they convey the shape I was aiming for in most cases. Which is more of the goal of this course in particular. Find the bare minimum to keep the message in the shapes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="squash-and-squish">Squash and squish<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/expressive-design#squash-and-squish" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Squash and squish" title="Direct link to Squash and squish">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Squash and squish" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Squash-squish-6f1df6fdc70354678ccc06af0d6cea33.png" width="2343" height="1688" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>This jump sequence was done to practice 'squash and squish'. Terms that come from animation for how you manipulate bodies, faces, etc. to emphasize motion and expression. You tend to give yourself more leeway with anatomy while communicating the motion that's happening.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Facial expressions" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/expression-emote-161c568404eb61a943dd9123ad4fa42c.jpg" width="2053" height="3276" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Squash and squish come into play in expressions to show movement in the face to convey emotions. While I understand the simple pieces to this I struggle adapting expressions to characters as I feel like I lose what makes a character face unique. In this practice I tried to ignore that fear and just push the expressions as far as I could. Which did result in some pretty ridiculous looking faces.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="bringing-it-together">Bringing it together<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/expressive-design#bringing-it-together" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Bringing it together" title="Direct link to Bringing it together">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Gesture drawing" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Gesture-drawing1-0688c6376fc56c8ae8bb8b4a0cc3f698.png" width="1784" height="1564" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>Did some full body gesture studies to try incorporating some of the tips that were covered. It's interesting to return to gesture drawing in every course while taking in the advice of new teachers each time.</p>
<p>After all those exercises the final piece of homework was supposed to be to bring it all together in a character drawing. I started that but... made a bad choice of reference image that didn't offer much life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Skril with a staff" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Skril-wip-course-674be5669061a64cd1fadf18138f92e6.jpg" width="2048" height="2048" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I then got hooked on wanting to work on this piece as I was actually pretty happy with parts of it and felt like I was making decent improvements every time I went back to it. But then I got stuck on hating the face and had the realization that I was no longer practicing the material covered in the course. So instead of pushing forward on the piece I closed Procreate and went to choose a new course to try again.</p>
<p>Started on a stylizing characters course a few days ago which pulls on a lot of the advice from this course so I'm hoping that it will help cement a lot of what I picked up here while I continue trying to really figure out these foundational techniques.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[March Lessons]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/more-courses</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/more-courses"/>
        <updated>2023-03-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For March I tried out a few shorter courses, two focused on getting familiar with Procreate and one about bringing life to your poses.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For March I tried out a few shorter courses, two focused on getting familiar with Procreate and one about bringing life to your poses.</p>
<p>The Procreate ones were fun, focusing on creating a single piece from start to finish while learning some of Procreates key features. These tended to focus on portraits, which aren't usually my own focus but they're a good place to start.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="from-pencil-to-procreate">From pencil to Procreate<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/more-courses#from-pencil-to-procreate" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to From pencil to Procreate" title="Direct link to From pencil to Procreate">​</a></h2>
<p>Course one was made by <a href="https://twitter.com/feefal_" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Feefal</a>, the artist who ran #funguary last month. Her program starts with pencil and paper then bringing that over to Procreate to add colours. It was nice to work with physical objects again so I enjoyed working on paper to create the original outline for this piece.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sketch of octogirl" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/octo-girl-sketch-d330240595ac2fd69f7b3a6dffaff2ca.jpg" title="First sketch" width="1832" height="1970" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I also felt like she really showed how to mimic her style by using specific brushes and colouring techniques. She definitely uses a few approaches I never do so it was cool to push myself beyond my comfort zone and kind of trust her process.</p>
<p>Having just recently kicked off a new D&amp;D campaign I knew I wanted to try and use my drawing time to create character art for future NPCs in the game. For this exercise I chose an octopus type person inspired by the <a href="https://www.mtggoldfish.com/price/Streets+of+New+Capenna/Queza+Augur+of+Agonies-showcase#paper" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cephalid</a> from Magic The Gathering. The end result doesn't look like something I would have reached on my own, so I'm pretty happy that it feels like something new.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sketch of octogirl" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/octo-girl-98b7c335c4bb39a375954a0a0b42a4fc.png" title="Final octo girl result" width="1935" height="2542" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="making-expressive-poses">Making expressive poses<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/more-courses#making-expressive-poses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making expressive poses" title="Direct link to Making expressive poses">​</a></h2>
<p>Since I got through that course in a weekend I quickly jumped into another: Drawing Character Poses with Personality. This one was pretty different from everything I'd taken so far. For one, Tony Bancroft is a traditional animator who started the program with paper and pencil. It feels like he's coming from a background of animation and storytelling more then the previous teachers who felt like they specialized in character design and illustration.</p>
<p>The tricks and theory he taught were great. Really broke down some ideas that seemed complex into very digestible tips. He didn't have too many assignments during the course so I only have these few messy sketches:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Character expression practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/IMG_0088-6d8d0d53b482cd6870ca0ed4a1a3d1ec.png" width="1169" height="1664" class="img_wQsy">
<img loading="lazy" alt="Character expression practice" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/IMG_0089-e09ccdd5d1ab9c8f838cc12d79dbe42f.png" width="1624" height="941" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_FNw8" id="back-to-procreate">Back to Procreate<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/more-courses#back-to-procreate" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Back to Procreate" title="Direct link to Back to Procreate">​</a></h2>
<p>After that theory focused, traditional approach I went back to another short Procreate lesson, this time by Erika Wiseman. This course was very similar to the first Procreate one I did, find inspiration on Pinterest, create a character, learn some Procreate tips.</p>
<p>There were a few techniques presented that I didn't care for and felt like they aren't great for refining technical skill so I didn't incorporate them into my sketching for the assignments. But I was very happy to learn the quick trick for making a layer for checking your values.</p>
<p>I once again made things more difficult for myself by now drawing a human. Choosing instead to take some inspiration from magical looking owl creatures. Maybe they'll make an appearance in a D&amp;D campaign some day.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Owl?" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/owl-woods-ec44bb9ebbc3e66114013ad3ebe746c1.jpeg" width="2048" height="2048" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>After slow progress in February it was nice to be able to check off 3 courses in one month. Next month I'll try to focus on more character design courses, but we'll see if I stick to it or get distracted by some of the new courses that 21 Draw has been teasing.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fungal February]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/funguary-2023</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/funguary-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[February was #funguary over on Twitter. A yearly art challenged focused on making different types of mushrooms into creatures hosted by @feefal.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>February was #funguary over on Twitter. A yearly art challenged focused on making different types of mushrooms into creatures hosted by <a href="https://twitter.com/feefal_" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@feefal_</a>.</p>
<p>I stumbled across this challenge in December and kept it in mind for my year of art practice.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Funguary 2023 is soon upon us! A February drawing challenge based around fungi🍄
Here are the rules and all the prompts for the month! -- feef (@feefal_)</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="The Funguary Challenge" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Funguary-80ec907906263727aaff7c007f18e8af.png" title="The rules of Funguary." width="1076" height="1212" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>A few years ago I was doing monthly challenges like this a few times a year. Those often meant drawing something new every day. For this challenge, I followed the suggested format of doing one a week to keep things more manageable.</p>
<p>In an attempt to make the process smoother for myself I spent time on Pinterest collecting images of all the suggested mushrooms for each week. With this reference collection I spent the first few days of the month sketching the mushrooms. I was hoping to do this for every week but it ended up taking more time then I expected.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Photo of my sketchbook" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/mushroom-sketches-27cb1d914090db29fdde3586ebcd19af.jpeg" title="Photo of my sketchbook, a page of mushrooms." width="818" height="1024" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I also spent time doing thumbnails for a few of the weeks. I wanted to use that as a chance to push past my first idea and try out different compositions or concepts. But just like sketching mushroom, this took up a fair bit of my limited drawing time so towards the end I started to skip this step.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Simple thumbnails" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/funguary-thumbnails-74f827d0374d9f65d746a6e967a4aab1.jpg" title="Some quick thumbnails for brainstorming." width="1500" height="1026" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>There were a lot of fun mushrooms discovered during this month so I was a little sad to only choose 4 to focus on. I did end up trying to fit in a few of the other ones in to a few of the projects. These are my 4 final pieces:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="My 4 Funguary pieces" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/all-fungals-2023-141444e5020a0be387016dd199a5cc19.png" title="My four fungal friends." width="3000" height="3000" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I resisted doing any cute lady mushrooms as that was my first instinct. But it felt too easy to just turn all the mushrooms into dresses. I'm not super happy with any of the pieces but there are parts that I like about all of them. I feel like #3 is decently creepy, I like how the shading came out on the body of #4 and I'm shocked I tried to do a scene in #2. I regret not tracking how much time was put into each one as I know I kicked out the last one in one day while the first one took at least 3.</p>
<p>Over the course of the month I did feel like I was improving and becoming more comfortable with Clip Studio Paint as time went on. It was nice to remember a few tricks to using the software too, proof that I hadn't forgotten everything I learned a few years ago.</p>
<p>I don't think I'll do another challenge like this for a few months as it ate away at my actual art lesson time. But it was very nice to take a break from figure drawing humans all the time.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with 21Draw]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/getting-started</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/getting-started"/>
        <updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Towards the end of 2022 I had already started thinking of 2023 as a year I wanted to make more of an effort to get back into drawing. I missed being creative and hated watching my large collection of expensive markers slowly dry out and die.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Towards the end of 2022 I had already started thinking of 2023 as a year I wanted to make more of an effort to get back into drawing. I missed being creative and hated watching my large collection of expensive markers slowly dry out and die.</p>
<p>While browsing Twitter one night I saw an artist I followed had recently published an art course on <a href="https://www.21-draw.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21Draw</a>. I'd never heard of the website before and was surprised to see that it was possibly the perfect fit for my 2023 goals. Online art lessons focused on core skills and even digital tools I was already familiar with.</p>
<p>I don't usually like buying something as soon as I see it but I got sucked in by the countdown clock at the top of the page promoting an End of Year Discount. 2 subscriptions for 1/3rd the price of a normal signal subscription. And I only had 5 hours left to take advantage!</p>
<p>So anyway, 30 minutes after finding the site I was registered and ready to go with a whole year of access.</p>
<p>While I was very excited to get to the courses focused on character design, Clip Studio, and Procreate, I forced myself to choose a beginner course as my first lesson. Then after the first lesson to stick to some core lessons like anatomy and perspective. So basically figure drawing all the time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Screenshot of the course page" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/figure-drawing-class-1eb55938e3a38f3898f1946d35969282.png" title="Figure drawing class" width="800" height="866" class="img_wQsy"></p>
<p>I'm now entering month two and I'm finding my time to devote to course material fading. Balancing two D&amp;D campaigns, other hobbies, and drawing is still a struggle. But thanks to the February drawing challenged called #Funguary over on Twitter I'm still putting in some drawing time every few days. Just a little less focused then I'd like it to be. I'll talk about #Funguary in my next post.</p>
<p>Hoping that in March I'll have more then just a few figure drawing sketches to share.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="21draw" term="21draw"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi!</p>
<p>This blog is going to be used to document my Return To Art.</p>
<p>I used to draw regularly, then I returned to working full time and the hobby died while I was busy doing a capitalism. Trying to find a little more balance for hobbies in my life now by making a conscious effort to take courses and build habits around regular practice.</p>
<p>My plan is to use this blog to document my lesson homework and other art challenges I try to take on over the rest of the year.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
</feed>