<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://kymira.ca/blog</id>
    <title>Kymira Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kymira.ca/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Kymira Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://kymira.ca/img/favicon2.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 2]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.</p>
<p>Not a huge change in the asset tracker as I wrapped up most of the small part and have spent the last 5 days in focused background mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/asset-tracking-week2-8ee3e007d5ece8383347068f29718aab.png" width="544" height="254" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="asset-creation">Asset creation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#asset-creation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Asset creation" title="Direct link to Asset creation">​</a></h2>
<p>Between backgrounds I was able to wrap up jackets (multiple forms for each character) for the 3 characters who can be seen outside on the first day of the game. Also designed this logo for an in-world restaurant:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/takeout-b8f96154c8d420e43885b0ac9bc6d3b6.png" width="254" height="300" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Drew a hand and a portal, multiple little cats. I really like doing these small one offs as I feel like I can experiment with them versus backgrounds which are way more demanding mentally. But since most of the small assets are done it’s been a pretty big week for background work.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I had a pretty terrible time with this street scene I worked on for 4 days.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-day-89b3797c1dff066b134bb3b77cadb007.png" width="1280" height="724" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m going to point out all the things wrong with it but I ask that you wipe the mistakes from your brain when you play the game.</p>
<p>I started fairly confidently, really loved the back line of buildings and managed to keep it mostly flat rectangles. Then I moved on to the right side of the street. Activated the perspective ruler and started to draw some buildings. It was decided that the eye line was too high and I told myself I would push all the lines down with the Transform tool once I had them done. But then I came back the next day and pushed them down and altered the perspective ruler and then started the left side. I didn’t realize how much I had altered the ruler by the time I was done with the lines on the left side. I kept returning to the right side, trying to push it down more, trying to fix the roof which I drew in after the shift because the top of the buildings didn’t exist in the first pass.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-perspective-lines-6337c03fc1bebab9261cb3c312117082.png" width="1282" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Something I had gotten good at for the first few days was Deleting My Art. A very common and helpful art tip. Didn’t like how a character was looking? Delete it. All the lines look bad? Delete them. There is learning to be taken from sticking with something incorrect and figuring out how to fix it, but I was mostly in ideation and discovery mode, so each deletion led to something better.</p>
<p>But as I feared with starting background, I fell into sunk cost fallacy and wasn’t willing to throw away 2 hours of work. The saving grace of the piece is that I am really happy with the left side buildings and the back row. It feels Montreal-esque without being too on the nose. And while I’m still struggling with colour selection in big pieces I don’t think there are too many mistakes.</p>
<p>I brought my fear into the next background I started and spent a lot of time in layout and perspective mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-room-measurements-f236e24903a38dbad90ab576bc982370.png" width="1281" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I am very happy with how main character Lauren’s room turned out. It doesn’t feel great to instantly jump into working on another character's bedroom but I’m hoping I can take what I learned from Lauren’s room and move a little faster. Lauren’s room took about 10 hours… I ended up downloading a lot of 3D objects from the Clip Studio Asset store which let me feel like I was playing with toys as I chose where to place them and size them.</p>
<p>I have 2-3 backgrounds to go, even if they all take 3 days each, which leaves me some wiggle room to revisit art pieces from earlier in the month and adding more details.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="version-01-launch">Version 0.1 launch<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#version-01-launch" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch" title="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch">​</a></h2>
<p>While conceptualizing our game we designed it around 7 days that the player would play through. When making a branching game, a solid rule is to build your Golden Path first. This can be your “happy” ending path, or the path you think most players will enjoy or gravitate towards.</p>
<p>Since our game is a romance sim it would mean choosing one of the love interests and completing their path before anyone else's. This proved difficult in a pretty big way in that one of the central parts of a romance sim is being able to choose who you romance. We worried that having one obviously foregrounded character would give the wrong vibe.</p>
<p>I kept pushing for finding a Golden Path during the build up week before the game as I’m familiar with watching new game makers spiral out of scope and get lost in the weeds. We talked it over multiple times, thinking about how the games break up in other ways. Just a day or two before the jam started we had the realization that if we wanted something that felt like a full game, we could scope by days instead of paths. We scoped down to the first 2 days of the story. The major downside being that this scoping didn’t help with scoping down asset requirements as we would still need art for each character and location.</p>
<p>And while this did mean rushing through as much art as possible in the first few days, I think this scope is what’s to credit for us being able to publish Day 1 as version 0.1 before the end of week two.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/littos-itch-3314046c65231a7437bbcbe7c4daffa5.png" width="2840" height="1404" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You can play Day 1 on our <a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/love-in-the-time-of-spellphage-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io page</a> however I do recommend downloading a version instead of playing in the browser as you’ll have a better audio and performance experience that way. We’ve gotten some positive feedback from friends already and possibly some Beta Tester who are strangers to us and have fewer reasons to be nice to us <!-- -->:o</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>The next big thing for the project is writing Day 2. We have some ideas on these scenes but it will likely be a fair bit of brainstorming still. For myself, I’ll likely be in background mode for the next week as we don’t even know all the scenes or locations we’ll need for Day 2 yet...</p>
<p>We’re also hoping to get feedback during week 3 and incorporate anything actionable before the end of the month.</p>
<p>It’s likely to be another focused week and I already feel myself longing to do art that doesn’t involve a perspective ruler. But feeling very accomplished in what we've been able to make so far!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 1]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New year new projects, starting with the Sealed With a Kiss game jam. My wife and I started work on the project bright and early on January first. With just a few days of vacation left I wanted to get as many assets done as I could before returning to work on Monday. Which has led to creating more art in a few days than any period last year.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New year new projects, starting with the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/swakjam-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sealed With a Kiss game jam</a>. My wife and I started work on the project bright and early on January first. With just a few days of vacation left I wanted to get as many assets done as I could before returning to work on Monday. Which has led to creating more art in a few days than any period last year.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/asset_tracking-842fa416ab5722a9e8be004a7fc5696c.png" width="1230" height="406" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The speed won’t last though. I got through most of the character art but now I’m mostly left with backgrounds and I probably won’t be able to get through more than one of those every few days. So far 5-8 hours seems like the average time they requires. But we’ll see how the next week goes, for now, it’s recap time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="asset-creation">Asset creation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#asset-creation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Asset creation" title="Direct link to Asset creation">​</a></h2>
<p>We had the basics of our game flow and story figured out before we started so I was able to get a pretty solid list of “to-do” work ready before day one. Characters were the priority as they take more than just drawing time but also programming time. So if I could get the characters done quickly it would give my wife more time to work with them in Ren’py.</p>
<p>I was able to get basic sketches down for each of the 4 main characters on day one which felt like an accomplishment and was already faster than I had planned for.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/character_sketches-07804267e8c9a5ff1c866a1f8d9a05d2.png" width="1607" height="691" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Aside from characters and backgrounds we also had some smaller assets that were needed. A wand for our energy mechanic, a large book for light novel scenes. It’s unlikely that we’ve reached the end of assets and new ones will continue to arise over the next few weeks. The asset tracker Total has already increased since I took that screenshot...</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="characters">Characters<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#characters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Characters" title="Direct link to Characters">​</a></h2>
<p>After the first sketches I let the characters sit for a day before returning to them. Art Director Wife wanted our main character to look a little more "student struggling" so I spent time revisiting her. Other characters had smaller fixes up I worked on during second passes. 7 days in and I think we have most of the final details for our cast.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/character_flats-bac79168f3041e09ce377b4460d33f31.png" width="1610" height="696" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Their designs are a mix of D&amp;D inspo meets Montreal in the 80s. I spent a fair bit of time scrolling through 80s fashion and trying to find a unique look for each of them. But then I remembered we set the story in December so everyone needs a jacket layer for being outside :| The scope just keeps growing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I haven’t done too much work on backgrounds yet but I have made the promising discovery of the default Pointillism brush in CSP. We had envisioned a slightly more abstract or impressionistic backgrounds and I wasn’t sure how to approach this. I spent a decent amount of time just testing brushes to find something pleasing to work with and look at. It’s worked for the one background that has a lot of plants and snow, now I’ll just hope it can hold up in backgrounds that have more buildings.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ao_day-819a6c377ba9cf8382836a9c138b5c96.png" width="1281" height="722" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Indoor scenes will be another whole thing. I don’t think pointillism will work as well there so I expect a decent amount of trial and error. So far I only have this computer background which still needs a fair bit of work but I wanted to get it in early since it’s a big part of the game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/computer_background-22481a10e68c6dfe174a7a26f3eade09.png" width="1924" height="1082" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>An additional added goal to backgrounds is having a day and night version of each scene. Ren’py has some shaders which can be applied to backgrounds and images on top of backgrounds which give a lot of options. But for outdoor scenes I’m going to try to do 2 versions of each:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ao_park_both-04ca40e0f3824ec7f9fdda1e074d619f.png" width="3840" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Also, a huge shout out to the Clip Studio Asset store. Everyone sharing assets is saving me hours of work, just some great stuff in there.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-game-so-far">The game so far<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-1#the-game-so-far" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The game so far" title="Direct link to The game so far">​</a></h2>
<p>While I’ve been fully focused on art assets my wife has been tackling everything else about the game. Launch screen, writing, sound effects, menus, energy mechanic, multiple text areas, music, assigning assets. Basically just everything.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/launch_screen-aa934a9db9f0cc4a691a37a942142e3a.png" width="2690" height="1496" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>As of today, the 8th, we’re almost done with day 1 of gameplay/story. This means written scenes and mechanics. There are still some missing key backgrounds, like our main character's room. We have some placeholder graphics in there currently for those. Once we have day 1 story all in place we’ll start sharing the game with some folks and try to get some feedback in hopes of actioning it before we get too far into day 2!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/day-1-activities-ca8d49e4832cc3c23f2be7ddfa3dfd37.png" width="2648" height="1490" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WAP Up]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year in review of my weekly art practice]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first launched into this goal of practicing art in a focused fashion every week I wasn’t sure I’d be able to maintain it. I also wasn’t sure if it was going to be a practice that would lead to noticeable improvements. Just drawing every day isn’t enough to keep getting better, so I was really relying on the focused methodology of practice flow to pay off.</p>
<p>Given my last 2 weeks of revisits, my new found near comfort drawing hands, and lack of fear of the blank page, I feel like it has. I did end up drawing mostly animals as a comfort zone, but then expanded my focus halfway through the year to include anatomy weeks to make sure I was still continuing to work on the fundamentals. Then in the last few months I tried to add the goal of completing a finished piece once a month as well. Easily making it my most productive art year in a decade.</p>
<p>Cara, the social media platform for artists, took off this year. I didn’t post all my finished work there but almost all these pieces are from this year:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/cara_2024-4eb6af427437f723325e7ca9667c2714.png" width="1080" height="1423" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I only posted a few of my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone backgrounds</a> there, the rest mostly only ever being posted to YouTube.</p>
<p>The best part is that I don’t feel burnt out on art. I didn’t have anyone to answer too, didn’t have many projects that took more than a week or two. Sure there were definitely days I wasn’t keen to do more WAP practice pieces, but every day I still wanted to try to find the time to do something.
Weekly Art Practice Subjects:
All my weekly themes in a list. This is mostly to create an easy way for me to find the ones I want in the future.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">1-10</th><th style="text-align:left">11-20</th><th style="text-align:left">21-30</th><th style="text-align:left">31-40</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Squirrels</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-11" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Books</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Waltz</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-31" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flowers</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pangolins</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-12" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Giant anteater</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Me</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-32" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon Hidden Ability Challenge</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pigeons</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-13" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Figure skating</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Skulls</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-33" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Swimming</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hands</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hawk</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-24" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sparrow</a></td><td style="text-align:left">Style study - <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-34" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon trainer</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hairstyles</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-15" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Penguin</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-25" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gymnastics</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Horses</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Goblins</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-16" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hyena</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Griffin</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-36" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bats</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rabbits</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Volleyball</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-27" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Material studies</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-37" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Running</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Landscapes</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-18" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sea turtle</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-28" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-38" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bicycle</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trees</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chameleon</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Horseback riding</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-39" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Revisit 1</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sword swing</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redraw (Butterfly girl)</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-30" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sugar glider</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Revisit 2</a></td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="beyond-the-wap">Beyond the WAP<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#beyond-the-wap" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Beyond the WAP" title="Direct link to Beyond the WAP">​</a></h2>
<p>For a few of the weekly studies I did end up pushing the subject matter beyond the basic 5 days. For week 4’s Hands I ended up using those hands in an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fBSK7HGX5Nc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone video</a>. The Goblin from week 6 has been turned into an animated gif, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/lpQ1jxd11gk?si=6_Cmi73tp87CkN_3&amp;t=6860" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">critiqued on a Drawclass</a>, and animated in Godot. I used the Me piece on the About page on this website. After doing a Pokemon trainer of myself I also <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kymira.ca/post/3lbwsojqvw223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">made one of my wife</a>.</p>
<p>I think practicing can feel like it’s “going nowhere” when you don’t have finished pieces you’re proud of. If I look through my blog posts it does just feel like a bunch of messy sketches and those don’t have “a use”. But this is from productivity brainrot of everything you do needs to lead to something or produce something and a big part of taking on a creative project for me was to get away from that mindset. In 2023 when I spent the year doing 21 Draw classes I felt like I didn’t have much to show for all the class time I put in. This year I have physical sketchbooks and multiple iPads filled with everything I’ve been doing. But I still want more “finished” pieces not so much to have something to show for my time but because there’s only parts of art that you get to after the sketch phase. And this year has been a lot of the sketch phase.</p>
<p>It’s easy to forget that I was also making animated backgrounds for Altar Stone for 10 months of the year. And working on some side pieces that I just felt inspired to do.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ikto-elden-5b1023d6835fdf3eb3cd1b84fee581b9.png" width="2600" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="courses">Courses<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#courses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Courses" title="Direct link to Courses">​</a></h2>
<p>While 2023 had been about trying to take as many 21 Draw courses as I could, I didn’t focus on courses this year. I’m at the Drawclass level of the Drawfee Patreon which means one, 2 hour course every month which has been a nice way to mix up art practice as it’s often on something I’m not focusing on myself.</p>
<p>Like Julia’s room class:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-interiors-49f8e1658268e0c908ce0a887b4311c5.jpg" width="3500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>And Karina’s dynamic pose class:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-dynamicposes-1-6ddc3450e6f464d3e1a305907435fd74.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/drawclass-dynamicposes-2-ed1b0a04f7a9c0033c2948f10cb81c87.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I spent some time looking at Domestika and did buy a map drawing course because I thought it would be a nice skill to develop for making D&amp;D locations. But I only ended up getting a few hours in before bouncing off it. Maybe I can revisit it during the winter holidays.</p>
<p>My favourite course of the year was probably Spencer Wan’s 2D visual effects course. It was a very intense 3(4?) hours but covered techniques I’d never seen before and really made a case for being an animator who specializes in effects. It felt like a course I could instantly take lessons from and apply them to Altar Stone videos. I shared my notes from it in my WAP 24 post (sparrows).</p>
<p>My course consumption will probably remain similar in 2025, Drawfee classes every month and a few one-offs here and there as they come up.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2025">2025<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-up#2025" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2025" title="Direct link to 2025">​</a></h2>
<p>I mentioned in one blog post already that I’m starting the year off by doing a game jam with my wife. I suspect it will be a rather big challenge, even while trying to keep the scope reasonable, so I won’t be doing any other art projects during the month.</p>
<p>In February I’m going to try to do a style study of a select artist (I’ve been putting together a list of artists I’d like to learn from). I’ve really been enjoying watching style study videos on YouTube and I’ll try to follow a similar format of how <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@thomoclock" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thom O'Clock</a> does his Render Breakdown series. I found his video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abHLAgvhUGs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the art style of Hades</a> very inspiring both in process and execution. These types of things seem decently effortful and intimidating so I’m setting my goals of doing 1 style study a month.</p>
<p>Another idea I have for a week-long project is a little less structured. I’ve created 3 Pinterest boards for the year, one is a collection of interesting looking places, one a collection of characters I like, and another for colour schemes I’d like to try. Once a month I’m going to randomly choose a piece from each Pinboard by rolling dice and then combing the character in the location while using the selected colour scheme. This is a bit of practice for learning to draw from references, to try to develop more environmental design skills and also work with colours I wouldn’t likely choose on my own.</p>
<p>I feel like anatomy studies are still important to keep in the rotation, and there are some WAP themes I wish I had thought of earlier. So I think my 2025 months might look something like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Week 1: Style Study</li>
<li>Week 2: Anatomy Week</li>
<li>Week 3: 3 Board Challenge</li>
<li>Week 4: Classic WAP</li>
</ul>
<p>I don’t yet know how much effort style study weeks or Pinterest style pieces will take. So I may need to simplify my schedule in the future. What made WAP so doable was that it was the same rotation every week. I found ways to make some days easier over time from doing it over and over again. Not sure I’ll have enough repeats to learn faster techniques for these new challenges but I'm excited to get started.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books - 2024 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Books I read in 2024]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was able to stick to my 1 book a month goal this year, squeezing in 2 extras. This was my first year of really seriously using the ebook library app, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libby_(service)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Libby</a>, since I was able to get it to finally sync with my Kobo. This makes for really random book consumption as what you’re reading at any time completely depends on when holds come in. But it also cutely led to me and my wife reading a lot of the same books.</p>
<p>In the last few years I’ve had a bit of focus to my book selection. For a while I wanted to wrap up all the series I had started. And then for a few years I had a growing number of water focused novels I wanted to read. I no longer have any large goals like that and am actually out there trying to find new authors to follow or catch up on. With the death of Twitter I no longer follow as many writers and readers so my to-read list hasn’t been growing all that quickly. The only serious source I go to for new stuff is <a href="https://kadoore.com/2024/12/14/2024-queer-adult-science-fiction-fantasy-books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">K. A. Doore’s yearly roundup of Queer Adult Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy Books</a>. I’m hoping library access will help make discovery easier going forward, but it’s a real shame how barely usable Libby is. An insult to app designers and librarians everywhere.</p>
<p>But on to the books. I tried writing this blog post a few times but found it was hard to talk about each one. So here are my top 3 and also my scoring (out of 3) for the rest.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/top-books-2024-0ce6b6d5aad599d458c35444a95668c3.jpg" width="2415" height="1200" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="floating-hotel-by-grace-curtis">Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#floating-hotel-by-grace-curtis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis" title="Direct link to Floating Hotel by Grace Curtis">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Floating Hotel</strong> was a surprise read of this year, I wouldn’t have read it if it weren’t for my wife hyping it up. It’s kind of a cozy murder mystery in space. Its setting and writing are cozy while the characters and central story are more dramatic. A high end hotel well past its prime, travels between planets hosting celebrities and the rich. It’s also a home to its staff, outcasts who can’t return to their world or people running from their past. There’s also a whole evil emperor and repressive education system thing going on but that’s not really what things are about (but also is).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="he-who-drowned-the-world-by-shelley-parker-chan">He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#he-who-drowned-the-world-by-shelley-parker-chan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan" title="Direct link to He Who Drowned The World by Shelley Parker-Chan">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>He Who Drowned The World</strong> is the sequel and conclusion to She Who Became the Sun. These two books are a powerful duo and have probably one of my favourite leading characters ever. The duology is rather violent and graphic which makes me hesitate to recommend it to people. But the main character is so driven and the villains merciless. So much backstabbing and betrayal but also loyalty and commitment to people and causes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-by-becky-chambers">A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-by-becky-chambers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers" title="Direct link to A Psalm for the Wild-Built by Becky Chambers">​</a></h2>
<p>It was nice to return to Becky Chambers after a few years. I loved her first 3 books but then I started to fall behind on her one-off releases. I really only got around to this one because our hold came up at the library. Compared to her other novels, which often take place in space, this one is set on a single planet (which I don’t think is earth) where the people are recovering from near disaster. They had accidentally created AI. The society had been supported by robot labour for a long time, and then the robots gained sentience and they didn’t want to labour for humans so they walked into the woods to disappear for a few decades. Just from that premise I was intrigued. Love the idea of a population of robots just peacing off to the woods, a common millennial wish.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rest">The rest<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#the-rest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The rest" title="Direct link to The rest">​</a></h2>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Book</th><th style="text-align:left">Thoughts</th><th style="text-align:left">Rating out of 3</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Siren Queen by Nghi Vo</td><td style="text-align:left">Historical rise of movies in a slightly magical world where making deals with a devil figure is the norm. Not nearly as many sirens as I was hoping for, way too slow and prose-y for me.</td><td style="text-align:left">1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Squid Empire by  Danna Staaf</td><td style="text-align:left">Non-fiction book about squid. Lots of good facts but I didn’t love the overall structure and flow.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Water Outlaws by S.L. Huang</td><td style="text-align:left">A decent alt-history &amp; magic adventure story. Has some similar vibes to things like She Who Became the Sun or The Poppy War but way less brutal.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Flux by Jinwoo Chong</td><td style="text-align:left">Had no idea what this was when I got into it. Was more sci-fi than expected and I liked how the main character was grappling with their childhood hero being exposed as a terrible guy.</td><td style="text-align:left">3</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Blood Ink Sister Scribe by Emma Törzs</td><td style="text-align:left">A fun adventure about magical books and those who can do magic. Got your classic rich boy and bodyguard duo, family members who haven’t spoken in years, and many, many family secrets.</td><td style="text-align:left">3</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Bookeaters by Sunyi Dean</td><td style="text-align:left">I was surprised at how dark this one started off for a book about a secret group of people who need to eat books to live.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Perséphone Station by Stina Leicht</td><td style="text-align:left">Ragtag team of ex-soliders protects secret, peaceful aliens. There was a lot of world building going on here that I wish the author showed more of in the story. But a solid space adventure overall.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Archive Undying by Emma Mieko Candon</td><td style="text-align:left">Huge robots are gods and human interfaces are needed to… feed them? Control them? Power them? A very cool world but I wish the story had been divided into 2 books because So Much Happens.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Cat Who Saves Books by Sosuke Natsukawa</td><td style="text-align:left">Kobo kept recommending this one to me so I finally bought it. Cute but a little childish and simple. I’m kind of confused about who the intended audience is as it features high schoolers who go into alternative worlds to defend the value of books. The arguments are fairly basic but I think meant to be taken like a big deal.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Familiar by Leigh Bardugo</td><td style="text-align:left">I worry I have too high of expectations for Bardugo as I haven’t really liked what she’s done since Six of Crows. This was well done but felt more formulaic than her previous work. Wanted it to be a book about women surviving men but still ended with what I felt was a boring couple.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Light from Uncommon Stars by Ryka Aoki</td><td style="text-align:left">A bit wild in its combo of student sacrifices and aliens who are running away from a cataclasm that threatens to end the known universe who are now running a doughnut shop. But its development and execution put it rather firmly in the “nothing really bad will happen here” camp.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">The Demon Haunted World by Carl Sagan and Ann Druyan</td><td style="text-align:left">Another non-fiction, but I didn’t finish this one as it was just way too long.</td><td style="text-align:left">Did not finish.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Hum by Helen Phillips</td><td style="text-align:left">So while I hated the ending (like a 2 page epilogue that nearly ruined the whole book for me. Just don’t read the epilogue maybe?), this book did grip me from the start due to the way the main character acted and just had me on edge the whole time. Doesn’t deserve to be called an “AI” book but does say some stuff about the current state of the world.</td><td style="text-align:left">2</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/books-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I rated a lot of the books a 2, and looking back on the year, it fits. There were few like, standout, amazing books that I read this year. But there was a general good enough consistency which helped me keep up my reading pace.</p>
<p>There were a lot of robots in books this year and I suspect that will continue as everyone is writing about AI now. I really loved the books I read in the last like 7ish years that had central AI plots or characters but now it feels a bit more like the “trendy thing” and I suspect the median quality of AI stories will be lower. And with Muderbot being turned into a TV series I worry more.</p>
<p>The other night I started reading To Shape a Dragon's Breath by Moniquill Blackgoose and I saw that there were 2 other books on the K.A. Doore list that mentioned dragons so now I’m kind of hoping 2025 is about dragon books. Feel those nostalgic Dragonriders of Pern feelings. Though I should probably assume that a new dragon trend is more likely brought about from Game of Thrones / House of the Dragon being huge TV hits. But as a kid who grew up obsessed with dragons, it’s always nice to see more of them.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="books" term="books"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 40]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40"/>
        <updated>2024-12-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 40 - Revisits]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WAP 40, the final WAP of 2024!</p>
<p>This is another week of revisiting animal subjects of the last year. I even tried to embrace slightly more cartoony looks for them. Really kind of trying to put my brain on auto-pilot and seeing what comes out. I went and included side by sides for each day as I realized that seeing the comparison was really what I was doing these 2 weeks for.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---sea-turtles">Day 1 - Sea turtles<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-1---sea-turtles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Sea turtles" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Sea turtles">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.1-c00802e98a5d212f91118f7089bab7d8.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.1.2-3157872e309a13de7b3c30e091122e91.jpg" width="3000" height="1200" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---chameleons">Day 2 - Chameleons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-2---chameleons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Chameleons" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Chameleons">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.2-4a8e4fa30c54e020be7b088501267a20.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.2.2-6cf42ce07b809b7f31a31f7b61a09d87.jpg" width="3000" height="1007" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---sparrows">Day 3 - Sparrows<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-3---sparrows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Sparrows" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Sparrows">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.3-79af39d5c46ad17bff9d664d8e9b8d67.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.3.2-82f84aeae9f678838f02bf2f1117b925.jpg" width="3000" height="1104" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---raccoons">Day 4 - Raccoons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-4---raccoons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Raccoons" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Raccoons">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.4-ccf692dec234bb2897f2f59f5cc5fa6e.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.4.2-0f137ecfc082de5bc798e10b563e4122.jpg" width="3000" height="1100" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---bats">Day 5 - Bats<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#day-5---bats" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Bats" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Bats">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.5-43c2276e2bad41b11d9c50581328fe17.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-40.5.2-daa051dbeefcff34e75a0d87cc81d828.jpg" width="3000" height="1105" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-40#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>And that’s the end of the year of WAPs. I’m happy I did these last 2 weeks as revisits, it’s reassuring that some of the things I learned from those weeks seem to have stuck around. It’s been an interesting year and I’m pretty proud of sticking with it. Even ended up blogging every week’s efforts which I hadn’t planned on being able to do, it didn’t feel like something I could keep up with at the start of the year. Having spent the last 2 weeks re-reading those old posts I do regret not writing more during the exercises. It would have been nice to return to a list of key features to focus on for each creature.</p>
<p>I’m putting together a summary post about my WAP year and art efforts for the year in general, which I hope to put up before returning to work.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video games - 2024 review]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Games I played in 2024]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I tried to break games down into what I loved and what was okay. This year I’m going to try organizing things a little differently. I liked a lot of games this year. Made a dent in my backlog, played some of the top regarded games of the year, and a lot of them were hits with me. So this will probably read like a long list of game recommendations.</p>
<p>Unlike your typical 'Best Of' list, I’m starting with my top games of the year instead of saving them for the end. Why make the people wait. Or read.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/top-games-2024-c51f0d4204245645393439f24b0b22c5.jpg" width="2500" height="908" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><strong>Cobalt Core</strong> was a very early game in the year for me. It came out in November 2023 so I wasn’t too far from release when I picked it up. It’s a deck builder disguised as a ship builder roguelike. I was almost turned off of it once I realized how many playthroughs were needed to unlock the full ending but the gameplay kept bringing me back. And eventually I found a rather consistent ship build that got me wins 70% of the time. The art is rather cutesy but I thought it had great humour and writing.</p>
<p>Probably don’t need to say much about the <strong>Elden Ring DLC</strong> since I had put Elden Ring in my top games last year. But for me I think I got a more true Elden Ring experience in the DLC than I did in the main game. I had watched my wife play through Elden Ring before I really got hooked so there wasn’t much mystery for me and I kind of just focused on the main line and one build. In the DLC I explored (nearly) every nook and cranny, going for a near completionist run without really trying. Just felt fully In It. People still complain about the DLC’s use of Shadowseeds as necessary for progressing in the game power-wise but I find their complaints unjustified and thought it was actually a clever way to reward exploration and not rushing through. While also not taking away your powers since many people were coming into the DLC after beating the main game.</p>
<p><strong>Return of the Obra Dinn</strong> was one that has been on my to-play list since it came out. But I didn’t love the visual style so I hesitated. Wanting to play more games on my Switch this year because I could then play games in the bath, I finally got it. And then played it for nearly 6 hours straight. Excellent mystery design, such a unique progression, so much UI design making it playable. Instantly became a game I encourage everyone to play.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="puzzlers">Puzzlers<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#puzzlers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Puzzlers" title="Direct link to Puzzlers">​</a></h2>
<p>So I said I was going to try to break things down a little differently. Mostly because there have been so many good games this year but they’ve all been very different styles. Obra Dinn wasn’t my first puzzle game of the year, I started with <strong>Cocoon,</strong> one of the top games from 2023. I loved how straightforward Cocoon was, how it made you feel just clever enough. While also giving you very minimal storytelling, you mostly went on vibes. I also like to describe it as a game for people who want to ponder over some orbs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="The meme of a wizard gazing at an orb but the orb has been replaced by the Cocoon orb within an orb." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ponder-orb-09bd382092436d5e6c7866bb66cc6b28.jpg" width="1244" height="750" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><strong>Animal Well</strong> was a more search-action platform puzzler. Another really unique style, interesting game play, but the extensive puzzles going levels deep was too much for me. I still think the game is great and I recommend it for people and tell them it feels good even just reaching the first credits. But I would have loved to have the experience of playing it at the same time as friends and sharing discoveries and maybe trying to figure out some of the more obtuse secrets.</p>
<p>Another one from the backlog was <strong>Chants of Sennaar</strong>. I don’t feel like this game ever got much hype but it was talked about on a gaming podcast I listen to and I was rather taken with the art style when I looked it up. The central game mechanic is deciphering languages used by different castes in a society so that you can try to figure out what’s going on. It has a similar game feel as Obra Dinn, where you are dragging and dropping your answers to the puzzles into menu slots. Which honestly, is probably where they got the design idea from and where the next game, <strong>The Case of the Golden Idol</strong>, likely got inspiration from too.</p>
<p>Golden Idol is a series of scenes, each containing mysteries you piece together through a bit of point and click investigating. It was really fun, and deployed a hint system that was enough to help me with a puzzle whenever I got stuck. I really like that as a mechanic because even though every game has been walkthrough to death online, it’s really nice to not pick up your phone and look for help and just be able to stay in the game.</p>
<p>I would honestly recommend all these games, I felt like they were all unique and all offered something a little different.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gatchas">Gatchas<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#gatchas" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Gatchas" title="Direct link to Gatchas">​</a></h2>
<p>While <strong>Genshin Impact</strong> is still my main gatcha game (I still play nearly every day), I tested the waters of a few others this year.</p>
<p><strong>Zenless Zone Zero</strong> is the newest Mihoyo game, one I was pretty excited for after years of small teases. I ended up only playing for 2 days before deciding it wasn’t really for me. I liked the character design, I liked the combat, but the general execution of being more locked into quests after the open world freedom of Genshin felt very restrictive. But I also knew it would want as much time as Genshin does and it’s hard to balance multiple huge games like that at the same time.</p>
<p>For a little over a month my wife and I played <strong>AFK Journey</strong>. This was also a time sink but it was when I wanted to get off Twitter so I was trying to get into the habit of opening games on my phone instead of opening brain numbing apps. It was fun while it lasted but didn’t have the staying power of Genshin to keep us coming back.</p>
<p>There are two gatchas that are staying a little better. <strong>Pokemon TCG Pocket</strong>, a game that’s mostly focused on giving you that “pulls” feeling. As it does give you 2 pulls every day without you having to do anything besides login. If this wasn’t such a strong IP I don’t think this game would last but it takes minimal time commitment and I love looking at Pokemon.</p>
<p>The other is <strong>Infinity Nikki</strong> which I thought I’d play for a week and then bounce but I’m now on week 3 or so and have basically embraced it as my killing time while tired game while waiting for the next big Genshin content drop. Infinity Nikki is very unique in its focus on fashion and story over combat, and I do love playing dress-up. But I will be surprised if I stick with this game longer than winter break.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="not-good-enough-at">Not good enough at<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#not-good-enough-at" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Not good enough at" title="Direct link to Not good enough at">​</a></h2>
<p>I consider myself pretty good at video games. I have what I consider decent reflexes and hand eye coordination for my age, enjoy puzzle solving and also believe in having to put the time in to get good at something. So I find it rare that I bounce off a game because I’m just not getting it. But it happened twice this year.</p>
<p>One was for <strong>Pacific Drive</strong>, a game I was very excited about because I loved some of its early trailers. But after multiple failed journeys in my car, and having to re-do missions over and over again, I just lost motivation. I felt like I was missing a key understanding for being able to get through even early missions. I saw some other people online with a similar complaint, and they were mostly told to “get good”. Others suggested that there were a few difficulty settings that can be changed. So if I do ever return to this I’d probably turn those on and try to enjoy the mystery of the world more.</p>
<p><strong>Rollderdrome</strong> was the other game I put down. I’d heard lots of good things about it and was super intrigued by the game player and weird setting, but I didn’t love the game feel. And the fact that you just went match to match without much going on between challenges meant I didn’t have much to latch onto besides the game play.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rest">The rest<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/games-2024#the-rest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The rest" title="Direct link to The rest">​</a></h2>
<p>Okay I tried being organized but there are only a few left and they don’t really fit in a nice category.</p>
<p><strong>Dave the Diver</strong>, one of last year's huge breakouts. I had a lot of fun with this and was blown away by the pixel art. I put a lot of time into it even though it got rather repetitive and honestly killing fish over and over again didn’t feel great. But it had such addictive pacing.</p>
<p><strong>Night in the Woods</strong> was my only VN-esque game this year. A famously beloved indie darling that is very well executed and had a twist I didn’t see coming. It was also a nice length with good writing overall. Which is why it often came up in my game circles since I spend a lot of time talking about storytelling and writing in games. So I knew I had to get to this one eventually and I’m happy I finally did.</p>
<p>And I replayed <strong>Hades</strong>. I had a strong urge to start playing early access Hades 2 but when trying to balance how much time you play video games versus other things I didn’t want to put 30 hours into Hades 2 knowing I would likely put in those same 30 hours on the full release. So I will keep trying to avoid any spoilers for Hades 2 and just hope that it gets a full release soon.</p>
<p>This feels a bit like a ridiculous amount of games to play in a year, but most of them were nice, reasonably sized experiences. The puzzlers were in the 5-12 hours of gameplayer area. Dave the Diver and Elden Ring were probably the only games I put in over 30 hours. I’ve just really come to enjoy a video game that I can start playing on a Friday evening and wrap it up by Sunday evening. Just a nice weekend experience.</p>
<p>I do have a list of games I’d like to play in 2025 and I think most should also be in the smaller game category. Which does make me curious for what huge game will be able to grab me next, as there’s nothing on my radar for releases in 2025 that seems like a contender. Unless Hades 2 does a surprise drop...</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="games" term="games"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 39]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39"/>
        <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 39 - Revisits 1]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For these last 2 WAP weeks, I decided to change it up. For each of the days I would revisit one of the themes I had done in the previous 38 WAPs. I didn’t want this to be extra extra hard mode or anything, I just wanted to see how much of what I took out of those weeks stuck around. So I let myself re-read the original blog post and scroll through the Pintrest page of images before I settled in to do some drawing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---squirrels">Day 1 - Squirrels<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-1---squirrels" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Squirrels" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Squirrels">​</a></h2>
<p>Still love squirrels, happy to revisit them. They were my <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">very first WAP</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.1-c41b74dfca4d6130ea2f4ead0627e7bd.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Then compare the day 5 from squirrel week to this iteration 50 weeks later.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.1.2-013bfef92ddecb4898d9b9af4d1749fa.jpg" width="2500" height="908" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---pangolin">Day 2 - Pangolin<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-2---pangolin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Pangolin" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Pangolin">​</a></h2>
<p>Pangolins still very cute and still very tiresome to draw all the scales. Pangolins are from <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 2</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.2-631bcc9910ae7dd570dd17d2056fdf3b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---pigeons">Day 3 - Pigeons<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-3---pigeons" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Pigeons" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Pigeons">​</a></h2>
<p>Went a little more cartoony for pigeons. Did them back in <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 3</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.3-2a5e9dc30723260aee5de5383dbaf6d7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---rabbits">Day 4 - Rabbits<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-4---rabbits" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Rabbits" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Rabbits">​</a></h2>
<p>Hard to resist just drawing big circles of fur for rabbits still. Another early one from <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 7</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.4-537ec703c707d339d19ff0ae0b545c19.jpg" width="2500" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---hawks">Day 5 - Hawks<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#day-5---hawks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Hawks" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Hawks">​</a></h2>
<p>Still can’t drawk hawks in a way I love but these did come out pretty quickly and I don’t hate them. First pass at hawks was in <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">week 14</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-39.5-7318701c2a20f8052bf14b30db6b9176.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-39#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m happy with this being how I’m wrapping up the year long WAP project. It was fun to revisit the work I had done earlier in the year, and feels a little unreal to compare those weeks to the work done now. Interesting to see how my sketching style has changed and just feeling like my lines have gotten more confident.</p>
<p>I’ll be doing the same thing for next week, week 40, the final WAP. Besides that I’m putting together posts on my favourite books and video games of 2024 like I did last year. And then I’ll put together a big post as a bit of an art retrospective hopefully before the new year.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 38]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38"/>
        <updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 38 - Bikes]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the end of the year approached I thought it was time to tackle a theme I’d been avoiding. There are 3 subjects that are often either ridiculed or acknowledged as being weirdly difficult to draw. Hands, horses, bikes. These likely aren’t the hardest for everyone but they come up and have been on my mind since starting this year long project. At the start of the year I did hands, just a few weeks ago horses, so it felt like it was time to stop avoiding bikes.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Pretty awful. I see bikes probably every single day, Montreal is a very active bike city, but it’s not enough for me to summon up bikes clearly in my mind.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.1-e723a3f375d7ae3d8cbcc76064390a93.jpg" width="2870" height="938" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Day two saw improvements quickly just by being able to look at some photos. However, a quick discovery: not that many exciting photos of bikes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.2-2989f2dc938e435f2b3ab2a8fc5d6c7d.jpg" width="2841" height="1834" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>The realization from day 2 was quickly apparent on day 3, the photos aren’t exciting and drawing bikes… also not exciting. Is drawing bikes hard because imagining a bike isn’t fun? I really had to push myself to just start working on bikes each day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.3.1-eab7633d5b5ac07c8b921d80e1284ce0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.3.2-e1cc81b66cc950d120d65005211553e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Things got a little nicer on day 4 if only because the references I chose to work with were big on simplification. Not including all the tiny metal bits in the wheels is a huge time saver and takes away the annoying act of having to draw 40 lines.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.4-dd4658adcc26c15126dabb5a7fbb7324.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.vectorstock.com/royalty-free-vector/bicyclist-rider-mans-bike-hand-drawn-sketch-vector-6224107" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sketchy bikes on VectorStock</a> and <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/diana-huang/art/Draw-People-on-Bicycles-and-Tricycles-510867169" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Diana-Huang on DeviantArt</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I put off day 5 for as long as I could because even though I found drawing bikes to be fairly boring I was afraid that boredom had stopped any memory of the shape of a bike from my mind. I was certain I was going to draw some kind of bike abomination.</p>
<p>But I decided to take it super slow and draw with some perspective to mix things up. Only to draw the best bike I’ve ever seen. Plus another bike in profile which is okay but doesn’t feel like as much of an accomplishment.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-38.5-2d1d44c8fa35b818ba8bb8d29a6066ad.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-38#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Even though I’m proud of the bike I drew on day 5 I’m still a little torn about this week. Inanimate objects just aren’t as interesting to approach this way due to their lack of movement and change. Living creatures have multiple shapes, sizes, motions, bikes just kind of… are. I had the same problem with a few other object weeks. If I were to keep up this kind of practice I’d probably try to find a different approach for inanimate objects.</p>
<p>I have 2 weeks left of WAP, during which I’ll also be putting together my practice format for next year. It won’t kick off until February as my wife and I are going to participate in <a href="https://itch.io/jam/swakjam-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sealed With A Kiss</a>, a month-long game jam to make a visual novel. A second go at Renpy for me after this year's NaNoRenO.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-bicycle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of bicycles</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 37]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37"/>
        <updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 37 - Running]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Possibly last anatomy week of 2024??? This week is running, which I was pretty surprised I hadn’t done yet. Even just went and skimmed my tracking sheet to double check.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Some early day 1 space misjudgements here. Chopped off the top of a head.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.1-b2f77ed8049904a90d9e07581659b258.jpg" width="2747" height="2016" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A fair bit better over day 1 I would say. It’s just so easy to mess up proportions on bodies in motion. I was also happy to find so many different angled shots on runners. Even though it did up the difficulty.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.2-7ff46f8c2be28f3adf4204c65cce260d.jpg" width="2586" height="1741" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.1-34720ca2dc3a590bf4bb4388230764e9.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.2-1909a472a0466bd64dabc4ed2094acc0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.3.3-f984d05caa0b1edba1f1ae2e32fbe1be.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I kind of wish I had leaned even further into anime runs for my style studies, but probably best to keep it balanced with other types of references. Anime just has lots of kinetic energy in their running animations. It’s through a lot of exaggeration which is still something I’m finding difficult to do.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.1-76a01cc36d51c8e365d66fec3e433a0a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: By <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/bintangpose/art/Male-pose-running-pose-655513693" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bintangpose on DeviantArt</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.2-d77dd07fbdb234461e1f0951a6868ecc.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: From a Korean <a href="https://www.clipstudio.net/drawing/archives/156316?epik=dj0yJnU9R2RxSkhLQW14NkVycHd5MnNPYkU1RzFoYjdFdHFHdHMmcD0wJm49YTlnaFRLRUgtemtWYy1ieEFCSHhZdyZ0PUFBQUFBR2RWMEhZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clip Studio blog post.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.4.3-035164593ec4ff9eb595c8608f715380.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/6Qdrr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TB Choi on ArtStation
</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Don’t love this final day, lots of mismatched angles from lower bodies to upper bodies. Couldn’t figure out the foot on the front facing one. The bird's eye view one came out okay though. And in profile feels easy enough now, but any angle beyond that becomes risky.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-37.5-c0bd210d5fa2488eba26ce6ff4c7a671.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-37#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I don’t have my last 3 weeks selected yet but I’m tempted to take up the challenge of bicycles. Which is terrifying. That or cars. Transportation objects, terrible. But also tempted to Maybe return to my very first WAP month and revisit some of my first subjects. See if any of the learning from the start of the year stuck around.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-running/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of runners</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 36]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36"/>
        <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 36 - Bats]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe I waited this long to do bats as a WAP theme. They’re an original favourite animal from my childhood, to the point that a book about different types of bats is one of my strongest childhood memories. However, the kids book Stellaluna may be the reason for my love of them:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A brown bat clumsily hangs onto a tree branch. The title Stellaluna is above her in the night sky." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/stellaluna-630ba2cd17d97e415a98dedeef7bf4d1.jpg" width="500" height="498" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 1 not too bad but I was probably picturing how dragons fly instead of bats. There is definitely more variety to bat faces than I could remember and I think my mental model of a bat has been fairly corrupted by cartoon versions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.1-565c6c92599e451b00baadb38b749972.jpg" width="2926" height="1797" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A little more variety, a better angle on the wings. Really seeing how boney bat wings are.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.2-38d404b778b636c678d5161bec094a73.jpg" width="2904" height="2005" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.3.1-ebf742cc32be2cf980ab5cc88aaa4e16.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>While bats are more known for flying, drawing them crawling on the ground is much easier. Perspective gets weird when creatures are flying, wings bend or get foreshortened. It’s hard to convey movement, especially with bats since they’re moving so fast.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.3.2-94b7dfd3571c174b0900d8982991e7c7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>All cartoon bats are so cute, it was very difficult to choose reference pieces for today.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.1-143967413e6fee679406e75828f357e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CKgRLO5DwID/#" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram bats by sarah.b.artist</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.2-a73d4f6f16ad2201cf0113f0dbf67322.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/sharkie19/art/Vampire-Bats-503728080" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vampire bats by sharkie19</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.4.3-3cfaf35518c596568baaa7d532c95652.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.inprnt.com/gallery/artcher/bat-rogue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bat rogue by Artcher</a>. I love this art piece so much T_T Very much an art style that I’d love to build a comfort with but I struggle to pull out such levels of cuteness.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>This one feels a little fumbled, but probably because I was fighting the urge to draw cute bats and I really just should have let myself draw cute bats. Instead you get Smokey, Tokey, and Ralph, as named by my wife.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-36.5-7172137ec3872f3b47b9045e4fe081e3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-36#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>WAP 37 is already in the works and I’m tempted to push through to wrap up the year with WAP 40 but I also have a few other art projects I’d like to wrap up before the end of the year. I do have some time off coming up so I might be able to power through them with that extra time. If I don’t spend it making tofu pies.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-bat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of bats</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 35]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35"/>
        <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After my week of horse riders I thought it would be appropriate to tackle horses on their own. One of the fabled Hard to Draw things along with <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hands</a> and bicycles (which I have yet to try).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I thought day 1 was going pretty okay until I took a step back and got “dog” vibes from my first day of sketches. So I wasn’t exactly getting the legs right.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.1-2aab33e97bf0f4ef3f2f90f81ab1299e.jpg" width="3072" height="2151" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>The tiny head on the first left hand horse here makes me laugh. Horses really are about getting the proportions right while they themselves have pretty weird proportions. I don’t have a natural eye to judge the proper sizes of head and body versus long skinny legs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.2-77d7bac5548db7c65140b2b6443742fe.jpg" width="2861" height="2075" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>More time with references was very valuable. Breaking down the horse into 3 balls or 2 balls connected by a tube is a pretty good base. But their legs can look like different lengths depending on the pose so I still lack confidence in judging when they’re accurate.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.1-48854ce9adcf9c3d8a75731876bd0d6a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.2-d53e1a71a9af429d2f6644a6d5d1855e.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.3.3-1f5373342bd1895f681ebb9ec680479d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>There are some very good horse references out there. An animal that has been widely Disney’fied. I did enjoy giving them from over the top facial expressions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.4.1-2ae010af34de928141d09d1ceee6c652.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Cartoon horses by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B3ZrjZWlHdu/?epik=dj0yJnU9YS1uMF9vSno1UTUxSlYxRktsR1l4cGM1X3VMVkdZaW0mcD0wJm49VHlIMkVGTlE4X3ZSS0haSlZGcERxZyZ0PUFBQUFBR2MtY24w&amp;img_index=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@mitchleeuwe on Instagram</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.4.2-7f5493a4272473f4c4e6cf4b355b6a91.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Horse expressions by <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/EQ4rv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hedvig H-S</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I kind of wish I had leaned more into the cartoon versions for test day. The larger eyes and over the top manes add a lot of character to a horse. Keeping them on the more realistic side makes them kind of boring to me. I’ll admit, I don’t super love horses.</p>
<p>My wife wanted it recorded that she has named this horse Pumpkin Wonderful. Place your bets now.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-35.5-ff66c39a67c6c75f48e6ed7285923262.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-35#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Overall, horses, not so bad. They definitely have a unique body type which makes them a bit more of a challenge but I don’t feel afraid or annoyed to draw them again. Hands still feel more difficult by comparison. And now I’m considering doing bicycles before the end of the year. Try to get through the big 3.</p>
<p>Just a few weeks left in the year and I have my final subjects selected. Considering going through all my blog posts and finding my unfinished pieces as there was a lot I started this year but didn’t finish. I don’t have a great track record for returning to unfinished projects but who knows, maybe I’ve changed.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-horses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of horses.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 34]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34"/>
        <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s practice was a style/master study of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Sugimori" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ken Sugimori</a>, the original Pokemon artist, known for drawing all original 151 Pokemon.</p>
<p>I didn’t want to draw just Pokemon, instead leaning on my learnings from anatomy practice and my goal of a self-portrait, I wanted to make myself into a Pokemon trainer. I did a fair bit of YouTube research for this one and I’ll share the resources that were most helpful or insightful throughout the blog post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1---pose">Step 1 - Pose<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-1---pose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1 - Pose" title="Direct link to Step 1 - Pose">​</a></h2>
<p>Following the workflow learn from character design week, step one was to focus on the pose only. Starting from Pinterest I gathered up a bunch of references of original Pokemon trainer artwork as well as a few modern interpretations.</p>
<p>I tried out a few poses, 2 from game references and one that just felt like it really fit the aggressive trainer look.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.1-e614a9fbedc60a5b27955a82b896ebd6.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I didn’t deviate too much from the original poses, wanting this week to be more about design and technique than anatomy or dynamic posing. For proportions, faces, and general shape design, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sratMdLyzvw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rjamez Valdez 4 piece trainer tutorial</a> is absolutely excellent. This is someone who has spent a lot of time studying the originals and also drawing trainers. He breaks down each feature to make it seem easy.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2---design">Step 2 - Design<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-2---design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2 - Design" title="Direct link to Step 2 - Design">​</a></h2>
<p>Design is one of my weaknesses but I feel like by doing 3 mandatory base sketches I’m finally starting to find ways to work around my weaknesses. I definitely used to just do 1 sketch and run with it, but now, for a lot of my work, I try to force at least 3 iterations to either get out of my comfort zone or increase the appeal of the original sketch.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="3 copies of the pose sketch, each with a different hair and clothing style." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.2-9a1b37483e3570722d5c610c0713c195.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-3---lines--colours">Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-3---lines--colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours" title="Direct link to Step 3 - Lines &amp; Colours">​</a></h2>
<p>So I messed up the process already. I should have forced myself to stay in step one longer because I really wasn’t happy with the hands. But the problem was that I had done them to match the reference image but then when looking at them again and trying out the hand pose in real life, it just didn’t make sense. So I ended up doing half the lines and then having to pause to re-work both hands over and over again. Even had my wife take a photo of my hand in the pose I wanted so I could use it as a visual reference.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.3-61cca4e6cb3b09b9061bee50a110b232.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Once I finally had the lines done I generated a colour palette from an image of mainline Pokemon trainers of the last 15-ish years. The palette of Pokemon art is rather specific so I didn’t want to choose colours on my own. They’re a combo of being rather muted with a few instances of strong saturation. I struggle with that balance so I tried to stay on the muted end of things. Which led to more beige than I really wanted…</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-4---rendering">Step 4 - Rendering<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-4---rendering" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 4 - Rendering" title="Direct link to Step 4 - Rendering">​</a></h2>
<p>Pokemon art has a very soft watercolour look to it. Where the original game work might have been done completely traditionally with water colours. Which makes for a challenge to duplicate digitally. But many have tried and I’ll share their experiences in the conclusion. I didn’t have to do too much experimenting as I was able to take other people’s brush recommendations and run with it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.4-3e4a37f1c447edc17617d6f056624181.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The shading is rather hard in Pokemon art, with some harsh lines. While the light is rather… light. I think what a lot of people learned was that you should be resisting the smudge tool and trying to keep those hard lines. I however, did not resist the smudge tool and ended up smudging most of my shadows as I didn’t like how hard they looked. I even did multiple shadow passes to add some harder lines back in after. I think this has led to way too much texture in the image which the original style doesn’t really have.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-5---adding-a-team">Step 5 - Adding a team<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#step-5---adding-a-team" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 5 - Adding a team" title="Direct link to Step 5 - Adding a team">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a lot of cute original trainer art pieces out on the internet. I copied their format of including your Pokemon team next to the trainer art. I didn’t want to spend a lot of time on the Pokemon so I just did quick sketch + lines and colour picked from the sprites to fill them in, then a touch of minimal shading.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-34.5-a83bcf6cf7722c4c7d40bd8c4fda0620.jpg" width="1964" height="2766" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-34#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>The most in-depth and helpful video on learning this style was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPyS9u3e5yg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mastering The Pokemon Art style! - Master Study</a> by IMTHEJOHKE. He does an intense 3 day style study in a format that I’d like to try out in the future. He talks about his experimentation to get the right look and also about his research. And it was funny to see him reference another style study video which happened to be the one I had watched just before, Subjectively’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BYrUE17SgdA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How to Draw in the Pokemon Style</a>.</p>
<p>Subjectively’s video was more focused on the Pokemon of Pokemon games but he shared the brushes he used in Procreate. Since the line and colouring style of Pokemon art is so unique this was a game changer for everyone in the comments.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="And image showing two Procreate brushes. The first being Gesinski Ink and the next Procreate&amp;#39;s Flat Brush. " src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/pokemon-brushes-c6648e521a73dc467ae5ee1fa9e0530e.jpg" width="2732" height="1522" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This is a screenshot from IMTHEJOHKE's video.</p>
<p>So while IMTHEJOHKE and Subjectively were really able to break down some of the larger pieces of the Pokemon style and how to replicate it digitally, I found Rjamez Valdez’s video series to be key to really making trainers. He seems to publish 1 video a year and has promised another one so I guess I’ll be waiting for that one to drop some day.</p>
<p>I haven’t done a style study like this before and it was really fun to go from idea to research to execution. It wouldn’t have been so easy if there wasn’t already people who had done the hard work and condensed their discovery into YouTube videos, so a challenge to myself will be to do a style study on my own instead of just second hand. But those are projects I hope to take into next year!</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/pok%C3%A9mon-trainers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of Pokemon trainers</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 33]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33"/>
        <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 33 - Swimming]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Action anatomy week, swimming. Some nice perspective shots but fewer variety to those shots than I expected.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>It quickly became obvious that foreshortening and proportion length would be the main difficulty with these.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.1-a580b15659a3e6cd1f720e52db4eff6d.jpg" width="2719" height="1947" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.2-374ceaf55ba9c0746449be8c5f032a14.jpg" width="2831" height="2126" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.3.1-ff30bd11b134f8ff1b624be4a2836980.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.3.2-0f137dcb30b12849b9008a93a50a3f45.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Reference options were pretty slim, I wasn't excited about these but once I started I appreciated the simplicity of the art. Made it easier to think about flowing lines which felt like an important feature to keep the movement looking fluid.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.4.1-efcd7d6e7a631d222c598e8cada6d2e5.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
Reference: <a href="https://www.etsy.com/ca/listing/154091122/swimming-illustration-gift-for-swimmer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vintage swimming instructional illustration</a> and <a href="https://www.etsy.com/ca/listing/1269769939/wild-swimming-print-sea-swimming-print" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Print by Penelope and the Ducks</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.4.2-61f7ce92693186c3515b1a5c76d9bdcd.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
Reference: <a href="https://www.casterman.com/Bande-dessinee/Catalogue/le-gout-du-chlore/9782203012165" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A page from the comic Le Goût du Chlore by Bastien Vivès</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-33.5-0611d1d04989a1991969016c9f1a79a8.jpg" width="3000" height="1514" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-33#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Rushed the last few days into the week as I got hit pretty hard by a vaccine reaction. And this coming week is busy with going into the office so I may not have a WAP for next week.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-swimming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of swimmers</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 32]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32"/>
        <updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 32 - Pokemon Ability Forms]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week is another shift in the weekly format. So along with the regular subject studies, and anatomy studies, I want to try to work in a “finished piece” once a month (even if there are only 2 left…). For me a finished piece mostly just means fully rendered to a degree where I’m happy to share it on socials. These will mostly be chosen from current internet art trends or challenges as I like to know my theme going into the week.</p>
<p>The theme for this week is the Pokemon Ability Forms exercise. All Pokemon have an ability, this is usually between two abilities with some Pokemon getting a 3rd hidden ability. Abilities will provide Pokemon with an extra, often passive, mechanic during combat. For example: Pikachu most often has the ability Static, which means that when an opposing Pokemon makes physical contact with that Pikachu, there is a 1 in 3 chance the opposing Pokemon is paralyzed by the static.</p>
<p>The idea behind this challenge is what if a Pokemon’s ability changed the way the Pokemon physically appeared. So a Pikachu with the ability Static might have static electricity jumping all over its fur. I heard of the exercise from a recent <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XAskhVaGu4Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Drawfee episode</a> and did some research to try to find the originator of the exercise and I’ve come to believe it was started by <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/n0rtist" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">n0rtist</a> with this <a href="https://n0rtist.tumblr.com/post/752603925067268096/what-if-abilities-changed-the-appearance-of-a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tumblr post</a> (Sounds like it may have been a Tweet first but Twitter is impossible to use now).</p>
<p>I like it as a challenge because it’s a design challenge with an existing character. So not a full head to toe design but working off of basically one word and a one sentence description to make changes with.</p>
<p>But anyway this is a lot of preamble for a blog post, let’s get into it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---research--sketches">Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-1---research--sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches">​</a></h2>
<p>I spent a decent amount of time scrolling a list of all Pokemon and reading their abilities. I wanted one that had 2 basic ones and a hidden ability to have 3 characters to draw. I went with Omastar because I have a soft spot for him after his role in the original Twitch Plays Pokemon and I wanted to keep drawing ocean creatures. He also has 3 abilities that I was able to imagine some solid visual elements right from the get go.</p>
<p>After doing the research phase I did some quick first idea sketches:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.1-76eb6cbec447e0732ad618db52b96490.jpg" width="4074" height="1275" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---digital-sketches">Day 2 - Digital sketches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-2---digital-sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Digital sketches" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Digital sketches">​</a></h2>
<p>Instead of bringing my hand sketches into a digital format I re-did them in CSP to spend a little more time thinking about poses and design.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Sketches in red digital pencil of 3 omastars" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.2-7480f891e495fac899390b34747c90a7.jpg" width="2800" height="2967" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---swift-swim">Day 3 - Swift Swim<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-3---swift-swim" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Swift Swim" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Swift Swim">​</a></h2>
<p>For Swift Swim I wanted longer tentacles for swimming but also a slightly more aerodynamic shell for faster movement in water.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.3-293848094ed93b91b45eca88902493f7.jpg" width="2323" height="2261" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---shell-armor">Day 4 - Shell Armor<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-4---shell-armor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Shell Armor" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Shell Armor">​</a></h2>
<p>I was torn between how big to go with Shell Armor, some of my earlier sketches definitely had more of the body covered but it ended up looking to diaper-like to me. I’m pretty happy with the helmet look though.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.4-c08e36ef61b0869ba6fcb1a3b08a5edb.jpg" width="2190" height="2109" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---weak-armor">Day 5 - Weak Armor<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-5---weak-armor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Weak Armor" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Weak Armor">​</a></h2>
<p>Weak Armor was probably the hardest design wise. How I conceptualised it was that on hit, the weak armor would break off and this makes the Pokemon faster as it’s carrying around less weight. Possibly even has some cool regenerate ability but I wasn’t sure how to visually represent that. So I just went with some big pieces being knocked off but still ready to fight.</p>
<p>This one is pink because that's the Omastar shiny variant.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.5-533d3c584e318faa698d57a22661ea44.jpg" width="2500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Once completed I put them all on a page with some experimental design so it wasn’t just a plain white background.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/omastar-abilityforms-827336f5598fe4f38f90c7a086d0bd78.jpg" width="2800" height="3508" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I really enjoyed this project. I don’t do design stuff often so it was a nice creative stretch. Dividing it into 1 character per day was also a nice breakdown as they each only took 1-2 hours depending on how confident I was in the sketch and after I figured out the painting method I wanted to use. It’s probably not noticeable but I did a light, textured white paint over the base colours to tone down the colours a bit. Original Pokemon artwork was in water colours so a lot of Pokemon art tries to emulate that and I liked the slightly softer look it gave this.</p>
<p>I used a web app to get the Omastar name in that font: <a href="https://pokemon-fonts-generator.netlify.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon Fonts Generator</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 31]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31"/>
        <updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 31 - Flowers]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s practice is another vague and ambitious theme; flowers. Vague because there are so many different kinds of flowers and ambitious because I often feel like I only know 5 flowers. But I see flowers constantly as they are probably the most common tattoo theme and I follow a lot of tattoo artists on Instagram. But I myself rarely draw them. So I thought it would be good to practice since they are such a common theme in art.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Not a terrible day one?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.1-9f671f0c4c3e423ac6203ea96f89efe5.jpg" width="2753" height="1833" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>When researching flowers it was a bit of a case of “I want to draw that one and that one and that one etc.”. There are a lot of interesting shapes out there so it was hard to choose to focus on a select few to get good at those or to keep trying new ones to try to internalise more ways flowers can look.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.2-f85777a65571d3e419f88f6ba4c6cd90.jpg" width="2899" height="2009" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Easily could have spent hours doing reference studies as I found these to be pretty relaxing. Sunflowers came up a lot in my search results so that and roses are probably the real theme of this week.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.1-e3d4d3be0e7ec3ef9c02ea29a4c70dd1.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.2-f8027bfc35a7d7d41b33c7f4987b61e7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.3-8bfc09795c59e313c68bd4a33b83807b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Is there a more drawn subject than flowers? (okay probably human bodies due to everyone’s efforts to do figure drawing practice). I probably could have scrolled Pinterest for hours for reference images but I knew it was a trap and grabbed the first few slightly different looking ones I found.</p>
<p>I worked on a few of these on the train and I felt the rocky, unsteadiness of the train added a nice jitter to my line work that made the petals look more organic.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.1-95b1219653ef2ab7da8ef94f24ce27c0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Pantone flowers by ??? I’m absolutely shocked that Google research image search had nothing for these. I even chose it because I felt certain I had seen these images on Twitter in the past. But the only thing I could find was links to Russian websites selling the art on merch?? <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/598978819227861200/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest pin</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.2-bf825b77eed479ec331f36045eb032c2.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Sunflowers by <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/libbyframe/711818392918687744/coming-soon-the-bloom-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Libby Frame</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.3-d5619fd9a81cd9100999e9de225a4506.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Hydrangeas by what seems to be an art resources from <a href="https://jeforel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jeforel</a>?? and <a href="https://www.howjoyful.com/flower-drawing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HowJoyful</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I chose the 3 flowers first for day 5 and then went from there. Mixing a bit of the stylistic flowers with general memory.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.5-86073de16a22c9477a3bed9a1b7c7966.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>After 2 weeks of flowers I do kind of wish I had chosen one flower type to focus on. Hydrangeas were lots of fun but drawing so many little flowers was definitely time consuming.</p>
<p>Been thinking a lot about how I want my art practice to change in 2025 which has led to thinking a lot about master studies. I’ve been watching videos of other people doing master studies and they always look like, like trying to solve a mystery or a puzzle. But they do also look rather intense so I’m not sure what’s a realistic goal for doing studies. 1 a week? 1 a month?</p>
<p>But I’d also like to start working on pieces I’m comfortable sharing as even though I’ve been drawing consistently all year, none of my weekly practice pieces are finished pieces. And while studies are important they aren’t really, fully “yours”. So I also want to find a way to work on new personal art more. Still have a few months to figure it all out.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-flowers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of flowers</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 30]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30"/>
        <updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 30 - Sugar Gliders]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week 30! It feels like a small number when compared to all numbers, but it’s pretty good when compared to 52. And there are still a few more weeks to go in the year. I’m starting to try to figure out how I want to approach art practice next year now. I don’t think I want to keep doing WAP guided practice, I feel like I should get out of the comfort zone and try to move into working on complete pieces. Or another idea is to do more Master Studies.</p>
<p>Having weekly homework has been great for having something to work on every day but it’s also been a fair bit of pressure to get through the practice every week and get a blog post out for each one. But we’ll see, I have no idea what 2025 is going to look like yet so don’t want to make any big commitments.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>So I actually had two pet sugar gliders from about the age of 14 to 21, so you’d think I’d have a pretty decent mental model of what they look like. But it has been more than 12 years since I’ve been around one…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.1-d1fc2006774c0bad800785588d0d17f9.jpg" width="2984" height="2204" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.2-6932829446b08d89f34e68a2825b9f90.jpg" width="2914" height="2115" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.1-1a55175c4bd1afdccd149483cc546cea.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.2-44e157eaaaceba2cd924d44558abfbfa.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.3-dca8c38f7c284cf7a56aa5b0a0551646.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I was fairly surprised to find that there aren’t too many stylized takes on sugar gliders. Possibly because they aren’t a North American creature. We had endless sources for creatures like raccoons, rabbits, pigeons, etc. But also Pinterest is a pretty garbage website as when I go to collect my references at the end of the week there are suddenly more results and I struggle to find the ones I used. Are there results that I only see on iPad, that are different than one desktop?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.4.1-f876595163a2af1e241d1c1cb7c782ea.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.ac-illust.com/main/detail.php?id=23007284" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">From illustAC stock images.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.4.2-1c50fda8ccb88015da6374b78a3fcf0b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.shutterstock.com/id/g/catalyststuff" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Catalyst Labs on Shutterstock.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Took a bit to find my groove on day 5. But I felt pretty confident that if I gave myself enough time I could refine the sketches into solid versions of sugar gliders.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.5-8ad199eb1c8ca618eadc228adb51096f.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Have a fair bit going on for the next two weeks so I’m not sure if I’ll have enough time to get through two whole WAP practices. I’ve started an ambitious possible Altar Stone animation but so far it involves drawing 100 trees and I don’t know if I’m going to still like it by the time I reach tree 100.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-sugargliders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of sugar gliders.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 29]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29"/>
        <updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 29 - Horseback riding]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anatomy week with an extra complication, horses. My goal for the week wasn’t to learn to draw horses, a famously difficult creature to master. But more to focus on the shape human bodies take while riding.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.1-bcc8326bdacce7e1cfcb315c8acddfbf.jpg" width="3031" height="2111" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I wanted to spend at least some time studying side saddle riding, even though I don’t think it’s going to come up as often as… non side saddle? Middle saddle?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.2-9d580ff572ab08ff179ba39bfb7be27f.jpg" width="3441" height="2391" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Did a first pass traced in red to try to understand the shapes going on. Bodies are often very hunched so it’s hard to place limbs properly. And because the legs are curved outwards they also lose some length, making for some not perfect looking proportions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.1-80ea63a249eff3027637da28217baa95.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.2-7a5ea62f08bd118309bb8266aca879ff.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.3-f9a36efa5c10b20dc1672c26a609c50b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>These aren’t super stylized but I wanted to do some artistic references to see if they felt any different. The main thing is that the horse feels like the wild card in artistic interpretations. Some people make the horse extra big to look more powerful while others keep them smaller to make them look more friendly.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.1-100556f614c9aa75f8a46e5b8eb97a2a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: I found this from <a href="https://skyryedesign.com/art/horse-drawing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sky Rye Design blog post on horse drawing.</a>. But they took this piece from <a href="https://toodrawtothink.tumblr.com/post/122776324553/horses-thanks-so-much-to-dan-and-cassie-sprenger" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a TooDrawToThink Tumblr post.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.2-7f3a8d220d9c7222e2c0e463ed499893.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Absolutely can't find a source on this one which is ridiculous. The reverse image search brings up links to music albums which makes no sense. <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/859132066431247458/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This is it's only pin.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.3-789e27f63207f9446e6b7ba76a6cd14d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Can’t find a proper source for this one either, <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/4362930875864189/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">just the Pinterest pin.</a>. But there's also a Reddit thread referencing it, but also with no original source that I could spot. Begging artist to tag/sign their stuff so I can find you T_T</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>There was definitely more variety to poses than I was expecting, which made going into day 5 feel intimidating. I ended up just trying to focus on simple poses as I felt like the hunched riding pose was decently difficult on it’s own.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.5-74e2d51a72dc016c239ac239e4639602.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I would like to do a horse focused week before the end of the year, feels appropriate to tackle the traditional hard subjects.</p>
<p>This coming week is hopefully a return to a nice simple creature week. I’ve found it hard to get into creative projects the last two weeks. When I don’t have a main project on the go, like an Altar Stone background, I often open Procreate, look at not finished pieces, and then just close it. Tried starting a few new things in the last 2 weeks but none of them felt great. Just kind of lost my creative steam.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-horseback/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of horseback riding.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Altar Stone - Item Set 1]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1"/>
        <updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 3 first items published with Altar Stone videos]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The most recent addition we’ve made to our Altar Stone videos is adding a homebrewed, on theme, item to the end of the video. This has been a fun creative challenge and our first attempt at bundling more “worth” into the video projects. These are the first 3 we've shared.</p>
<p>We are basing the items off of 5e (2014) for now. Might be fun to revisit the mechanics if we personally branch out to other systems in this golden age of new TTRPG releases.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="abyssal-harp">Abyssal Harp<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#abyssal-harp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Abyssal Harp" title="Direct link to Abyssal Harp">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-harp-c418140d157b961a258fa6a86fe2afa5.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, instrument, very rare (requires attunement by a bard),</em>
<em>5lbs</em></p>
<p>An instrument of the submerged Eighth College, this harp takes the form of a series of interconnected tubes mounted on a frame of coral. When moved through water in a precise and fluid motion, the harp creates sound vibrations and subtle changes in water pressure that are perceived as ethereal music by the listener.</p>
<p>While you are fully immersed in water and holding this harp, the current adds its voice to yours when you cast spells. You gain a +1 bonus to the saving throw DC of your bard spells and a +1 bonus to Constitution saving throws made to maintain concentration on a spell.</p>
<p>While you are holding this harp, you can cast <em>prestidigitation</em> as an action. Illusions created with this spell take on a watery character: visual illusions shimmer and waver, while auditory illusions are deep and sonorous. Once per day, as an action, you can use the harp to cast <em>create or destroy water</em> as a 5th level spell. This property recharges at dawn, whether or not the sun is visible at your current depth.</p>
<p>The harp can only be played underwater. The vibrations and pressure changes it generates are imperceptible in air or empty space. When affixed to an underwater surface in an area with strong currents, the harp will seemingly play itself as water flows through it, allowing the ocean to speak with a gentler voice and for the patient listener to hear the musings of its queen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rod-of-reanimation">Rod of Reanimation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#rod-of-reanimation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rod of Reanimation" title="Direct link to Rod of Reanimation">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-rod-90d6b4070aa010859e76c40523245f8a.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, rod, very rare (requires attunement by a wizard, warlock, or sorcerer),</em>
<em>10lbs</em></p>
<p>This rod of crystal and steel is topped with a transparent sphere, inside which arc and sputter streams of blue and purple lightning. Adventurers are advised not to spend undue time considering the origin of the fluid that circulates within the handle.</p>
<p>The rod has 3 charges. While you hold it, you can use an action and consume a charge to cast one of the following spells from it: <em>animate dead</em> or <em>lightning bolt</em>. As charges are consumed, the fluid within the handle depletes proportionately. The charges (and the fluid) return at dawn.</p>
<p>Creatures reanimated by the Rod have the property <em>Came Back Wrong</em>. At the beginning of the creature’s turn, roll a ten-sided die.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Roll</th><th style="text-align:left">Condition</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">1</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature cannot act this turn. If the creature was capable of speech in life, it begs for death from the nearest creature. Otherwise, it howls in wordless agony.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">2-3</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature goes into a wild rage, screaming and attacking the nearest creature with all its strength. It makes a melee attack roll with an additional +2 to hit and a 1d6 bonus to damage.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">4-10</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature behaves normally this turn.</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="glass-of-sands">Glass of Sands<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#glass-of-sands" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Glass of Sands" title="Direct link to Glass of Sands">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-hourglass-3da755a556fececffe6c232611ac19d4.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, legendary,</em>
<em>5lbs</em></p>
<p>Within the hourglass, discovered in the outstretched hand of a withered corpse, the sands swirl without cease as if scattered by eternal sirocco. When you pick it up, you feel as though you can hear the wind inside, the susurrus of a thousand thousand imprisoned in dust.</p>
<p>Once a week, as an action, you may cast any one spell of 8th level or less on your class’s spell list by turning the glass upside down and reciting the incantation inscribed along its edges. While the sand is flowing, time is paused for the user as the hourglass draws power from within the core of their soul to assemble the energies necessary for the spell. Consult the table below to determine how much your character ages as a result of using this feature.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Spell level</th><th style="text-align:left">Duration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">1</td><td style="text-align:left">1 month</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">2</td><td style="text-align:left">2 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">3</td><td style="text-align:left">3 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">4</td><td style="text-align:left">5 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">5</td><td style="text-align:left">8 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">6</td><td style="text-align:left">1 year</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">7</td><td style="text-align:left">2 years</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">8</td><td style="text-align:left">3 years</td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>While time is paused, the hourglass’s holder cannot act, and only the sand within the hourglass moves. The rest of the world is held in suspension. The subjective duration of the time freeze for both the user and those in the vicinity is left to the GM.</p>
<p>If the hourglass is shattered, the soul-dust within is freed, and each fleck will spend the remainder of its existence attempting to locate and re-incorporate with the soul that shed it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Next week is back to regular WAP posting. I may have chosen an anatomy challenge that’s too complicated but we’ll see if it can be done without learning the anatomy of horses…</p>
<p>I ended up downloading Resprite on the iPad so I’ve been poking around at pixel art a bit. Hoping to try out animating in a few weeks when I look up a tutorial on how to properly use the app. But also a bunch of my Clippy points were going to expire so I went on a big Clip Studio Paint spending spree and now have a bunch of new brushes I want to experiment with. And Swordtember is still going on!!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="dnd" term="dnd"/>
        <category label="homebrew" term="homebrew"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 28]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28"/>
        <updated>2024-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 28 - Raccoons]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week's raccoon theme gets me close to wrapping up “city creatures”. Though I guess I’ve skipped rats and mice but that’s more because my wife is afraid of them and also I don’t want to think about mice when I don’t have too.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 1, a little messy as always. The big thing being I couldn’t remember what raccoon face patterns look like. And there body shape came out much too similar to cats.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.1-17ea79033a15d9cd6ba67642ff976fa0.jpg" width="3072" height="2102" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 2 gave us the raccoon who wants a hug, who took off on BluSky a bit. Setting the bar high for the rest of the week. How could a raccoon be cuter?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.2-125f301429828f6bb903c362d4f736e0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Ended up spending 2 days on reference studies. Probably too long but I was enjoying the process. I’m a big fan of the chunky raccoon shape. Just drawing a bunch of fur and curves.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.3-ff39d36af80f4f20b58669bc668fda82.jpg" width="3000" height="2074" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I know I could find endless raccoon cartoon references if I kept digging but I had a very busy week so just grabbed the top Pinterest results.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.1-a74677cfbbc48a5dfe158e89ca11a4f1.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://spicymochi.tumblr.com/post/720210870068789248/he-is-sitting-politely" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Art by SpicyMochi / Renee</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.2-fecc47208807f79836ce3409bc4a1aaa.jpg" width="2757" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://society6.com/eloisenarrigan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon print by Eloise Narrigan</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.3-bafc822bf73cc1c4e1325f07d4abe8b3.jpg" width="2372" height="1859" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://gamepackstudio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon Twitch emojis. It says these are from Game Pack Studio, but the website doesn’t share this anywhere.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I was afraid to do justice to cute raccoons on day 5. Still images of raccoons don’t really show the silliness and mischievousness. I wanted to try to capture that in chip raccoon. Sleeping raccoon was from a photo I remembered seeing and then the sitting guy was just me trying to get the shape right from memory.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.5-4cb47a1d5fa5ae569833bfd7ffe9c180.jpg" width="3000" height="1321" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="software-contemplations">Software contemplations<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#software-contemplations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Software contemplations" title="Direct link to Software contemplations">​</a></h2>
<p>There’s been a lot of new iPad apps dropping over the last year that I’m currently tempted by. I feel like 3 years ago when I was looking for 3D modelling things there were zero options. Then a few weeks ago I learned of <a href="https://nomadsculpt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nomad Sculpt</a> which people compare favourably to Blender (which is desktop only). And then very recently <a href="https://www.maxon.net/en/zbrush-for-ipad" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZBrush</a> also released an iPad version of their software. I’m not familiar enough with the existing software to draw my own conclusions and everything is still pretty recent so I haven’t found great comparison articles or videos yet.</p>
<p>But I’d like to mess around with 3D models next year so I’ll keep trying to find a good option. Blender is free but being desktop only is a downside for me as my laptop is starting to show its age so the iPad is the more reliable hardware choice.</p>
<p>I’ve also been eyeing <a href="https://www.aseprite.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aseprite</a> for pixel art, but again, it doesn’t have an iPad version. People recommend <a href="https://resprite.fengeon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Resprite</a> for iPad, but the main thing people say Aseprite does better is video game assets and video game assets are my long term goals. So it feels like the wrong choice to go for the inferior choice when I know what I’m trying to do. There’s also just a very noticeable lack of Resprite tutorials out there, but there is a wealth of Aseprite tutorials.</p>
<p>Just feeling stuck in choices right now and wishing there were more people writing and comparing these softwares. But all I can really get info from is Reddit posts :|</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Running a bit behind on art due to having a very busy week last week. Gonna focus on some other art projects and blog posts and resume WAP exercises next week.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-raccoon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of raccoons.</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 27]]></title>
        <id>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27</id>
        <link href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Week 27 - Material studies]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week's study theme was inspired from the <a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc">One Week Character challenge</a> I did a few months ago. The instructure spent a decent amount of time talking about material painting and using it to livin up your character's look. I struggled with the focus on metal as I didn’t feel like I had enough time in the 1 day devoted to materials to really learn, and instead just ended up trying to fake it. But after that I added Material Studies to my list of upcoming WAPs, and now we finally got there.</p>
<p>I started by gathering up material step-by-step guides I could find on Pinterest. The most common ones are gold and metal, but the metadata on these things isn’t great so it was hard to keep searching for more, broader themes. Out of the ones I found I choose 5 that feel like decent beginner materials, by which I probably mean most common. I also choose ones that had the most understandable guides, preferring ones that also had text that explained the steps.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---wood">Day 1 - Wood<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-1---wood" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Wood" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Wood">​</a></h2>
<p>I find wood rather intimidating to paint, I suspect others do too as it’s very easy to find a brush to do the effect. It’s my go-to move for Altar Stone videos or other backgrounds where I need to do a large piece of wood because the idea of drawing all the needed lines is exhausting. But that’s what we did on day 1.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.1-ef890115c8b406a0996efa002eddcff8.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m very happy with how this went, even though I did get lost in the steps for a while. The instructions could be more clear. I didn’t add as many scratches but that was mostly because I felt like the ones I did do were enough to learn what was going on. This piece also came together rather quickly which was a nice discovery, making the idea of doing hand drawn wood objects in the future less daunting.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/gimaldinov/art/How-to-draw-wooden-plank-267517599" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wood tutorial</a> by
Gimaldinov. I found this version of the tutorial while putting the blog post together and now I see that there were more steps! I didn’t know about the last few!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---gold">Day 2 - Gold<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-2---gold" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Gold" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Gold">​</a></h2>
<p>Gold felt pretty straight forward and was the fastest of the bunch. I do feel like I’ve lost some texture and I could have pushed the highlights harder.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A step by step guide on how to paint gold next to a large golden chalice." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.2-6af054c375be199f7d294a4aee3cc9bc.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Gold tutorial by <a href="https://www.colinadams.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Colin Adams</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---metal">Day 3 - Metal<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-3---metal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Metal" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Metal">​</a></h2>
<p>I hesitated on doing metal and gold on back to back days, thinking they would feel too similar. But I tried to focus on fixing the texture problem which led to some impressive results. At least after my first attempt which turned into a smudged mess.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.3-3dc172fe8f1d17e681368a9a64ffc349.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>A big struggle with the instructions for these things is that it’s not clear how you’re meant to be painting. Not everyone suggests a brush type so I would do trial and error with different kinds of brushes to try to get a similar look. Then I would try to soften the edges between colours but if you smug too much it’s easy to lose texture and lighting.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/mateslaurentiu/art/Armor-tutorial-220805678" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metal tutorial</a> by <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/mateslaurentiu/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MatesLaurentiu</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---scales">Day 4 - Scales<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-4---scales" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Scales" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Scales">​</a></h2>
<p>I was pretty excited for scales, thinking I would learn a technique to make 100 diamonds look good all at once. Turns out, no, you must draw every diamond.</p>
<p>At least if you want to do a shiny, impressive close up.</p>
<p>This study took the longest of the 5. The base approach of wavy lines on a column is very good for getting the shape down, but after that it’s very much <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/how-to-draw-an-owl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“draw the rest of the owl”</a> feeling.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.4-d7e00538588f280a9945db0c81fe7a93.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I lined every scale, painting in the base colour, did one round of highlights, a second round of highlights, 2 rounds of shadows, then added more detail base colours somewhere in between. Went back and fixed the shadows because they needed to be blended. Went back and fixed the highlights because they needed to be blended. All those steps repeated for each scale.</p>
<p>When I write it out it sounds terrible, but it can become relaxing. Once you know what you’re trying to accomplish with the specific step you’re on, it’s easier to turn your brain off and just do it for a while. So I could see a huge scaled creature project being pretty fun. But I don’t think it’s something I’ll do often.</p>
<p>Scales tutorial by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Anastasiaberry" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anastasia Deg aka AnastasiaBerry</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---fur">Day 5 - Fur<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-5---fur" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Fur" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Fur">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t love this fur tutorial at first glance but all the steps felt clear so I went with it. It wasn’t until I started to read the instructions and follow along that I noticed that the shading part of the approach focused on hue shifting which is a technique I want to get better at (hue shifting is where you change the hue instead of something else like value or saturation).  This is a pretty good <a href="https://www.blue-canary.net/miniature-painting/painting-tips-and-guides/hue-shifting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">guide to hue shifting</a>.</p>
<p>I wasn’t able to get the exact colours they have in the guide but I’m pretty happy with where my hues ended up. I feel like I lost some structure in the fur pieces but I think I understood the made shape takeaways that make the fur look dynamic.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.5-1f014abd456dadc88bf5f5be78f239de.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.6-a0be5cb5cc81676c931a5cce70fe2a4d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This was a very fun and refreshing week. It was nice to focus on small little studies that could be completed, while feeling like I’m filling in some blanks in my brain. I’m going to keep collecting guides like this and try to do another small studies week before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-materials/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kylie</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/kylies</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="art" term="art"/>
        <category label="wap" term="wap"/>
    </entry>
</feed>