<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kymira Blog</title>
        <link>https://kymira.ca/blog</link>
        <description>Kymira Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 32]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 32 - Pokemon Ability Forms]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week is another shift in the weekly format. So along with the regular subject studies, and anatomy studies, I want to try to work in a “finished piece” once a month (even if there are only 2 left…). For me a finished piece mostly just means fully rendered to a degree where I’m happy to share it on socials. These will mostly be chosen from current internet art trends or challenges as I like to know my theme going into the week.</p>
<p>The theme for this week is the Pokemon Ability Forms exercise. All Pokemon have an ability, this is usually between two abilities with some Pokemon getting a 3rd hidden ability. Abilities will provide Pokemon with an extra, often passive, mechanic during combat. For example: Pikachu most often has the ability Static, which means that when an opposing Pokemon makes physical contact with that Pikachu, there is a 1 in 3 chance the opposing Pokemon is paralyzed by the static.</p>
<p>The idea behind this challenge is what if a Pokemon’s ability changed the way the Pokemon physically appeared. So a Pikachu with the ability Static might have static electricity jumping all over its fur. I heard of the exercise from a recent <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XAskhVaGu4Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Drawfee episode</a> and did some research to try to find the originator of the exercise and I’ve come to believe it was started by <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/n0rtist" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">n0rtist</a> with this <a href="https://n0rtist.tumblr.com/post/752603925067268096/what-if-abilities-changed-the-appearance-of-a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tumblr post</a> (Sounds like it may have been a Tweet first but Twitter is impossible to use now).</p>
<p>I like it as a challenge because it’s a design challenge with an existing character. So not a full head to toe design but working off of basically one word and a one sentence description to make changes with.</p>
<p>But anyway this is a lot of preamble for a blog post, let’s get into it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---research--sketches">Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-1---research--sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Research &amp; Sketches">​</a></h2>
<p>I spent a decent amount of time scrolling a list of all Pokemon and reading their abilities. I wanted one that had 2 basic ones and a hidden ability to have 3 characters to draw. I went with Omastar because I have a soft spot for him after his role in the original Twitch Plays Pokemon and I wanted to keep drawing ocean creatures. He also has 3 abilities that I was able to imagine some solid visual elements right from the get go.</p>
<p>After doing the research phase I did some quick first idea sketches:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.1-76eb6cbec447e0732ad618db52b96490.jpg" width="4074" height="1275" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---digital-sketches">Day 2 - Digital sketches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-2---digital-sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Digital sketches" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Digital sketches">​</a></h2>
<p>Instead of bringing my hand sketches into a digital format I re-did them in CSP to spend a little more time thinking about poses and design.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Sketches in red digital pencil of 3 omastars" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.2-7480f891e495fac899390b34747c90a7.jpg" width="2800" height="2967" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---swift-swim">Day 3 - Swift Swim<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-3---swift-swim" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Swift Swim" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Swift Swim">​</a></h2>
<p>For Swift Swim I wanted longer tentacles for swimming but also a slightly more aerodynamic shell for faster movement in water.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.3-293848094ed93b91b45eca88902493f7.jpg" width="2323" height="2261" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---shell-armor">Day 4 - Shell Armor<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-4---shell-armor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Shell Armor" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Shell Armor">​</a></h2>
<p>I was torn between how big to go with Shell Armor, some of my earlier sketches definitely had more of the body covered but it ended up looking to diaper-like to me. I’m pretty happy with the helmet look though.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.4-c08e36ef61b0869ba6fcb1a3b08a5edb.jpg" width="2190" height="2109" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---weak-armor">Day 5 - Weak Armor<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#day-5---weak-armor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Weak Armor" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Weak Armor">​</a></h2>
<p>Weak Armor was probably the hardest design wise. How I conceptualised it was that on hit, the weak armor would break off and this makes the Pokemon faster as it’s carrying around less weight. Possibly even has some cool regenerate ability but I wasn’t sure how to visually represent that. So I just went with some big pieces being knocked off but still ready to fight.</p>
<p>This one is pink because that's the Omastar shiny variant.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-32.5-533d3c584e318faa698d57a22661ea44.jpg" width="2500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-32#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Once completed I put them all on a page with some experimental design so it wasn’t just a plain white background.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/omastar-abilityforms-827336f5598fe4f38f90c7a086d0bd78.jpg" width="2800" height="3508" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I really enjoyed this project. I don’t do design stuff often so it was a nice creative stretch. Dividing it into 1 character per day was also a nice breakdown as they each only took 1-2 hours depending on how confident I was in the sketch and after I figured out the painting method I wanted to use. It’s probably not noticeable but I did a light, textured white paint over the base colours to tone down the colours a bit. Original Pokemon artwork was in water colours so a lot of Pokemon art tries to emulate that and I liked the slightly softer look it gave this.</p>
<p>I used a web app to get the Omastar name in that font: <a href="https://pokemon-fonts-generator.netlify.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokemon Fonts Generator</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 31]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 31 - Flowers]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week’s practice is another vague and ambitious theme; flowers. Vague because there are so many different kinds of flowers and ambitious because I often feel like I only know 5 flowers. But I see flowers constantly as they are probably the most common tattoo theme and I follow a lot of tattoo artists on Instagram. But I myself rarely draw them. So I thought it would be good to practice since they are such a common theme in art.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Not a terrible day one?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.1-9f671f0c4c3e423ac6203ea96f89efe5.jpg" width="2753" height="1833" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>When researching flowers it was a bit of a case of “I want to draw that one and that one and that one etc.”. There are a lot of interesting shapes out there so it was hard to choose to focus on a select few to get good at those or to keep trying new ones to try to internalise more ways flowers can look.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.2-f85777a65571d3e419f88f6ba4c6cd90.jpg" width="2899" height="2009" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Easily could have spent hours doing reference studies as I found these to be pretty relaxing. Sunflowers came up a lot in my search results so that and roses are probably the real theme of this week.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.1-e3d4d3be0e7ec3ef9c02ea29a4c70dd1.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.2-f8027bfc35a7d7d41b33c7f4987b61e7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.3.3-8bfc09795c59e313c68bd4a33b83807b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Is there a more drawn subject than flowers? (okay probably human bodies due to everyone’s efforts to do figure drawing practice). I probably could have scrolled Pinterest for hours for reference images but I knew it was a trap and grabbed the first few slightly different looking ones I found.</p>
<p>I worked on a few of these on the train and I felt the rocky, unsteadiness of the train added a nice jitter to my line work that made the petals look more organic.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.1-95b1219653ef2ab7da8ef94f24ce27c0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Pantone flowers by ??? I’m absolutely shocked that Google research image search had nothing for these. I even chose it because I felt certain I had seen these images on Twitter in the past. But the only thing I could find was links to Russian websites selling the art on merch?? <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/598978819227861200/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest pin</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.2-bf825b77eed479ec331f36045eb032c2.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Sunflowers by <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/libbyframe/711818392918687744/coming-soon-the-bloom-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Libby Frame</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.4.3-d5619fd9a81cd9100999e9de225a4506.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Hydrangeas by what seems to be an art resources from <a href="https://jeforel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jeforel</a>?? and <a href="https://www.howjoyful.com/flower-drawing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HowJoyful</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I chose the 3 flowers first for day 5 and then went from there. Mixing a bit of the stylistic flowers with general memory.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-31.5-86073de16a22c9477a3bed9a1b7c7966.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-31#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>After 2 weeks of flowers I do kind of wish I had chosen one flower type to focus on. Hydrangeas were lots of fun but drawing so many little flowers was definitely time consuming.</p>
<p>Been thinking a lot about how I want my art practice to change in 2025 which has led to thinking a lot about master studies. I’ve been watching videos of other people doing master studies and they always look like, like trying to solve a mystery or a puzzle. But they do also look rather intense so I’m not sure what’s a realistic goal for doing studies. 1 a week? 1 a month?</p>
<p>But I’d also like to start working on pieces I’m comfortable sharing as even though I’ve been drawing consistently all year, none of my weekly practice pieces are finished pieces. And while studies are important they aren’t really, fully “yours”. So I also want to find a way to work on new personal art more. Still have a few months to figure it all out.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-flowers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of flowers</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 30]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 30 - Sugar Gliders]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Week 30! It feels like a small number when compared to all numbers, but it’s pretty good when compared to 52. And there are still a few more weeks to go in the year. I’m starting to try to figure out how I want to approach art practice next year now. I don’t think I want to keep doing WAP guided practice, I feel like I should get out of the comfort zone and try to move into working on complete pieces. Or another idea is to do more Master Studies.</p>
<p>Having weekly homework has been great for having something to work on every day but it’s also been a fair bit of pressure to get through the practice every week and get a blog post out for each one. But we’ll see, I have no idea what 2025 is going to look like yet so don’t want to make any big commitments.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>So I actually had two pet sugar gliders from about the age of 14 to 21, so you’d think I’d have a pretty decent mental model of what they look like. But it has been more than 12 years since I’ve been around one…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.1-d1fc2006774c0bad800785588d0d17f9.jpg" width="2984" height="2204" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.2-6932829446b08d89f34e68a2825b9f90.jpg" width="2914" height="2115" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.1-1a55175c4bd1afdccd149483cc546cea.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.2-44e157eaaaceba2cd924d44558abfbfa.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.3.3-dca8c38f7c284cf7a56aa5b0a0551646.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I was fairly surprised to find that there aren’t too many stylized takes on sugar gliders. Possibly because they aren’t a North American creature. We had endless sources for creatures like raccoons, rabbits, pigeons, etc. But also Pinterest is a pretty garbage website as when I go to collect my references at the end of the week there are suddenly more results and I struggle to find the ones I used. Are there results that I only see on iPad, that are different than one desktop?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.4.1-f876595163a2af1e241d1c1cb7c782ea.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.ac-illust.com/main/detail.php?id=23007284" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">From illustAC stock images.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.4.2-1c50fda8ccb88015da6374b78a3fcf0b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.shutterstock.com/id/g/catalyststuff" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Catalyst Labs on Shutterstock.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Took a bit to find my groove on day 5. But I felt pretty confident that if I gave myself enough time I could refine the sketches into solid versions of sugar gliders.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-30.5-8ad199eb1c8ca618eadc228adb51096f.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-30#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Have a fair bit going on for the next two weeks so I’m not sure if I’ll have enough time to get through two whole WAP practices. I’ve started an ambitious possible Altar Stone animation but so far it involves drawing 100 trees and I don’t know if I’m going to still like it by the time I reach tree 100.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-sugargliders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of sugar gliders.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 29]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 29 - Horseback riding]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An anatomy week with an extra complication, horses. My goal for the week wasn’t to learn to draw horses, a famously difficult creature to master. But more to focus on the shape human bodies take while riding.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.1-bcc8326bdacce7e1cfcb315c8acddfbf.jpg" width="3031" height="2111" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I wanted to spend at least some time studying side saddle riding, even though I don’t think it’s going to come up as often as… non side saddle? Middle saddle?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.2-9d580ff572ab08ff179ba39bfb7be27f.jpg" width="3441" height="2391" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Did a first pass traced in red to try to understand the shapes going on. Bodies are often very hunched so it’s hard to place limbs properly. And because the legs are curved outwards they also lose some length, making for some not perfect looking proportions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.1-80ea63a249eff3027637da28217baa95.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.2-7a5ea62f08bd118309bb8266aca879ff.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.3.3-f9a36efa5c10b20dc1672c26a609c50b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>These aren’t super stylized but I wanted to do some artistic references to see if they felt any different. The main thing is that the horse feels like the wild card in artistic interpretations. Some people make the horse extra big to look more powerful while others keep them smaller to make them look more friendly.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.1-100556f614c9aa75f8a46e5b8eb97a2a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: I found this from <a href="https://skyryedesign.com/art/horse-drawing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sky Rye Design blog post on horse drawing.</a>. But they took this piece from <a href="https://toodrawtothink.tumblr.com/post/122776324553/horses-thanks-so-much-to-dan-and-cassie-sprenger" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a TooDrawToThink Tumblr post.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.2-7f3a8d220d9c7222e2c0e463ed499893.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Absolutely can't find a source on this one which is ridiculous. The reverse image search brings up links to music albums which makes no sense. <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/859132066431247458/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This is it's only pin.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.4.3-789e27f63207f9446e6b7ba76a6cd14d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Can’t find a proper source for this one either, <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/4362930875864189/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">just the Pinterest pin.</a>. But there's also a Reddit thread referencing it, but also with no original source that I could spot. Begging artist to tag/sign their stuff so I can find you T_T</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>There was definitely more variety to poses than I was expecting, which made going into day 5 feel intimidating. I ended up just trying to focus on simple poses as I felt like the hunched riding pose was decently difficult on it’s own.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-29.5-74e2d51a72dc016c239ac239e4639602.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-29#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I would like to do a horse focused week before the end of the year, feels appropriate to tackle the traditional hard subjects.</p>
<p>This coming week is hopefully a return to a nice simple creature week. I’ve found it hard to get into creative projects the last two weeks. When I don’t have a main project on the go, like an Altar Stone background, I often open Procreate, look at not finished pieces, and then just close it. Tried starting a few new things in the last 2 weeks but none of them felt great. Just kind of lost my creative steam.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-horseback/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of horseback riding.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Altar Stone - Item Set 1]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 3 first items published with Altar Stone videos]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The most recent addition we’ve made to our Altar Stone videos is adding a homebrewed, on theme, item to the end of the video. This has been a fun creative challenge and our first attempt at bundling more “worth” into the video projects. These are the first 3 we've shared.</p>
<p>We are basing the items off of 5e (2014) for now. Might be fun to revisit the mechanics if we personally branch out to other systems in this golden age of new TTRPG releases.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="abyssal-harp">Abyssal Harp<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#abyssal-harp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Abyssal Harp" title="Direct link to Abyssal Harp">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-harp-c418140d157b961a258fa6a86fe2afa5.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, instrument, very rare (requires attunement by a bard),</em>
<em>5lbs</em></p>
<p>An instrument of the submerged Eighth College, this harp takes the form of a series of interconnected tubes mounted on a frame of coral. When moved through water in a precise and fluid motion, the harp creates sound vibrations and subtle changes in water pressure that are perceived as ethereal music by the listener.</p>
<p>While you are fully immersed in water and holding this harp, the current adds its voice to yours when you cast spells. You gain a +1 bonus to the saving throw DC of your bard spells and a +1 bonus to Constitution saving throws made to maintain concentration on a spell.</p>
<p>While you are holding this harp, you can cast <em>prestidigitation</em> as an action. Illusions created with this spell take on a watery character: visual illusions shimmer and waver, while auditory illusions are deep and sonorous. Once per day, as an action, you can use the harp to cast <em>create or destroy water</em> as a 5th level spell. This property recharges at dawn, whether or not the sun is visible at your current depth.</p>
<p>The harp can only be played underwater. The vibrations and pressure changes it generates are imperceptible in air or empty space. When affixed to an underwater surface in an area with strong currents, the harp will seemingly play itself as water flows through it, allowing the ocean to speak with a gentler voice and for the patient listener to hear the musings of its queen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rod-of-reanimation">Rod of Reanimation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#rod-of-reanimation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rod of Reanimation" title="Direct link to Rod of Reanimation">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-rod-90d6b4070aa010859e76c40523245f8a.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, rod, very rare (requires attunement by a wizard, warlock, or sorcerer),</em>
<em>10lbs</em></p>
<p>This rod of crystal and steel is topped with a transparent sphere, inside which arc and sputter streams of blue and purple lightning. Adventurers are advised not to spend undue time considering the origin of the fluid that circulates within the handle.</p>
<p>The rod has 3 charges. While you hold it, you can use an action and consume a charge to cast one of the following spells from it: <em>animate dead</em> or <em>lightning bolt</em>. As charges are consumed, the fluid within the handle depletes proportionately. The charges (and the fluid) return at dawn.</p>
<p>Creatures reanimated by the Rod have the property <em>Came Back Wrong</em>. At the beginning of the creature’s turn, roll a ten-sided die.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Roll</th><th style="text-align:left">Condition</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">1</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature cannot act this turn. If the creature was capable of speech in life, it begs for death from the nearest creature. Otherwise, it howls in wordless agony.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">2-3</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature goes into a wild rage, screaming and attacking the nearest creature with all its strength. It makes a melee attack roll with an additional +2 to hit and a 1d6 bonus to damage.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">4-10</td><td style="text-align:left">The creature behaves normally this turn.</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="glass-of-sands">Glass of Sands<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#glass-of-sands" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Glass of Sands" title="Direct link to Glass of Sands">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/AS-hourglass-3da755a556fececffe6c232611ac19d4.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Wondrous item, legendary,</em>
<em>5lbs</em></p>
<p>Within the hourglass, discovered in the outstretched hand of a withered corpse, the sands swirl without cease as if scattered by eternal sirocco. When you pick it up, you feel as though you can hear the wind inside, the susurrus of a thousand thousand imprisoned in dust.</p>
<p>Once a week, as an action, you may cast any one spell of 8th level or less on your class’s spell list by turning the glass upside down and reciting the incantation inscribed along its edges. While the sand is flowing, time is paused for the user as the hourglass draws power from within the core of their soul to assemble the energies necessary for the spell. Consult the table below to determine how much your character ages as a result of using this feature.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Spell level</th><th style="text-align:left">Duration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">1</td><td style="text-align:left">1 month</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">2</td><td style="text-align:left">2 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">3</td><td style="text-align:left">3 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">4</td><td style="text-align:left">5 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">5</td><td style="text-align:left">8 months</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">6</td><td style="text-align:left">1 year</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">7</td><td style="text-align:left">2 years</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">8</td><td style="text-align:left">3 years</td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>While time is paused, the hourglass’s holder cannot act, and only the sand within the hourglass moves. The rest of the world is held in suspension. The subjective duration of the time freeze for both the user and those in the vicinity is left to the GM.</p>
<p>If the hourglass is shattered, the soul-dust within is freed, and each fleck will spend the remainder of its existence attempting to locate and re-incorporate with the soul that shed it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/as-items1#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Next week is back to regular WAP posting. I may have chosen an anatomy challenge that’s too complicated but we’ll see if it can be done without learning the anatomy of horses…</p>
<p>I ended up downloading Resprite on the iPad so I’ve been poking around at pixel art a bit. Hoping to try out animating in a few weeks when I look up a tutorial on how to properly use the app. But also a bunch of my Clippy points were going to expire so I went on a big Clip Studio Paint spending spree and now have a bunch of new brushes I want to experiment with. And Swordtember is still going on!!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>dnd</category>
            <category>homebrew</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 28]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 28 - Raccoons]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week's raccoon theme gets me close to wrapping up “city creatures”. Though I guess I’ve skipped rats and mice but that’s more because my wife is afraid of them and also I don’t want to think about mice when I don’t have too.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 1, a little messy as always. The big thing being I couldn’t remember what raccoon face patterns look like. And there body shape came out much too similar to cats.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.1-17ea79033a15d9cd6ba67642ff976fa0.jpg" width="3072" height="2102" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 2 gave us the raccoon who wants a hug, who took off on BluSky a bit. Setting the bar high for the rest of the week. How could a raccoon be cuter?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.2-125f301429828f6bb903c362d4f736e0.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Ended up spending 2 days on reference studies. Probably too long but I was enjoying the process. I’m a big fan of the chunky raccoon shape. Just drawing a bunch of fur and curves.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.3-ff39d36af80f4f20b58669bc668fda82.jpg" width="3000" height="2074" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I know I could find endless raccoon cartoon references if I kept digging but I had a very busy week so just grabbed the top Pinterest results.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.1-a74677cfbbc48a5dfe158e89ca11a4f1.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://spicymochi.tumblr.com/post/720210870068789248/he-is-sitting-politely" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Art by SpicyMochi / Renee</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.2-fecc47208807f79836ce3409bc4a1aaa.jpg" width="2757" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://society6.com/eloisenarrigan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon print by Eloise Narrigan</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.4.3-bafc822bf73cc1c4e1325f07d4abe8b3.jpg" width="2372" height="1859" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://gamepackstudio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raccoon Twitch emojis. It says these are from Game Pack Studio, but the website doesn’t share this anywhere.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I was afraid to do justice to cute raccoons on day 5. Still images of raccoons don’t really show the silliness and mischievousness. I wanted to try to capture that in chip raccoon. Sleeping raccoon was from a photo I remembered seeing and then the sitting guy was just me trying to get the shape right from memory.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-28.5-4cb47a1d5fa5ae569833bfd7ffe9c180.jpg" width="3000" height="1321" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="software-contemplations">Software contemplations<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#software-contemplations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Software contemplations" title="Direct link to Software contemplations">​</a></h2>
<p>There’s been a lot of new iPad apps dropping over the last year that I’m currently tempted by. I feel like 3 years ago when I was looking for 3D modelling things there were zero options. Then a few weeks ago I learned of <a href="https://nomadsculpt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nomad Sculpt</a> which people compare favourably to Blender (which is desktop only). And then very recently <a href="https://www.maxon.net/en/zbrush-for-ipad" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZBrush</a> also released an iPad version of their software. I’m not familiar enough with the existing software to draw my own conclusions and everything is still pretty recent so I haven’t found great comparison articles or videos yet.</p>
<p>But I’d like to mess around with 3D models next year so I’ll keep trying to find a good option. Blender is free but being desktop only is a downside for me as my laptop is starting to show its age so the iPad is the more reliable hardware choice.</p>
<p>I’ve also been eyeing <a href="https://www.aseprite.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aseprite</a> for pixel art, but again, it doesn’t have an iPad version. People recommend <a href="https://resprite.fengeon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Resprite</a> for iPad, but the main thing people say Aseprite does better is video game assets and video game assets are my long term goals. So it feels like the wrong choice to go for the inferior choice when I know what I’m trying to do. There’s also just a very noticeable lack of Resprite tutorials out there, but there is a wealth of Aseprite tutorials.</p>
<p>Just feeling stuck in choices right now and wishing there were more people writing and comparing these softwares. But all I can really get info from is Reddit posts :|</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-28#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Running a bit behind on art due to having a very busy week last week. Gonna focus on some other art projects and blog posts and resume WAP exercises next week.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-raccoon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of raccoons.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 27]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 27 - Material studies]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week's study theme was inspired from the <a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc">One Week Character challenge</a> I did a few months ago. The instructure spent a decent amount of time talking about material painting and using it to livin up your character's look. I struggled with the focus on metal as I didn’t feel like I had enough time in the 1 day devoted to materials to really learn, and instead just ended up trying to fake it. But after that I added Material Studies to my list of upcoming WAPs, and now we finally got there.</p>
<p>I started by gathering up material step-by-step guides I could find on Pinterest. The most common ones are gold and metal, but the metadata on these things isn’t great so it was hard to keep searching for more, broader themes. Out of the ones I found I choose 5 that feel like decent beginner materials, by which I probably mean most common. I also choose ones that had the most understandable guides, preferring ones that also had text that explained the steps.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---wood">Day 1 - Wood<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-1---wood" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Wood" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Wood">​</a></h2>
<p>I find wood rather intimidating to paint, I suspect others do too as it’s very easy to find a brush to do the effect. It’s my go-to move for Altar Stone videos or other backgrounds where I need to do a large piece of wood because the idea of drawing all the needed lines is exhausting. But that’s what we did on day 1.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.1-ef890115c8b406a0996efa002eddcff8.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m very happy with how this went, even though I did get lost in the steps for a while. The instructions could be more clear. I didn’t add as many scratches but that was mostly because I felt like the ones I did do were enough to learn what was going on. This piece also came together rather quickly which was a nice discovery, making the idea of doing hand drawn wood objects in the future less daunting.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/gimaldinov/art/How-to-draw-wooden-plank-267517599" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wood tutorial</a> by
Gimaldinov. I found this version of the tutorial while putting the blog post together and now I see that there were more steps! I didn’t know about the last few!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---gold">Day 2 - Gold<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-2---gold" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Gold" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Gold">​</a></h2>
<p>Gold felt pretty straight forward and was the fastest of the bunch. I do feel like I’ve lost some texture and I could have pushed the highlights harder.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A step by step guide on how to paint gold next to a large golden chalice." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.2-6af054c375be199f7d294a4aee3cc9bc.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Gold tutorial by <a href="https://www.colinadams.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Colin Adams</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---metal">Day 3 - Metal<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-3---metal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Metal" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Metal">​</a></h2>
<p>I hesitated on doing metal and gold on back to back days, thinking they would feel too similar. But I tried to focus on fixing the texture problem which led to some impressive results. At least after my first attempt which turned into a smudged mess.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.3-3dc172fe8f1d17e681368a9a64ffc349.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>A big struggle with the instructions for these things is that it’s not clear how you’re meant to be painting. Not everyone suggests a brush type so I would do trial and error with different kinds of brushes to try to get a similar look. Then I would try to soften the edges between colours but if you smug too much it’s easy to lose texture and lighting.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.deviantart.com/mateslaurentiu/art/Armor-tutorial-220805678" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metal tutorial</a> by <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/mateslaurentiu/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MatesLaurentiu</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---scales">Day 4 - Scales<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-4---scales" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Scales" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Scales">​</a></h2>
<p>I was pretty excited for scales, thinking I would learn a technique to make 100 diamonds look good all at once. Turns out, no, you must draw every diamond.</p>
<p>At least if you want to do a shiny, impressive close up.</p>
<p>This study took the longest of the 5. The base approach of wavy lines on a column is very good for getting the shape down, but after that it’s very much <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/how-to-draw-an-owl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“draw the rest of the owl”</a> feeling.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.4-d7e00538588f280a9945db0c81fe7a93.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I lined every scale, painting in the base colour, did one round of highlights, a second round of highlights, 2 rounds of shadows, then added more detail base colours somewhere in between. Went back and fixed the shadows because they needed to be blended. Went back and fixed the highlights because they needed to be blended. All those steps repeated for each scale.</p>
<p>When I write it out it sounds terrible, but it can become relaxing. Once you know what you’re trying to accomplish with the specific step you’re on, it’s easier to turn your brain off and just do it for a while. So I could see a huge scaled creature project being pretty fun. But I don’t think it’s something I’ll do often.</p>
<p>Scales tutorial by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Anastasiaberry" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anastasia Deg aka AnastasiaBerry</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---fur">Day 5 - Fur<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#day-5---fur" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Fur" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Fur">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t love this fur tutorial at first glance but all the steps felt clear so I went with it. It wasn’t until I started to read the instructions and follow along that I noticed that the shading part of the approach focused on hue shifting which is a technique I want to get better at (hue shifting is where you change the hue instead of something else like value or saturation).  This is a pretty good <a href="https://www.blue-canary.net/miniature-painting/painting-tips-and-guides/hue-shifting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">guide to hue shifting</a>.</p>
<p>I wasn’t able to get the exact colours they have in the guide but I’m pretty happy with where my hues ended up. I feel like I lost some structure in the fur pieces but I think I understood the made shape takeaways that make the fur look dynamic.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.5-1f014abd456dadc88bf5f5be78f239de.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-27#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-27.6-a0be5cb5cc81676c931a5cce70fe2a4d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This was a very fun and refreshing week. It was nice to focus on small little studies that could be completed, while feeling like I’m filling in some blanks in my brain. I’m going to keep collecting guides like this and try to do another small studies week before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-materials/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 Year of Altar Stone]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A look back on our first year of Altar Stone and some other art projects in August]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I haven’t been doing my weekly art practice while on vacation, there has still been a lot of projects on the go as well as our 1 year anniversary of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone</a>.</p>
<p>I haven’t posted all of the art I’ve done for Altar Stone as it’s split between multiple iPads and computers at this point. But the anniversary feels like a good time to put in the effort to gather them into a post.</p>
<p>It was also Drawclass week last week so I’ll share my progress of trying to follow along to portrait painting.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-year-in-review">A year in review<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024#a-year-in-review" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A year in review" title="Direct link to A year in review">​</a></h2>
<p>Our first Altar Stone video went up on August 23rd 2023. I believe I’ve mentioned in the past that this was just going to be a static image until my wife took a shot at animating the sword in the octopus’s arm. That launched the animation project that Altar Stone has become for me. We’ve gone from PowerPoint, to multiple different animation apps to now learning the Godot game engine to try out different animation flows.</p>
<p>In the last year we’ve published 13 videos, some of which reused assets as alternate themes of a song released. Putting us at a little more than 1 video per month. We both have art and music in the pipeline waiting to be paired so I’d say our real total is closer to 15 videos.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Screenshot of our YouTube page showing 13 videos listed." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yt-altarstone-464608aca1757893445c79a3dba30331.png" width="1310" height="1346" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>We’ve been brainstorming ways to make Altar Stone into a product and have some ideas for the next year. We’ve already started by adding some homebrew magic items paired to each song. We’re going to wrap up Songs in the Key of Sea as our first album / completed playlist, and we’ll start packaging that either on our own site or somewhere people can purchase it to have .mp3 versions of the songs to use outside of YouTube. Maybe we’ll entertain the idea of commissioned work, but pricing a whole thing. We’ve even <a href="https://ko-fi.com/altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">set up a Ko-fi</a> for people to support the project, which was first motivated by people asking what to get us as wedding gifts, we encouraged them to support our project.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="All the backgrounds I drew for Altar Stone videos so far." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/as-year1-f6471b5060a4c78e37ffef8a2336275d.png" width="5760" height="8650" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>For my own artistic goals with the project, I’m hoping to learn more Godot for the videos. Our first pixel art/Godot video got nearly 100 views in the first 24 hours, with us only sharing it with our friends. So the algorithm liked something about it to suggest it to other viewers. Easily the largest day 1 response we’ve seen to a video. But I also feel like if I can get the fundamentals of Godot down I can create videos faster as it’s often much easier than animating my ideas by hand.</p>
<p>I’m also considering doing some still backgrounds. I’ve been learning a lot of animation for the last few months, which has led to practising different artistic skills. Non-animated backgrounds will give me a chance to play around with more ambitious paintings and scenes that are beyond my ability to animate in a month.</p>
<p>So one year into this project and it feels like we’re still gathering steam. Last month we even started a Trello board to better track the pieces that are in the works. The 2nd year of Altar Stone should be an exciting one.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="latest-altar-stone-release">Latest Altar Stone release<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024#latest-altar-stone-release" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Latest Altar Stone release" title="Direct link to Latest Altar Stone release">​</a></h2>
<p>We released a new Altar Stone video a few days ago. Sophie’s approach to mermaid music as I had finished the art a few months before she started to work on the music so she had some imply direction already.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W79yyLzZiJY?si=cmvOW2l6ESJgtazw" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>I’m happy with a lot of this piece. I spent a lot of time trying to make a convincing stone texture on the walls and on the mermaid statue. Did some research into options for the water flowing from the pot and I feel like it sells really well for one of the simpler approaches to moving water. Feeling like the falling water, the drops, and the surface water wasn’t enough for a scene I then added the little crab to practise some frame by frame animation (where you draw each iteration of the thing moving each frame).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="portraits-with-julia-drawclass">Portraits with Julia Drawclass<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024#portraits-with-julia-drawclass" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Portraits with Julia Drawclass" title="Direct link to Portraits with Julia Drawclass">​</a></h2>
<p>The monthly Drawfee Drawclass was portraits this month. I almost didn’t attend because portraits have never been my thing and I was in the middle of making tater tots when the class started. But Sophie encouraged me to go sit down and I ended up enjoying it a lot.</p>
<p>Julia covered some of the main things to keep in mind and how to approach a portrait, emphasising the importance of your sketch and having good, high quality reference photos. Julia was using a version of this still from Glass Onion and I Googled my own version for following along but suspect I didn’t get a high quality one as I didn’t want to spend too much time searching.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Screenshot of Benoit Blanc from Glass Onion, straight on face, half shadowed." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/bb-portrait-ref-25be9d2bbce1f4cdb6edc7a9e8cf501e.jpg" width="963" height="914" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>There wasn’t enough time to get through the whole process, she covered all the blocking in and then started to blend/paint the skin. This is how far I got:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Day 1 progress." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/dc-portrait1-0c57511715f7958e199924d537e7f62d.PNG" width="2732" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m honestly surprised at how well it came together with just blending the blocks together, it’s already starting to look like a face.</p>
<p>I returned to it a little bit in the days after the class. We didn’t cover eyes, hair, or lips during the class so I was afraid to get to those. First attempt on lips feels bad, first pass on hair also felt bad. To the point where I felt like I was starting to lose Daniel Craig’s face. But the eyes! I feel like the eyes came out super well on the first try, not even taking that much time.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Daniel Craig portrait progress." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/dc-portrait2-34c5bad5a028d2f725ce1438563822ba.jpg" width="2218" height="1825" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This went smoothly enough that I would consider doing other portraits from reference in the future. But I still don’t feel like I know how to approach hair which will hold me back for a bit.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="art-talk-by-aleksander-rostov">Art talk by Aleksander Rostov<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024#art-talk-by-aleksander-rostov" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Art talk by Aleksander Rostov" title="Direct link to Art talk by Aleksander Rostov">​</a></h2>
<p>Aleksander Rostov was the Art Director on Disco Elysium, a game that has some extremely beautiful and messed up art in it. His talk focuses on the piece of composition and design, going over how they are the pieces that you use, alter, change, or ignore, to create your own style. I had hoped he’d spend some time talking about his personal workflow or how things came together in the game but the talk was fairly focused on understanding the board fundamentals. But Rostov is a pretty interesting speaker, so it made for an entertaining talk even when being familiar with the concepts.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ByiwvWN4_NA?si=BCCyUxLRtS1Nr3j_" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/august-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Next week I’m back to weekly art practice now that life is returning to a regular pace. But I’m breaking from the classic format once again, this time to do a week of material / texture studies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>altar-stone</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 26]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 26 - Griffins]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week is another fictional creature week. Started off pretty rough but came up with a good practice approach for a creature that doesn’t exist.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 1 was rough. I’m not really sure if I should put more time into the day one task as it doesn’t feel like I’m set up to learn anything yet. But it makes the jump in progress also feel a little fake as I know I can do better than what I draw on day 1 sometimes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.1-47c7bc0517e1d781b5e536f4baa943d7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 2 was good, used some of my favourite images I had found as reference for some quick sketches. I love the little cat-peregrine.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.2-f4b207b74b9204f4995b1fcfe971a3a9.jpg" width="3072" height="2132" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Reference studies went okay, went with some more traditional griffins. A mediaeval emblem type and a simple modern adaptation.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.3.1-d19033d3ceea2f6368d914621314532c.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://about-mythical-creatures.weebly.com/griffin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Someone’s cute old-web site about mythical creatures.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.3.2-b13d911c3d990ae4447c449922ead9fb.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://cole_chetti.artstation.com/projects/rRJXZ5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Griffin by Cole Marchetti</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Instead of style studies for day 4 I return to the practice of “drawing from life” by choosing one bird reference and one lion reference. The exercise being I need to merge them together myself but would have realistic portions for each half.</p>
<p>This was my favourite day as it felt like the “right” approach. I wish I had thought of it sooner and I would have just done different combos every day cause I like seeing different bird types of griffins.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.4-063d7036fa99672c041963a03431e416.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Drawing from imagination felt a little rough. I wanted to try a more dramatic flying pose but that ended up being a bit more perspective work than I was prepared to do. For the second one I wanted to try to capture cute cat + bird but without a reference for either it feels messy.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-26.5-0623abc563147e05bca2d669795a39ac.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-26#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I’d like to spend another week with griffins as they’re one of my favourite mythological creatures. Maybe I’ll return to them later this year. But next up is some travel time so I’m going to take a week or two off of focused practice and just doodle for the next week or so.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-griffin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of griffins.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 25]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 25 - Gymnastic bars]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I added this theme to my list, I didn’t realise it was going to coincide with the olympics. Thought there would be some good photography of bodies in motion with gymnasts as a theme. I hadn’t meant to be so narrow but ended up only using references of people on the bars. Then when I got deeper into it I thought there would be some more unique poses, but people seem to love the shot of a person looking long.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>When I started the week I thought I’d find more references where people would be simply hanging from the bar. Maybe warming up? Well I saw none.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.1-a306c7853eebdb47bb3c9d5818dfb169.jpg" width="2988" height="2101" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Lot of C curves going on.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.2-eae72f43ef4c488ef96b1f4e5dee5c20.jpg" width="2970" height="2102" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Days 3 and 4 become basically the same thing on anatomy days now. Trying to think up a different kind of challenge for day 4 other than continuing regular reference studies.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.3.1-776a9cdf22fa6bb2b1bb2b71db77f814.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.3.2-99d2255f6a79498ee5194d4ae46f9f3c.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>As usual, there wasn’t much to find style wise for gymnasts. So I treated it as another reference study, with some added difficulty of the up angled shot. Struggled with that one a lot, trying to understand where the legs and body were hiding.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.4.1-2b3305291223eb1550f1cfcac93513bd.jpg" width="3556" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.4.2-d76f0cd76f03d2f1bf2834b9f9fd84f1.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Since I found the photography fairly limited angle wise, I’m trying to push myself on drawing from imagination on anatomy weeks. So I’m trying out some “rotate shapes in your head” kind of exercise here. Well in one of my attempts, the overhead, downwards angle. I feel like it turned out even, aside from losing track of what the centre body is doing. The other 2 were more straightforward attempts to practise basic proportions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-25.5-1e7526536aa5cdcf9cb6fb8170aa4daa.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="elden-ring-final">Elden Ring final<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#elden-ring-final" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Elden Ring final" title="Direct link to Elden Ring final">​</a></h2>
<p>I forgot that I didn’t share the final version of my Elden Ring / Honeymoon piece. It’s probably my favourite piece of the year. I see it everyday on my phone screen and it still doesn’t make me cringe.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/eldenring-honeymoon-d5ddf05437e4d4528187702f62d1e3ac.jpg" width="1376" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-25#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m not sure what I’m going to work on this week. I’m torn between taking a week off from art to do some website stuff since I’ll be away from my computer next week. Or just do one final practice week before travelling next week. Also want to keep learning some Godot stuff to see if I can get a nice setup together for getting things out faster. I have a new character and world tileset to play with from <a href="https://www.oryxdesignlab.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oryx Design Lab</a>. Already have a space with a character moving around. Next goals will be to try adding some visual effects and maybe pathing NPCs so they walk around on their own.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/pins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of gymnasts on bars.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 24]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week was a return to creatures, with the common house sparrow as our subject. I also attended an animation course last weekend so I’ll share some stuff from that, and I’ve been working on a new Altar Stone video which was more technically demanding than art demanding for the last few weeks.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>While I chose sparrows to continue on the most common animals in Montreal, it turns out I can only imagine them as basic small birds when not using a reference.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.1-2f6c44cb7769c0827248e8513ff5b918.jpg" width="2838" height="1960" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>With a reference they still kind of look like a basic small bird, but then the colouration patterns really become important for identification. I ended up focusing on male sparrows as they have a really distinctive black chest marking.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.2-579dc59f1574ea076f497525a2c7ba28.jpg" width="2652" height="1954" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.3.1-490c6d1391d9b5591beb75f1c046b9e4.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.3.2-80780b6a985758c540713177f898cbef.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Tried out a variety of styles. But I think I like the classic more detailed sparrow the most.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.4.1-fe9632df6f6cd24f57e562e480d2bea4.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.artstation.com/biabiabia8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stickers by @biateleur</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.4.2-d09677904487b966610afdd0b8828f0a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.vectorstock.com/royalty-free-vector/bird-drawing-vector-548810" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">From VectorStock</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.4.3-36ead8a566616e11223d55166f5240df.jpg" width="3000" height="1334" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://sinitza.gallery.ru/watch?ph=jNT-enOpv#feature=topscroll" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By Shozo Ozaki.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-24.5-d0f03a298eff786ec9ea5171b18ace80.jpg" width="3000" height="1285" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="learning-godot-for-altar-stone">Learning Godot for Altar Stone<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#learning-godot-for-altar-stone" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning Godot for Altar Stone" title="Direct link to Learning Godot for Altar Stone">​</a></h2>
<p>After hearing the most recent Altar Stone track I got hooked on the idea of pixel art for the video. I’m not great at pixel aren’t and I don’t love it. Watching people making tiny pixel changes and getting a whole new character feels like magic to me. So I got the idea to look for open source assets instead of making my own.</p>
<p>I also had a few ideas for the basic animation but while ideating on how I would approach it, it became clear that this would be something easier to do in a game engine than in an animation program. I had poked at Godot a few months ago out of curiosity at the 4.0 launch and the new Brackey video tutorial. So I understood some of the basic steps I knew I’d have to do.</p>
<p>It turned out to be harder than I hoped to find good free assets. There are plenty out there but when you already have an idea in your head it’s hard to accept the limited options. But I eventually chose a tileset, a cute bat for decorations, and some characters who don’t look too ridiculous in the setting.</p>
<p>And then I made the “level” aka the walking course.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Screenshot of a pixel art platformer in Godot" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/cave-level-8c0bd77e3d58fccb1f3c8e7b2e34704d.png" width="1314" height="846" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I got the basics of moving the character around, controlling the camera and working with collision layers. Then needed my wife’s help for follower logic code to execute the idea I had of “adventurer party walking”. Final product coming soon to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone YouTube channel!</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="animation-class-with-spencer-wan">Animation class with Spencer Wan<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#animation-class-with-spencer-wan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Animation class with Spencer Wan" title="Direct link to Animation class with Spencer Wan">​</a></h2>
<p>A few months ago I signed up to a <a href="https://x.com/spencerwan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spencer Wan</a> animation course focused on visual effects. Since effects, instead of full on character animations, is what I have been focusing on in my Alter Stone videos, I thought this course sounded like the perfect fit.</p>
<p>It ended up being 30C+ the day of the course. That’s in the apartment even. So it was the most comfortable 4.5 hours to spend at a computer. But even just the first hour of the program felt enlightening. I did my notes in Clip Studio and then tried to follow the animations steps in SquidToon but the course moved pretty quickly due to time constraints (it was an ambitious agenda!) and only managed to complete the first lightning step by step:</p>
<img src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lightning-spencer-582fcd99f98c9ba9fb1c456a018149bd.gif" width="500">
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="general-notes">General notes<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#general-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to General notes" title="Direct link to General notes">​</a></h3>
<p>Overall it was really great and I find myself trying to find Spencer’s catalogue of work and video to see what else I can learn as he was great at breaking down concepts and approaches to very doable chunks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Animation class notes p1." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Spencer-p1-981f5e690f751101e9c6da36550b512e.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Animation class notes p2." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/Spencer-p2-d17136bf591d078e1d0d233aea4e770a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-24#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>It was a big week for projects. I have a head full of animation ideas now and want to jump into some more big pieces to put them to use. Might get one more week of art in before I got on vacation for a week. It feels nice as I feel like I'm having ideas for projects at a rate I can no longer keep up with. Nice to have the creative sparks and energy firing at the same time.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-sparrow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of sparrows.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 22 & 23]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 22 and 23]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m a blog post behind in WAPs so I'm going to cover the last two weeks in one.</p>
<p>The first week was an attempt at drawing myself. I’ve wanted a self drawn avatar to use online my whole online life but I’ve never managed to draw one I’m happy enough with. And spoiler I still haven’t.</p>
<p>The week after was skulls, which was a theme that was probably too broad. Lots of skull are very different from one another, so choosing something like Human Skulls probably would have given the week more focus.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---myself">Day 1 - Myself<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-1---myself" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Myself" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Myself">​</a></h2>
<p>A few attempts at drawing myself without looking at myself.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-22.1-051dbd893197e33149fa1db065e5ef9c.jpg" width="3071" height="1968" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Starting already a step behind one that I did earlier this year which I don't love.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/first-portrait-87174891eda2ab32a111823af34df175.jpg" width="528" height="824" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---myself---research">Day 2 - Myself - Research<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-2---myself---research" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Myself - Research" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Myself - Research">​</a></h2>
<p>For day two I pulled up some general character art to try out some different styles of drawing faces. This turned out to be more difficult than I expected as it’s not easy to just get a list of different looks so there was a lot of Pinterest.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-22.2-73ee234f15e909f04f61fbbaf32a6cb9.jpg" width="2987" height="1761" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---myself---reference-studies">Day 3 - Myself - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-3---myself---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Myself - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Myself - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>On day two I went through my phone and used old selfies as reference. I haven’t taken many selfies in the last few years, it’s a habit I’m gotten out of. Partially out of a desire to have fewer photos of myself online and just wanting to take photos of cats and squirrels instead.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-22.3-3103a2ff3e14628ec632c0aba9297219.jpg" width="3072" height="2139" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4--5---myself---sketch-progress">Day 4 &amp; 5 - Myself - Sketch progress<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-4--5---myself---sketch-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 &amp; 5 - Myself - Sketch progress" title="Direct link to Day 4 &amp; 5 - Myself - Sketch progress">​</a></h2>
<p>I took another stab at sketching myself after my girlfriend voted for bowl cut with bangs as the most Me looking, look. One of the hardest things about trying to cartoonify myself is that I don’t have a central feature to focus on. Hair is a big identifier for a cartoon and mine changes pretty drastically over 6 months, so even when I do have an avatar I like (Thanks Catarina <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/radiantlethe.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@radiantlethe</a> for previous avatars!) it’s outdated extremely quickly. These days I have 2-3 pairs of glasses that I swap between and are all pretty different. And my face is very… average. Which I mean more in like, my forehead size is very average, not distinguishable, same thing about my nose. My lips are a little different due to surgery but that’s not enough to make a face look like me. Square chin is maybe the strongest face shape feature that can be leaned on.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-22.4-de7f57dd7e4ad242dd07a4b1c7bc6d80.jpg" width="3069" height="1295" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>And then I took it digital. It’s shocking how quickly sketches go from looking okay to looking ridiculous.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-22.5-f68f3563013b270edab7902dd5369ba4.jpg" width="1435" height="1716" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---skulls">Day 1 - Skulls<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-1---skulls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Skulls" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Skulls">​</a></h2>
<p>I thought I had a decent grasp on human skulls but putting pencil to paper really makes my brain want to stop imagining things clearly.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.1-ecf0689140868d92477db2cf74e3bd0c.jpg" width="3058" height="1250" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---skulls">Day 2 - Skulls<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-2---skulls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Skulls" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Skulls">​</a></h2>
<p>Skulls were much easier with references but there are so many kinds and they’re all pretty interesting. There seems to be a lot of interest in cat skulls so those come up a lot.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.2-4e1ab563095adb135b114f58efb35a62.jpg" width="2924" height="2108" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---skulls">Day 3 - Skulls<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-3---skulls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Skulls" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Skulls">​</a></h2>
<p>Drawing more detailed skulls was fairly relaxing. There’s a comfort in them being solid objects.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.3.1-2963ac4e145a39e62c17753dd284d6bb.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.3.2-b9b429bedc897696bc6c313d5c720a9f.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---skulls">Day 4 - Skulls<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-4---skulls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Skulls" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Skulls">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.4.1-f705c521974920840b10ff2aab7c1024.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.4.2-80bb6b8c09fba567e69de6598393b01f.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.4.3-955ea09d5d0828751a62dca435da836c.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---skulls">Day 5 - Skulls<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#day-5---skulls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Skulls" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Skulls">​</a></h2>
<p>I get into a bit of a bird skull rut with the week. It felt easier than a lot of the other ones.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-23.5-4076ecfdb781c1ec14d835a5f84d20e8.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="end-of-sketchbook-1">End of Sketchbook 1<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#end-of-sketchbook-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to End of Sketchbook 1" title="Direct link to End of Sketchbook 1">​</a></h2>
<p>Last year I bought a fresh sketchbook for carrying around, taking to the park and traveling and all that. This morning I used the last page! I picked this up while I was still trying to get into the swing of doing art more often. After a few years of barely drawing at all it felt like such a long shot to fill a new sketchbook.</p>
<p>I’m a notorious sticker hoarder so after getting this sketchbook I put every sticker I got across the course of the year on to it, which has made it into a nice little visual memory of a lot of activities.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/sketchbook1-2d6c3666045fdb577f0b0b57379c678d.jpg" width="4059" height="3213" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-22-23#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>So I had been hoping to end the week with a self portrait avatar I would use, but haven’t. Skulls went pretty okay. And I bought a new sketchbook so it kind of feels like starting a new chapter.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-skulls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">for skulls</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 21]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I didn’t complete my WAP exercises last week. It’s my first time not getting through all 5 exercises but it was an anatomy week which often feel a little weird on the last two days. I hadn’t even found any stylistic waltz references to use for day 4.</p>
<p>But it’s not a lack of references that kept me away. I had a piece that, initially, was going to be rather simple but had turned into one of my most ambitious pieces yet (will share progress later in this post). One of the reasons I have such a structured practice schedule is that I haven’t had many ideas for projects and these focused weeks help me to keep practising and creating even when my head is empty. So the idea that I’m so taken with a new piece feels like my creativity is starting to stir again (it only took 1.5 years). So I’m pretty happy to put weekly practice to the side if it means completing a full piece that I’m excited about.</p>
<p>Besides the new piece getting most of my creative attention, I’ve been dealing with some pretty back upper back/neck pain. So while I want to spend multiple hours a day working on art I’m having to take many breaks and also just limit the amount of time I spend with my head bent in hopes of not making the pain worse. And don’t even get me started on how the current heat wave is completely sapping all my energy.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>One of the reasons I chose waltz as a reference is that it’s a fairly structured dance, almost stiff as dances go. But I also wanted to get into practising pieces with multiple characters where they are touching. Along with the challenge of having most of the pose hidden by a dress. Day 1 poses were rather simple from my brain.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-21.1-54bd3c65d194eb0e102a1df3554a79bc.jpg" width="2549" height="4048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I still think I should be doing this exercise faster than I usually do. Especially with anatomy weeks as I should be trying to capture the movement flow or dynamics of a pose instead of trying to get it exactly right.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-21.2-e3ff40f50e8bad8d3f17ecccf30f5fdc.jpg" width="3072" height="2153" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Only did 2 pieces as I felt like since there are 2 people in each it’s like doing 4 practices. This is where I really tried to problem solve the pose of the figure I can’t see clearly. The nice part of waltz is that the two people are often moving in tandem so it means copying the more visible pose and applying it to the partner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-21.3.1-d3cdb089983bed844dbf6318d71f9854.jpg" width="4607" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-21.3.2-aaa10972d7f72af9fcda02ac875ee40a.jpg" width="4607" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-elden-ring-piece">New Elden Ring Piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21#new-elden-ring-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Elden Ring Piece" title="Direct link to New Elden Ring Piece">​</a></h2>
<p>So I shared a version of my Elden Ring character last week. Ever since the Shadow of the Erdtree DLC came out we’ve been playing for at least 2 hours every day. It’s a lot of Elden Ring. Because this was our main activity after our wedding we’ve been joking that we honeymooned in the Shadow Realm (the new Elden Ring region). We have a collection of video game screenshots as a couple, Animal Crossing, Pokemon Sw/Sh, but we can’t co-op in Elden Ring, so if I wanted our characters together I would have to do it myself.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/er-honeymoon-base-95c9157f9680140ad460a2575488f09d.jpg" width="2395" height="3232" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’ll keep working on this for a few more days. I feel like I’m in the final stages but the background is giving me a pretty hard time. I’m struggling to balance the colours and details in a way that the background doesn’t take away too much from the characters in the foreground, while also trying to not introduce too many colours to keep things balanced. But I keep finding a new thing about the image I don’t love and then re-working it lol.</p>
<p>I’m hoping to focus on the last bit of lighting and shadows and then push the background “further back” so it doesn’t steal attention. All while trying to not make the image too dark or muddied.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-21#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Going to spend a few more days on the Elden Ring Honeymoon piece and then try to get into my new WAP subject. But I also have a whole other Elden Ring piece idea which I know is going to try to claim all my attention.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-waltz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">for waltz references.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 20]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 20 - Redraw]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Took a bit of an art break over the last two weeks while getting married. Still did some work on an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@altarstone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altar Stone</a> animation and also drew my Elden Ring character as we’re deep into the DLC.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Greyscale image of squatting Elden Ring character" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/er-blorbo1-65a23fc8cb1a747db32901afd26c26f9.jpg" width="1738" height="2215" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This week kicked off more focused practice time and I’m returning with:
1 - Focusing on a single piece for a week
2 - A childhood re-draw</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---pose">Day 1 - Pose<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20#day-1---pose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Pose" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Pose">​</a></h2>
<p>Here’s the original piece I started with.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/butterfly-princess-2006-2d794045b2691804a18f2c970e1ae35d.jpg" width="1435" height="1796" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I can’t remember any of the context for the design or composition. All I know is that this was done in pencil crayon and was likely one of my main pieces for art class when I was 17. So big into my Always Online internet years.</p>
<p>I’m following the workflow that was covered in the One Week Character program, so day 1 was mostly gathering reference, choosing a pose and getting the composition down.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---outfit">Day 2 - Outfit<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20#day-2---outfit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Outfit" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Outfit">​</a></h2>
<p>The outfit was already established in the original but I made some minor changes to the wing designs to make them more easily recognizable as Butterfly. I deleted my sketch layers so I don’t have a great image for this day. This is a screenshot of the video replay in Procreate.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-20.2-855c0d53389336441cbb12956d63bea7.jpg" width="1927" height="1798" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---colours">Day 3 - Colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20#day-3---colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Colours" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Colours">​</a></h2>
<p>I generated a palette from a monarch butterfly dress which gave me a good starting point.  I lightened the colour of the dress by a fair bit as I didn’t want to work so heavily with black while also assuming I would end up darkening everything in the shading phase.</p>
<p>I also changed the hair colour as the bright pink was just too random for me. Or at least 35 year old me.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-20.3-aa2c3bb800742568b7c4b9d7274c8d16.jpg" width="2640" height="2397" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4--5---shading-and-details">Day 4 &amp; 5 - Shading and details<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20#day-4--5---shading-and-details" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 &amp; 5 - Shading and details" title="Direct link to Day 4 &amp; 5 - Shading and details">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t take any inbetween screenshots of this process. I’ve found a trick to how I approach shading. Often I don’t go hard enough on my shadows so I figured out I could just duplicate my Multiply layer I was using and then the shadows really pop.</p>
<p>I spent a rather long time on the magic circle, trying to make it look interesting. Then went hard on the rim lighting where the body is closest to the circle. Just a fair bit of experimental choices to try to make the circle pop will not pulling in all the attention by being too bright.</p>
<p>Something that was new for me was colouring in my black lines. I painted over them with an airbrush to bring them closer to their nearest colour and I feel like this does a nice job of smoothing things out. The place with the most black lines no longer draws in a lot of attention by being a place of high contrast. I’ll try this out again in the future but maybe will commit to it harder instead of doing light airbrushing.</p>
<p>I probably could have spent time adding more details and texture to the skin and the long part of the dress. I wrapped up the piece Thursday night as I was generally happy with it and didn’t want to stress out my back muscles too much more by adding another day of fine tuning.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-20.4-4f3f3acf2b3471204cf721597a50fe14.jpg" width="2640" height="2397" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-20#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Going to make next week an anatomy week by drawing waltz poses. However I am a little worried that most references will have people in rather ornate outfits, making it difficult to see exact limb poses.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/butterfly-redraw/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">for butterfly princess</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Week Character Challenge]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/owc</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/owc</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Designing a character in a week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I took a break from my usual practice schedule to participate in <a href="https://paintable.cc/one-week-character/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paintables’s One Week Character class</a>. The students were provided with briefs to choose from and then focus on trying to work with that brief while following <a href="https://davidbelliveau.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David Belliveau’s</a> workflow. He did live videos from Monday to Friday covering each stage of the process and answering questions.</p>
<p>It’s a good workflow overall, but I struggled to tune in to the sessions so did everything a day or two behind. There was a whole Discord community for it but I found it was too busy and messy, the way I often find Discord servers to be. But it was a good experience and it helped me stay focused on one piece for a whole week and be pretty happy with the end product.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---figure-drawing-and-finding-a-pose">Day 1 - Figure drawing and finding a pose<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#day-1---figure-drawing-and-finding-a-pose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Figure drawing and finding a pose" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Figure drawing and finding a pose">​</a></h2>
<p>I wasn’t hype on any of the five briefs that were provided, even by the time day one rolled around. I found them all to be extremely basic and straightforward character wise. This made it pretty difficult to get started, so I spent a good 20 minutes scrolling Pinterest while watching the first video.</p>
<p>The first thing I decided on was ‘scythe’. They’d been on my mind since the launch of Arlecchino in Genshim Impact…</p>
<p>This led to looking for poses of people holding poles that could have a blade added to the end of them. Ended up with this reference and this base figure. By this point Fallen Angel felt like the most logical choice from the briefs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/OWC-Day1-190339e7ec14b32fb18ec3d2248e7106.jpg" width="2732" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---clothing">Day 2 - Clothing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#day-2---clothing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Clothing" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Clothing">​</a></h2>
<p>Day 2 focused on dressing the figure from day 1. I was pretty familiar with this step from last years courses and used parts of those approaches for this. Search for references and ideas then work with blocking in shapes to focus on balance on composition. I created 3 different ones during the course of the video for the day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/OWC-Day2-f525ea3e1c84f62dee50b06ad11fb922.jpg" width="3706" height="1906" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---colours">Day 3 - Colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#day-3---colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Colours" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Colours">​</a></h2>
<p>The video for day 3 started with linework so I felt behind instantly as I’m still kind of stuck in having linework for a lot of my work. This day ended up taking a fair bit of time as I did a cleanup pass on the clothing, then a true linework layer after that. And then got around to trying out colours.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/OWC-Day3-e9d82107ccc41bc7365d8cc1b1393c54.jpg" width="2826" height="3664" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---details">Day 4 - Details<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#day-4---details" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Details" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Details">​</a></h2>
<p>Another thing that made the challenge more… challenging, was that colouring details other than clothing weren’t covered until day 4. The main outfit detail I had was all the metal and honestly, I don’t have too much experience with metal. I’ve done a lot with flat greys but haven’t done a lot of shading techniques. David’s little tutorials were very helpful for how to approach these details. Choosing a reference and really focusing on it to learn a style to then apply to the parts of the character that require that. An exercise I’ll try to fit into one of my practice weeks.</p>
<p>A lot of this day was spent trying to develop how I wanted the metal to look. I don’t love it but I started with the boots and I am pretty happy with the boots. I feel like they have the right amount of details.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/OWC-Day4-6bd2e854bba927d5b03dab0c1cc34ff2.jpg" width="2826" height="3664" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---finishing-details">Day 5 - Finishing details<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#day-5---finishing-details" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Finishing details" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Finishing details">​</a></h2>
<p>The stuff focused on day 5 was a lot of the stuff that I often skip over. Usually after I accomplish the stuff from day 4 I’m feeling fairly over a piece. The big emphasis of the lessons over the week was to skip to a workflow. It helps to know which part to work on next and in which order. I found this very helpful in sticking with the piece for this long, even feeling like I was doing something different every day since each focus is a rather different creative challenge.</p>
<p>This day was re-doing the breastplate which I wasn’t happy with, finishing up any textures I wanted to add and doubling down on the shadows and highlights.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/OWC-Day5-7e566ca1a70e1a9f2ce5209c73b37db6.jpg" width="2826" height="3664" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/owc#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I wasn’t sure I was going to make it through this week. I didn’t like the community aspect, I wasn’t sure if I was going to learn anything different from the previous courses I had done, and I went to the movies when there was a chance the videos would be taken down and I wouldn’t have a chance to watch the last one. But they ended up being still available Sunday morning and I was able to get my last details in then.</p>
<p>It feels good to finish a digital piece, and to not skip on the details. A lot does really come together in those last few stages. Given that this feels like a success I’m thinking of changing up my practice schedule once again. Along with adding a week every month to focus on anatomy, I might also devote a week to completing a single piece to put my practice into place.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 19]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week's theme is chameleons, another creature I’ve always loved. But I can’t trace back my memory to any particular stand out chameleons. Not in tv, movies or books. They’ve always been weird little guys, between the colour changing, the long tongue. Maybe that’s enough to make them memorable to a kid.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.1-641858d08df869c66a763e9db98a9c34.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.2-1d36b24e7fa72dc907d396c591f2d947.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.3.1-308ff1e764732c76a30d01624fc560a6.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.3.2-592651f570b540612450fb4a64c809fd.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.4.1-09a4cb70c7235f07c6b31b105b0b1511.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://x.com/oakleybillions/status/1100854218871586816" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The blue guys are by Oakley Billions on Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/419116309047725147/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the green guys are from someone’s deleted DeviantArt page.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.4.2-31fefcd0b976e1b375251859b6c2a419.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://bigheadbonecos.wordpress.com/2011/04/19/as-incriveis-ilustracoes-de-kikariz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Illustration by Kikariz</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I’ve been trying to jot down little notes about key traits you want to capture when drawing specific creatures. While also noticing what gets changed for cartoon versions. For chameleons almost everyone changes their tiny eyes into huge eyes. A classic cutifying move but to me it loses a key chameleon trait. For my final day I did a chameleon with regular eyes and then did a copy with the cartoon style eyes. It does change of the face drastically, making it way easier to work with expressions. But I still don’t love it, the swivel eyes are so good and unique.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-19.5-f75c1f2ac5e8f94fe257d32f45fb30f3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-19#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>This might be the week with the least amount of change form day 1 to day 5... maybe I already knew chameleon's pretty well.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-chameleon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of chameleons.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 18]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week is another one pulled from old childhood art, another book cover I made featuring a crying sea turtle. I loved turtles a lot when I was a kid. Franklin was my favourite toy, I had almost every book, even dressed as Franklin for Halloween once. These turtles are not Franklin turtles though, this week is sea turtles only.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kid-seaturtle-5bca5e0fd27c740e0f8ed11244c79f2f.jpg" width="908" height="1297" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Sea turtles have a nice consistent shape to them, it makes sense, way more than hyena’s at least.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.1-29b089429b99dbac09064a77af8fd1b2.jpg" width="3072" height="1780" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I know there are other types of sea turtles out there but I ended up with a lot of either green sea turtles or hawksbills.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.2-671c7ab46f9f0d88d87cc6a97bcbd4d0.jpg" width="3072" height="1887" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Someday I’ll be willing to draw all the scales.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.3.1-4099df81e68f8b5839871cbbc1397b42.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.3.2-9f97f6e3363d45a072ddef518624e732.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.3.3-e8c97a43efaeb999a3c59c1199b7b7bf.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I was kind of surprised at how few stylized sea turtles I could find on Pinterest. Once again babies dominated and there was a lot of Disney influence going around.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.4.1-3c53c1ee7253e7e5ec6cc213e4111e23.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://creativemarket.com/An-Maler/5886337-Set-of-big-green-sea-turtle-cartoon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By Alfmaler on Creative Market</a> and <a href="https://aaronberchild.blogspot.com/2012/03/sea-turtle.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aaron Berchild on Tumblr</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.4.2-463bb22a5567cda83739042176c6fb57.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This one was fun to find because it’s someone doing a similar exercise. Various attempts at a cartoon version of a baby turtle.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/D3VmG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Donovan Valdes on ArtStation</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>A little rougher than I was hoping. The below shot with the front fins pulled in was ambitious and kind of loses its shape.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-18.5-80847e6c2df5eed9a0a67c2aa9533951.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-18#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Falling behind on blog posts, at this exact moment I already have all the art pieces completed for number 19. I also just signed up for a mini character design challenge next week so I may break from the format for a week.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-seaturtle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of sea turtles.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 17]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s time for another anatomy week. This week I went with volleyball poses. I played a lot of volleyball between the ages of ~14-18 so I’m pretty familiar with the sport, but it has been a long time since I’ve seen any volleyball in action.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t hate these sketches after doing them which is a pretty rare day 1 feeling.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.1-05ac165b67eac4564aeb96a0aedfb304.jpg" width="3072" height="2085" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>There’s plenty of volleyball photography out there, and some really good action poses since there’s a lot of quick movements during a game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.2-34b374dcbebd1a7813e366c9a67b24d8.jpg" width="3062" height="1909" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Each day feels like it's getting a little cleaner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.3-e5676cf209498e406cc29251a68b889a.jpg" width="3622" height="2207" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>People have done some really dramatic angles in their volleyball poses. I still rarely play around with perspective, especially with the anatomy weeks since I still want to get more consistent at proportions but also foreshortening.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.4.1-cadb740c218961b0ee11121a5867bcab.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/Ka26oB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xuexiang Zhang on ArtStation.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.4.2-f5bf65113d60e1565cdc53a9d5dbb19b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.ingridpamela.com/sketches" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sketches by Ingrid Pamela</a></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://twitter.com/vvvmung/status/1374725039589785607" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@vvvmung on Twitter.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t push too much outside my comfort zone with this one but I did try to do an aerial angle on one. I can now see that the head is off angle but overall it feels like a small baby step to playing with perspective more.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-17.5-13f259ce74c12decb98ca9b95c6d4abe.jpg" width="2538" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-17#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>On top of my weekly practice I also did a colour study this week. A common practice method I’ve been wanting to do more is to try from movie stills. Movies are heavily invested in lighting and composition so learning from movies you like is a good way to learn.</p>
<p>I did direct colour picks from this still from The Fall, one of my favourite movies. The whole movie is rather muted but the characters themselves often have a very vibrant colour as part of their outfit. I really like this bright red and gold outfit in this scene of beautiful stucco structures. Next time I’ll try choosing the colours manually instead of colour picking them with the eye drop tool to see if I can guess the colours because when using the eye drop I’m often surprised by how much darker or lighter a colour is once I see it on the colour wheel.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fall-colours1-622ae3457c0e052a152e3683888b302a.jpg" width="2436" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-vollyball/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Volleyball</a> Pinterest board.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 16]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I went for hyenas. They’ve always been pretty cool and feel like another “weird dog” type. But surprise surprise, I actually learned a lot about hyenas this week. First one being, they aren’t that closely related to dogs. Instead they are closer to the cat family but their closest animal relative is actually the meerkat.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I was very over confident on day 1. It disappeared as soon as I started sketching. Very much a ‘head empty’ kind of day where I feel like I did just draw some weird dogs. Can’t even say these are recognizably hyenas.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.1-b9a573e31a4f582dfe4043a2063be64a.jpg" width="2952" height="1146" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A little better with references. But already I’m feeling like this animal is a challenge. Its shapes are un-intuitive to me.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.2-652a149d422d8c7ca772aace4d41663b.jpg" width="3065" height="1849" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Now we’re starting to get somewhere.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.3.1-ae293614f7d8da56eed75523c4734088.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.3.2-3059c89665e3c3a41f96a20bf1d3717b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>One of my goals with hyenas was to avoid having only Lion King art for reference. Which actually didn’t turn out to be that hard. People love to draw hyenas, possibly because their faces are so expressive.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.4.1-b00f8557679341e36c98a4735b86250b.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://gnoll-train.tumblr.com/post/159438633778/toulouseart-hyena-doodles-i-did-a-bit-ago" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gnoll Train on Tumblr</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.4.2-92d5cdb4f880e8a4953f5683a3bcb7e4.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://x.com/frozenspoots/status/1235886581107568640" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By FrozenSpoots on Twitter</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.4.3-08bef3a642b3866417fbf9cb3b63e234.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://i0.wp.com/pbs.twimg.com/media/Ef0CtsUWkAcmyB4.jpg:large?ssl=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Things you don’t know when using Pinterest as your main search. This image seems to only exist on a Beaststars compilation fan art page that’s tagged as pornography.</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>My girlfriend says the large face here brings furry energy, which probably isn’t wrong.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-16.5-1a6f0799d1ac506abacd483f178398f3.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-16#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>The fun facts about hyena’s I learned came from this <a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/598978819224783588/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anatomy study by BitterSweetDisease on Deviantart</a>. However I’m not the first person to go searching for their account. I found a forum of someone else trying to find their original stuff saying the account has been deactivated. Which is unfortunate because the pieces that have made it to Pinterest are well done.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-hyena/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest Hyena board</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 15]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m two weeks behind on blog posts so I’m gonna keep these two rather short to get them out. This week was another childhood animal revisit: Penguins.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kid-penguin-32af8256922f836c78ec9b50541e9988.jpg" width="840" height="1325" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Penguins were honestly pretty easy from the get go. They have a pretty iconic yet simple shape. However, non of these day one guys are any specific species of penguin and are more just my mental model for what a penguin is.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.1-9c7a26c6035a901c5ff3976abe0a1d6e.jpg" width="3011" height="1825" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>I did struggle with movement on day 1. Other than walk around, stand around, and swim, what to penguins do? I had forgotten about how more active they could look when moving about.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.2-b00d6d8e2a90d9df733844ce7f6b0849.jpg" width="2918" height="1824" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>By this day I’m starting to wonder if I should have chosen a specific species to focus on as there is a fair bit of variety between different penguins.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.3.1-f7304a7eba277bec2f6abaf63e4175f9.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.3.2-8c0b6b61b628d6e88516a2b43a54b449.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.3.3-5217effe2ba80bacd569c7a9934c3639.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I made a mistake here in that a lot of the styled images are baby penguins. Very cute but I hadn’t meant for that to become the focus.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.4.1-e885c100d442549b98d7734cf9244b88.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.animatetimes.com/news/img.php?id=1535357662&amp;p=1&amp;n=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Concept art from Penguin Highway, automated English translation</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.4.2-e5c635710f089c6ffcf322f5979acb48.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: This is a screenshot from the anime Mawaru Penguindrum</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.4.3-c5e3941810f376dcdb0207f31d27e8b1.jpg" width="2816" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sheba.drawing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By Sheba</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>This is one of the first times where I feel like there is almost zero change from day 1 to day 5. Partially due to the lack of pose options and partially because I really rushed through this day 5. I’m not sure if I should force myself to get day 5 done in a sloppy way or if not even doing it is better as I’m unlikely to learn anything if I just force something on paper without giving it conscious thought.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-15.5-a247e8e4c4339db9b7a361a6104fb1e3.jpg" width="3054" height="1877" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-15#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/maeanu3639/wap-penguin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinterest Penguin board</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>