<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kymira Blog</title>
        <link>https://kymira.ca/blog</link>
        <description>Kymira Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateweaver Milestone - Fate Cards v1]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/fate-cards-v1</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/fate-cards-v1</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A review of the first version of 20 Fate Cards]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We've been hard at work on the Fateweaver prototype as a funding opportunity looms ahead of us in August.</p>
<p>Sophie's been implementing the ruleset we came up with months ago while adding animation and design in Godot. I've been creating the main art assets that we'll need to make the game playable but also have some of it's final style. I'm happy I spent so much time trying out different styles because it gave me time to really get better at the one we went with, woodcuts.</p>
<p>With a few social plans cancelled for the weekend, I was able to get my last remaining cards done this weekend and declare version one of the Fate Cards ready to go.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fate-cards">Fate Cards<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fate-cards-v1#fate-cards" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fate Cards" title="Direct link to Fate Cards">​</a></h2>
<p>I did a first reveal of 3 cards <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wtchcrft.com/post/3ltutqgii7225" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15 days ago</a>. Looks like I averaged about 1 card a day with that timeline. Faster than I had planned! The first few cards were slow going but as I got used to the brushes I had to work with things started to go rather smoothly. Here's a big spread of all of them.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fc-all-tall-8c65f7fdcabe1c47c900225364a87eea.jpg" width="3750" height="5000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>There's no name or text on the cards because we printing the text all in-engine.</p>
<p>I'm fairly pleased with how most of these turned out. A few needed touch-ups once seen in the game and I think there are a few I might continue to tinker with when I get fed up with seeing things I want to change after many game playthroughs. The owl (Night) and squirrel (thief) are on watch for being too cute. While a few others already took multiple takes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fc-river-85f4e0f2d8eab068c0f8acc008ba1ed9.jpg" width="1500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This river card took much longer than I thought. It was one of my early exploration cards and I felt pretty confident about drawing a simple river. But the thing about woodcuts is that the style isn't often used to depict landscapes. So my original ideas for the composition really struggled due to having too much empty space. I still don't love it but I do love the fish.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fc-scales-6c296d893ef5b95218fcdea77cf2bd83.jpg" width="1500" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I re-did the snake here multiple times because I couldn't find a way to do scales that didn't look one, too busy, and two, too simple. I knew I didn't want to draw every individual scale but I still wanted to imply enough scales so that it wasn't just a worm.</p>
<p>Sophie was building out the functionality of all the cards while I was drawing them so they've already nearly all been implemented in-game. Which brings us pretty close to being rules complete! Next up is 10 items that the player can acquire. Which will also be my next art tasks.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-character">First character<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fate-cards-v1#first-character" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First character" title="Direct link to First character">​</a></h2>
<p>When it was too hot to sit at my art desk I did some dabbling and research into character design. We don't have all our characters plotted out yet but there are a few early ones figured out.</p>
<p>While the cards took a decent amount of exploration and experimentation, I'm still more afraid of doing the full body characters. I'm still happy with the characters I did for Spellphage but I want this set of characters to be sharper and more designed than those. A full on level up.</p>
<p>I have created more completed art this year than probably any other year before, but it's been for fairly specific things. Backgrounds, character sprites, small assets, all these cards. Very few pieces have been fully rendered characters.</p>
<p>If we get the grant we're applying for there's a good chance we'd try to commission characters from another artists. It would free me up to learn more Godot and work on the supporting assets. But I would love to be able to pull it off, I just know that I should really take my time with each character. Ideally 1-2 weeks would probably be enough time to achieve something I'm happy with but with a minimal 8 characters = 8 * 2 = 16 weeks aka 4 months...</p>
<p>4 months isn't the worst given our timeline. We haven't started writing the story or tying the characters into the world, that will take a few months right there. So if I start characters in August my calendar would be full till December. Could still aim for a February early access release...</p>
<p>Suffice to say this and future blog posts will probably have spoilers in it. But since the story won't be out for months I'm pretty sure most people will forget some early spoilers.</p>
<p>A lot to think about! What I really wanted to show was how even with all the drawing I've been doing I'm still producing some pretty ugly stuff between the good stuff.</p>
<p>We're thinking about tying certain cards to certain characters (which will be easier now that the cards are done) which led me to an idea for the Warden card. I thought we could have a mysterious warden character who, upon a first meeting or two, is covering their eye. Either out of injury or exhaustion. And then would later reveal that under there hand is the stylized eye from the warden card.</p>
<p>I tried to pull off a 3/4rds face with arm up a few times one evening. Everything was coming out bad. I kept trying and they even all came out looking the same? Close the iPad, went to bed. The next day I chopped up a few "close enough" references and took another shot at it. And instantly got something I was actually happy with.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/warden-evolution-b33eecc7bc046cfef751cd81bce890c5.jpg" width="3270" height="2506" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Sometimes it really is a matter of getting the bad attempts out to be warmed up enough to get the drawing you want.</p>
<p>I don't know what rendering style we want to go with yet so I'm keeping this character in basic greyscale as a general placeholder for where characters can appear in game.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fate-cards-v1#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Big strides with Fateweaver this week (the last 3 weeks really). I have some small bits of studio business to look after in the next few days and some family commitments so I think it will be a low art week coming up. August will be about characters, getting ready for <a href="https://www.qgcon.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">QGCon</a>, and submitting a grant application. With a little cabin trip in the middle as a mini forced vacation so that my wife and I step away from our own to-do lists for a few days.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Additional Summer Learning]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Summarizing some recent classes, courses, and tutorials.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While a lot of my time has been on studio stuff and Fateweaver assets these last few months, I’m still squeezing in some additional learnings. Not all of them art related. So this is a grab bag of random things kind of blog post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="spencer-drafting-for-animation-class">Spencer drafting for animation class<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025#spencer-drafting-for-animation-class" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Spencer drafting for animation class" title="Direct link to Spencer drafting for animation class">​</a></h2>
<p>I attended the yearly <a href="https://spencerwan.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spencer Wan</a> animation class last month. This one focused on draftmanship for animation, which is basically how to draw figures quickly because you need to draw so much for animation.</p>
<p>It’s a pretty different concept from his last class, which was on 2D visual effect animation. Here he went over some of the traditional draftmanship approaches, their pros and cons and what he thinks is best. I don’t see myself doing any fully body character animations any time soon but all the tips applied to more general things like gesture studies and capturing dynamic poses. It’s also just cool to learn about how there are identified approaches to these kinds of things. Lots of people acting like online educators don’t know the terms or background to these established practices.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/draftmanship-p1-24a4a2f4b7a893ac6f4e7254a7280a5d.jpg" width="2514" height="1300" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/draftmanship-p2-fb6dd7327658b219c16519df4a99980d.jpg" width="3400" height="1300" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/draftmanship-p3-9edc907e9d62ef2ec7439eada7eb7da2.jpg" width="2290" height="1431" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The class then ended on a talk about “confidence” which was really good. Spencer’s point with it was that feedback that other artists will give you is “to be confident” to “have more confident lines” and he found this really vague and unhelpful because no one tells you how to get that confidence.</p>
<p>My page of his suggested exercises for learning confidence turned into this weird scribble mess which I didn’t remember at all when I opened the file to export these images.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/draftmanship-p5-603f5374529b10fab1ee729b6712555a.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gdquest">GDQuest<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025#gdquest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to GDQuest" title="Direct link to GDQuest">​</a></h2>
<p>When we decided to make a game with more traditional game play to it we needed to choose and engine. Even while I work at Unity I have a huge soft spot for Godot…</p>
<p>My experience using the Unity Editor is crashes and long wait times. I know it’s a good engine and has a huge amount of built in features that speed up a lot of development. But I’m working on a MacBook Air, we’re being tight with our money, I don’t want to invest in a new computer just to run Unity. We also shouldn’t need a lot of the things that Unity has built in. We’re going for a 2D game so we don’t even need 3D support. So that’s how we ended up with Godot.</p>
<p>My wife hadn’t used it before so she bought the <a href="https://school.gdquest.com/products/learn_2d_gamedev_godot_4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn 2D Gamedev from Zero with Godot 4</a> and started learning. I watched her progress through the lessons and thought it would be a good idea for me to take the course as well.</p>
<p>While watching a talk by a game developer from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_Twin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Motion Twin</a> I learned that the studio is a worker cooperative that has a really interesting approach to development. Everyone there is comfortable in-engine, if someone gets an idea for a feature or level instead of having to pitch it and win people over to their idea and wait for an engineer to build it, they just build it themselves. I love the idea of being able to be more hands on in-engine but this takes the idea to the extreme. I hope to be comfortable enough to contribute code to our games but I think it will be a while yet.</p>
<p>The GDQuest course is really well done and I feel like I’m learning a lot, even just on chapter 4. It’s just difficult to squeeze it in while also working on art assets, learning how to run a studio, and all the things that come along with that.</p>
<p>But! I won’t learn unless I keep plugging away at it. They suggest trying to do 30 minutes every day and I’ve been failing on that front :| Hoping to do little blog updates on my progress to help motivate me to keep going. There’s a lot at the start of the course on how to get the most out of it and the earliest homework is answering these 6 questions:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why do you want to learn to code? What's your goal?</strong> : Make game + contribute to game</li>
<li><strong>What will you get when you reach your goal?</strong> : A game, be helpful with Godot</li>
<li><strong>Where and at what time will you practice?</strong> Some time between noon-9 everyday (oops)</li>
<li><strong>For how long will you practice?</strong> 30 minutes minimum (oops)</li>
<li><strong>How will you avoid distractions?</strong> Close apps that send notifications, tell Sophie I’m in focus time</li>
<li><strong>How will you stay accountable?</strong> Post to BlueSky / Write blog posts / Show Sophie
I did manage to complete every lesson in the <a href="https://gdquest.itch.io/learn-godot-gdscript" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn GDScript From Zero</a> which did take many hours. But it also felt like a very good start. Now it’s time to get back in engine.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="game-juice">Game Juice<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025#game-juice" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Game Juice" title="Direct link to Game Juice">​</a></h2>
<p>I haven’t started this one yet but one of the things I’m most interested in learning in Godot is to do small effects and visuals. A day into my GDQuest course I bought <a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/learn-how-to-make-a-game-juicy-in-godot-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn how to make a juicy game in Godot 4</a> as what I get to start as a reward to finishing the full GDQuest. It was on sale for like 80% off so I bought it earlier than I would have.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fateweaver-updates">Fateweaver updates<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025#fateweaver-updates" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fateweaver updates" title="Direct link to Fateweaver updates">​</a></h2>
<p>Development on Fateweaver is swimming along. Sophie has nearly implemented all the playing cards now. Next up will be Fate Cards then Items and then we’ll likely be ready to put it in people's hands.</p>
<p>I’ve been working on a pitchdeck which is required to apply for an upcoming grant. Since pitchdecks are so art heavy I’ve been trying to get at least a few assets ready for that. Which has lead to:</p>
<p>Card backs for Landscape Tiles and Journey Cards:
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/journey-cardback-f53ccc3e4c10566ba679b2c1532d7ea8.png" width="1024" height="1536" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>A decent amount of Fate Cards:
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fc-group2-0ad419442b200f35d6b357e1fbb4e228.jpg" width="6200" height="2500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>My first attempt at one of the characters the player will meet:
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ch-warden-wip-1142e71f077f95442f4e9334c531ce85.png" width="1258" height="2972" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/summer-learning-2025#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>If you’re someone who happens to be awake late at night, check out the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hard-drive.net/post/3lub7iol2r22n" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hard Drive’s Wheel of Woke And Gay Charity Stream</a> happening from 8PM ET on July 25th and goes until 8PM the next day. From 10PM to 1AM they’ll be spinning the Wheel of Woke, a collection of games deemed woke and gay from LGBTQ+ creators and Love in the Time of Spellphage is on the wheel!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/littos-wheelofwoke-3175e988cefe96b684391d407c613520.png" width="354" height="108" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Not sure what my next blog post will be about yet, feels like there’s a lot of projects on the go.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
            <category>godot</category>
            <category>animation</category>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Living our (studio) values]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Early explorations into studio values and how values look in practice.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Companies have values. Studios are companies and thus studios have values.</p>
<p>They at least say they have values, they state them. But it’s pretty hard to tell if they actually live them or believe in them.</p>
<p>As part of the <a href="https://babyghosts.fund/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Baby Ghost</a> program we’ve been thinking about company values a lot. Because I like to process my thoughts by writing, I’m going to do some brain dumping about how we’ve approached the exercises, what values we’ve landed on, and how to make our values explicit through our actions.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="finding-our-values-as-a-studio---first-draft">Finding our values as a studio - first draft<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#finding-our-values-as-a-studio---first-draft" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Finding our values as a studio - first draft" title="Direct link to Finding our values as a studio - first draft">​</a></h2>
<p>I like to start all my homework with a bit of research. So when given the assignment of brainstorming our values I first searched for lists of other company values.</p>
<p>All the places I’ve worked have had values, very few of those places took them seriously. So starting this assignment feels a bit like “choose the values you’ll eventually fail to live up to”. But that’s not approaching the assignment in good faith or with optimism. There’s nothing wrong with planning for success.</p>
<p>A piece of advice we got was to “go wild” with our values, even if they seem weird or difficult or extreme.</p>
<p>But it was still a struggle to think about “what values should our studio be built on”, probably because I don’t often think of my actions as “what is an action that serves this value”.</p>
<p>What eventually clicked and helped make the exercise easier was remembering that I’m a person of pretty strong values and that the studio could also be a thing of strong values.</p>
<p>I have a lot of ethical choices I make in life that sacrifice convenience because to me it’s The Right Thing To Do. Hell, in our wedding vows I wrote “I promise to keep striving with you to live a better life, to live by our morals…”. Which helped frame studio values as “things that aren’t easy but are important”. Which eventually helped to lead us to our tree of values:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="An image of an oak tree with a root system below. There are circles all over the image which contain value keywords." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/values-tree-1daa589acf6c297139e4f3bd910cdb3a.png" width="952" height="998" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="top-3">Top 3<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#top-3" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Top 3" title="Direct link to Top 3">​</a></h2>
<p>It feels like most companies choose a few key values that they eventually put on a website. Our assignment sheet also started with room for 3 so we ran with that lol.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sustainability</li>
<li>Sincerity</li>
<li>Awareness</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ll elaborate more on these another time or on our website. Whichever comes first. What I wanted to focus on today was how our values shape our actions, or really, how our already existing actions helped shape our value choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="actions-that-support-our-values">Actions that support our values<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#actions-that-support-our-values" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Actions that support our values" title="Direct link to Actions that support our values">​</a></h2>
<p>Awareness is the value I wanted to highlight today. We break awareness down into a few more granular things to specifically be aware of:</p>
<ul>
<li>Our ethics &amp; social responsibility</li>
<li>Community engagement</li>
<li>Data-driven decision making (being aware of markets, trends, what consumers are interested in)</li>
</ul>
<p>Ethics &amp; social responsibility is probably the largest sub-group and one that strongly shapes the foundation of the studio early. For us a big part of this means avoiding Big Silicon Valley tech and US companies as much as we can.</p>
<p>We’ve both worked for tech companies of varying degrees of evil over the last 10 years. In the last year the US has basically threatened to invade our country. Big Tech spends a lot of money on US elections. Big Tech also supports on-going wars and genocides. Big Tech absolutely wants to take advantage of your attention, your data, and your money. There’s a lot of reasons to try to avoid them.</p>
<p>This is not convenient (we spend a lot of time looking for alternative tools and paying money for tools that could otherwise be free (at the cost of your data)) but it is important to us.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="alternatives">Alternatives<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#alternatives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Alternatives" title="Direct link to Alternatives">​</a></h2>
<p>These aren’t exclusively game or studio alternatives to tools but they are alternatives to exploitative tools. They can be hard to find and evaluate so I wanted to make a list in case anyone else is looking to make some switches.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="music">Music<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#music" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Music" title="Direct link to Music">​</a></h3>
<p>The alternatives to Spotify are growing! It’s a good time to switch! We ended up going with <a href="https://www.qobuz.com/ca-en/discover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Qobuz</a>. It has apps for Apple and Android, lets you buy content through the app and has actual music journalism going on within the app. Write ups and reviews by people who know music.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="analytics">Analytics<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#analytics" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Analytics" title="Direct link to Analytics">​</a></h3>
<p>I recently added analytics to my blog because I’ve started sharing it beyond my little circle of friends. I haven’t tracked anything beforehand and I was curious if there was something simple I could do to just track page views. And there was!</p>
<p>This alternative to Google Analytics popped up very quickly on a search: <a href="https://www.simpleanalytics.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simple Analytics</a>. Based in Europe they’re following the bigger privacy focused laws like GDPR. They also have a nice free tier which will fit my needs for many years. Basically I’m just getting the number of page views, number of unique visitors, and which country they’re from. While it’s very minimal, most blocking extensions will still stop this data collection. I use Ghostery on one browser so I don’t even track my own visits there lol. We’ll eventually add Simple Analytics to our studio website.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="search-engines">Search engines<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#search-engines" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Search engines" title="Direct link to Search engines">​</a></h3>
<p>Tired of the constant enshitification of Google, we are paying users of <a href="https://kagi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kagi</a>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="newsletters">Newsletters<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#newsletters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Newsletters" title="Direct link to Newsletters">​</a></h3>
<p>This one took a lot of investigation. Mostly because I was hoping to find an alternative to Substack which is more precise than just “newsletters”. Newsletters are tricky because by law you need to include an address (often a business address). We aren’t comfortable putting our home address out into the internet like that. Substack gets around this by letting users default to using the Substack address.</p>
<p>To get around putting our personal address on newsletters we’ll eventually pay for a business address or PO box to avoid doxing ourselves. And once that’s done we’ll likely go with <a href="https://www.cakemail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cakemail</a> as they’re an established Canadian service.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="docs">Docs<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#docs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Docs" title="Direct link to Docs">​</a></h3>
<p>Probably the fastest growing Google alternative. <a href="https://proton.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proton</a> offers mail, calendar, docs, and more. I’m someone who’s lived in the Google ecosystem for decades now. Mostly because it’s the only tool I use. I don’t need anything fancy, I just want web based documents. So now I’m early into my Proton evaluation to see if it can fully replace Google as my go-to.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="project-management">Project management<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#project-management" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Project management" title="Direct link to Project management">​</a></h3>
<p>We don’t require much for project management or brainstorming right now. We both keep paper to-do lists and just do the work that needs to be done. We don’t have task tracking because every few hours we’re showing each other our progress. The to-do list for programming is implementing the pages of game rules we have. The only tracking we currently have is my festivals/opporunities list of things to apply to.</p>
<p>We’ve kept things very simple and will be trying to keep things simple for as long as we can. If there's one thing I've learned from Knowledge Management school it's to be very careful with your tools and practices, the tools you use will shape how you approach work. They'll also make it harder to change due to classics like sunk cost fallacy.</p>
<p>I’ve already set a standard for being a journaling minimalist through my <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/microjournaling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1-page per year journaling method I call microjournaling</a>. This while also blogging every few weeks for over 2 years... The real key to documentation is being able to tell what's important, an absolutely herculean task. But when it comes you how you work, you can learn what's important to you and build from there. Which is how I ended up with my tiny journaling method. A way for me to set priorities while avoiding feeling overwhelmed. Possibly some big changes ahead for me as I consider adding another page just for studio and game things!</p>
<p>Over time we'll figure out what's important for collaboration and for how we make games. Brining on a 3rd person will absolutely revolutionize our approach as we learn what works for them. Eventually, and also hopefully, we’ll one day grow to needing something else to manage projects, and for that we’re looking at <a href="https://www.zenhub.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zenhub</a> to stay closely linked to GitHub. Our main point of collaboration.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/studio-values#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>There of course will always be this:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/improve-society-5e0f944b5516bad025568045ef0d16d2.png" width="1942" height="1038" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>There are lots of things we won’t find good alternatives to. We’re going to keep using GitHub, we’re going to post on social media sites because that’s where the people are, etc, etc. But in the places where we can find alternatives that keep us working we’ll continue to prioritize them. We’re still early into our studio and everything is still baby steps for us. But we want it to be baby steps in the right direction.</p>
<p>If anyone has non-American tool recommendations that you’re really happy with, I’d love to hear about them!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>video games</category>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Early concept art exploration for Fateweaver]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Some of the art styles we’ve experimented with for our next game so far.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From marketing our existing games to more early concept work for our new game.</p>
<p>Since our existing games were done for game jams they didn’t really have much of a development cycle, you kind of jump straight into production for game jams. I remember very clearly sitting down on January 1st and getting started on character sprites for Spellphage with very little preparation. I had made Pinterest boards for a few of them, maybe did a few messy sketchy Lauren attempts, but that was it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Line up of Littos characters." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/swak-characters-lineup-c8f84028f9fdd8081271f85d04119aed.jpg" width="2800" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>For Fate Weaver we’re giving ourselves way more than a month. We still want to keep development tight but we are still aiming to have a playable demo out before the end of the year. This feels like a luxurious amount of time at the moment but I know it’s going to feel like nothing soon.</p>
<p>This does mean that I still need to be smart about the art style we go with. For an MVP of a demo we’ll still need 20 Fate Cards, 5 Land cards, 10 items, and hopefully 2 characters. It’s still a decently large amount of assets so I want to choose a style that’s not too difficult to pull off consistently.</p>
<p>So I’ve been experimenting.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-draft">First draft<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art#first-draft" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First draft" title="Direct link to First draft">​</a></h2>
<p>I did some early Pinteresting boarding to gather some classic tarot card designs and also some more modern takes from different artists. There are some really beautiful tarot re-makes out there, almost to the point of having too much reference material. So I tried to not browse for too long as it was starting to feel like an un-ending tunnel of great art.</p>
<p>After collecting some inspiration I started to do some sketches and then some inks to try out some looks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Paper versions of early Fate Cards." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fatespinner-v1-460b7132819edcd88b1e7a2315adac76.jpg" width="2268" height="3070" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I ended up really liking it when there was a “frame” to the image, almost creating the look of a gate or a portal. We entertained the idea for a while because it also led to the possibility of the player going “into” the cards.</p>
<p>These sat for a while as we continued to develop the cards. During that time my wife mentioned having the game be all pixel art so I wanted to give that a try. So I started exploring that. Also entertained the idea of doing 1 bit, just white and black. Then she suggested a woodcut/woodblock visual. So I added that to the list.</p>
<p>I still wanted to try basic digital art with similar soft tones from traditional tarot card art. So I tried out all 4 ideas… twice…</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="digital-approaches">Digital approaches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art#digital-approaches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Digital approaches" title="Direct link to Digital approaches">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Weeping woman test cards." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/style-test-seer-c88549c3d4ea8e556524c91987f29ab0.JPG" width="8024" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Classic flat colours, black &amp; white, woodcut, and pixel.</p>
<p>I got the idea for this image for the seer card weeks ago. Before we cut the card from the deck… but I still wanted to draw it and since it was for testing styles it doesn’t feel like a waste. I just really like the idea of tears streaming down into a puddle with eyes in the puddle.</p>
<p>I did really like the pixel version of this one, but I did work way too small as the eyes are barely legible. I wanted to keep things small because after watching multiple videos on pixel art tips it kind of feels like “what? Are you some kind of chump that needs more than 32 by 32 pixels?”. The flats and black &amp; white feel too plain to me, like they would need a lot of detailing to look more professional. Woodcut started to pull ahead.</p>
<p>So I did it again, this time for the card The Depths. A card which can stop you from leaving a Mist space.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="The Depths test cards." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/style-test-depths-9970ef6d74910806aed641665cfa3452.JPG" width="8024" height="2887" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Once again the pixel version is just too small, way too difficult to depict something as detailed as multiple hands. I do like the colour one here, even if the colours are a little muddy in this test version. The woodcut does stand out again though, but I’m not sure how I would try to portray an underwater gradient without colour. So that would be a challenge if I want to try to go that detailed.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="making-a-card">Making a card<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art#making-a-card" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making a card" title="Direct link to Making a card">​</a></h2>
<p>Woodcut style started to pull ahead. It was time to see how the style would look when trying to make a more polished version.</p>
<p>Having done all the tests on my iPad I did swap over to CSP and my tablet as it makes things feel more serious. And I wanted to try out a few brushes I thought could make the woodcut style faster and more decorative. I chose a card with an idea design, The Tempest, and experimented a bit.</p>
<video controls="" width="350"><source src="/tempest-wip-video.mp4"></video>
<p>When I started working on things I was worried that my lines were way too big. Seeing it online after it became clear that these brushes were much too small and instead they just look kind of blurry so I think I’ll do another pass but with the brush size cranked up.</p>
<p>Once I finished this Tempest attempt I wanted to see if I could animate a card in Godot because it would be really fun to do some drip marketing with animated card reveals. I hadn’t touched any of the 3D stuff in Godot before but I thought it’s gotta be easy to just spin a 3D object around an axis.</p>
<p>I created a Node3D, gave it a Sprite, then gave it a second Sprite. One sprite for the front of the card and one for the back. This is probably, absolutely, not the best way to do this. I had to resize the back of the card because it was made weeks ago at a ratio I don’t remember. Then I created an animation to spin the parent node and recorded it with OBS.</p>
<video controls="" width="650"><source src="/tempest-spin.mov"></video>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fateweaver-concept-art#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>All art is still very experimental right now, nothing is in its final form. We’re still searching for the style that we think will fit the vibe and the story of the game best. Since we have the time it’s been nice to be able to not just have to take the first idea you have and run with it.</p>
<p>Ideally we can have at least decently presentable, if not final, assets for our first playable. One of our previous collaborators as mentioned his interest to make another game with us so we may even be able to tackle this with 2 artists which would be a nice multiplier for a game 🤔</p>
<p>I expect to make more art iteration posts before launch! But for the next few weeks I want to spend time learning and testing out 2D effects in Godot to see what kind of visuals we can add to cards. So another use for my early card prototypes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>video games</category>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A beginners journey through indie marketing]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Learning to market your indie game while you market your indie game.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From game design to game marketing. A near fully entwined pair. With the amount of games published year over year, marketing has become less optional than ever.</p>
<p>So I’ve been learning how to market.</p>
<p>I can’t say I love it, nor can I say it feels like a science. Modern marketing feels like Tweeting to zero followers and hoping someone stumbles by.</p>
<p>But I’ve been spending time in marketing places and trying to learn from those who don’t see it as a nebulous black box.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-market-a-game">How to Market a Game<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#how-to-market-a-game" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How to Market a Game" title="Direct link to How to Market a Game">​</a></h2>
<p>If you search for anything concerning marketing a video game you’re going to quickly come across Chris Zukowski. Over the last few years he’s become the expert on marketing video games and Steam trends. If you see people doing videos on YouTube about what genres of games to make and which ones to avoid, they are likely pulling from the work that Chris has done.</p>
<p>He has a website where he blogs regularly, he runs a Masterclass to get you marketing faster, he runs an active Discord, and he really seems to constantly be doing talks all over the place.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/howtomarketagame-d9ed7d7da3ab23d46789c23b4ec6b495.png" width="2502" height="936" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The thing I really like about Chris’s content is that he gives the vibe that he really wants people to succeed with their game. He shares so much data, making it publicly available, saving individual marketers and researchers so much time.</p>
<p>It’s been really interesting to watch his talks going back a few years and into the present as it’s really helped make it clear that while there are trends there are also some strong consistencies too. Like rogue-like deck builders really look like they’ll continue to sell if they’re done well, and that a good Steam page is probably better than any cost-free marketing you might be doing.</p>
<p>The HTMAG Discord feels a little more intense than a lot of Chris’s talks. People there are trying to figure out the best platforms and pricing and techniques for paid ads and that’s something I struggle to wrap my head around. There’s so much data and tracking. As someone who hates being advertised too it also takes a little bit of reflection to consider what it would mean to run paid ads. Especially when understanding that visibility is so precious and this is a way to reach people you likely never could on your own.</p>
<p>I don’t feel prepared technically or knowledge-wise for running paid ads. Maybe if we had a game that felt like it had proof of market and mass appeal, but it's risky with smaller, more artsy games.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="itchio">Itch.io<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#itchio" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Itch.io" title="Direct link to Itch.io">​</a></h2>
<p>So what I’ve written so far has been very Steam focused.</p>
<p>But what about Itch.io?</p>
<p>We first launched our games on Itch because that was where the game jams were happening and because it’s also just way easier than going through all the steps that Steam requires. Steam can honestly take multiple days to set up before even submitting it for review to get permission to go public.</p>
<p>There is less shared knowledge out there about marketing for Itch. Some things seem to be the opposite from Steam: On Itch you want to use the underused tags so that you are more likely to surface in less over populated spaces. While on Steam you want to have common tags so that popular games show up in your “Similar to” section on your games page. Wishlists are everything on Steam while people adding your game to their Collection doesn’t really seem to bring any tangible benefit to you.</p>
<p>We have stumbled upon one good trick for increasing views, giving your game a price but have it on sale as free, this will place you instantly into a smaller cohort of games. Our daily views took off after this, having made no other changes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/itch-views-post-free-sale-5ea6739ebdbf56d069c597e11ff09bb5.png" width="1717" height="610" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I was expecting it to drop off after that first peak but it really seems to be at a new regular level for a while. Not sure how long it can last but it was super interesting to see the instant impact of the change.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-marketing-we-did">What marketing we did<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#what-marketing-we-did" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What marketing we did" title="Direct link to What marketing we did">​</a></h2>
<p>With Spellphage as our first game and our first real dip into the world of game publishing we went into marketing fresh faced and bleary eyed from having spent the last month game jamming.</p>
<p>We watched one or two Chris talks and then got to it. We aren’t people with big online social followings, hell, my wife works hard to exist on the internet as little as possible. And with the fall of Twitter I lost a lot of old connections. So we were kind of starting from zero.</p>
<p>We didn’t even have our studio website or studio Blueky account yet. So our reach was limited.</p>
<p>A lot of our early promotions were to our friends. Then we expanded to the visual novel Discord server that was hosting the original game jam that started us on this journey. I wrote some BlueSky posts once we had our first day of the story finished. Then made a Tumblr as we heard that it had a more active visual novel audience.</p>
<p>None of this really got us... anything substantial.</p>
<p>So we kicked it up a small notch and my wife started posting in subreddits that accept promotion posts. These did lead to some traction and we were able to see from the Itch incoming links that a lot of our views came from Reddit.</p>
<p>As Escape from Precinct 27 approached completion we had set up our website and our BlueSky. These were still places with no traffic so they weren’t going to help us reach people but it did mean I felt more comfortable talking exclusively about our games with every post.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wtchcrft-bluesky-c7c282d87ae00f09cc36dc6cdcf187d7.png" width="1230" height="846" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>But other than that nothing had really changed, we went through the same cycle of BlueSky, Reddit and Tumblr posts about the game. Reddit once again being the obvious winner. But then something interesting happened. We got 2 unsolicited YouTube streams. One a silent playthrough and one which was live streamed with a full read through.</p>
<p>I’ll admit, I thought this was it, I thought 2 unprompted streamers was a sign that we were entering a new level.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-IuUTgx7CE0?si=gwEHqNj9tceIIXqN" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>This didn’t turn out to be true. We got a few extra views, befriended a streamer who we sent keys to share with his viewers. But Precinct didn’t end up taking off that much more than Spellphage. A reminder that you really need to be hustling on the promotion front. But an interesting thing that it did confirm was Chris Zukowski’s consistent messaging that “marketing starts the moment you chose your genre”.</p>
<p>I’m one hundred percent sure that we only got videos for Precinct 27 because it’s marketed as a horror game. Horror is so popular that there are way more streamers interested in it. So much so that the one who played ours seems to just grab newly launched games on Itch tagged horror nearly every day. So the choice to make a horror game opened doors that were never available to Spellphage.</p>
<p>All this promotion was done before we got our Steam page for Spellphage. Which is honestly, a pretty big game changer.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="steam">Steam<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#steam" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Steam" title="Direct link to Steam">​</a></h2>
<p>Now Steam is a whole other beast. As I said at the start, a lot of our learning came from the How to Market a Game material and this is focused on marketing for Steam. It’s the largest video game storefront and it offers up a huge amount of data to analyze and dissect.</p>
<p>All our marketing is now focused on getting Wishlists on Steam. So much prediction around success and failure is calculated on how many wishlists you can get before you launch. Certain amounts of wishlists and wishlist speed is also what allows you to get more promotion on Steam itself.</p>
<p>But getting our game on Steam has opened another new marketing door: Steam Festivals. Which brings me to another big take away from the HTMAG Discord: The Spreadsheet.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-spreadsheet">The Spreadsheet<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#the-spreadsheet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Spreadsheet" title="Direct link to The Spreadsheet">​</a></h3>
<p>I don’t think anyone else is calling this spreadsheet <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1NGseGNHv6Tth5e_yuRWzeVczQkzqXXGF4k16IsvyiTE/edit?gid=0#gid=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Spreadsheet</a>, but it feels so valuable to me. The spreadsheet is a collection of game festivals, their submission window and a few other notes on the event. This is geared towards festivals that have been judged “worthy” so none that should be a complete waste of time for anyone.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/festival-spreadsheet-27313ae340d36e3c770a74d9408a96fc.png" width="2340" height="716" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This is a big spreadsheet and I like the way it’s been made to have lines change colour based on approaching deadlines and open submissions, making it super easy to quickly scroll through. I was able to find 3 festivals that felt like Love in the Time of Spellphage would fit into and apply to them within just a few hours. I likely never would have heard about these festivals otherwise. Highly recommend.</p>
<p>I now have my own spreadsheet of festivals that fit our games and multiple Google forms that I need to fill out.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/event-apps-2025-e0886f45a1efca23e08caff2cc3d585c.png" width="2330" height="734" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The only reason we got our Steam page out recently was because there was a festival coming up that seemed perfect for Spellphage. The deadline was soon though, we had only 13 days to get our Steam page up to be able to submit to even be considered.</p>
<p>You might be unsurprised to hear that a lot of game development (including marketing) involves crunching. I wouldn’t say that we fully crunched on getting the Steam page out (Work after 10pm? I could never!) but it was an intense focus for a weekend. If it wasn’t for the festival deadline, we probably would have put off the Steam page for a few more weeks. We had the same thing happen to our website. When applying for QGCon I wanted to have a website for organizers to see when reviewing our application. So I pushed working on the website for that application deadline.</p>
<p>It’s a strange way to progress, jumping from one external deadline to the next. But we’ve been lucky so far. None of these deadlines have overlapped. We were lucky enough to be able to shift our focus to the newest deadline without compromising our other goals. Some people might hate it, but honestly I love working towards a deadline, at least realistic ones.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="other-resources">Other resources<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#other-resources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Other resources" title="Direct link to Other resources">​</a></h2>
<p>So while How to Market a Game videos have dominated my research time, there have been a few other talks that got my attention and got me thinking about marketing in different ways.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@indiegamemarketingtips" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Indie Game Marketing Tips on YouTube</a> is a channel that, on paper, I would have zero interest in. As I mentioned in the post about learning game design, I love a sharply edited YouTube video with graphics and video clips. But Indie Game Marketing Tips? This is literally a guy sitting in front of a benign wall talking directly to the camera. Not a single visual graphic to spice things up. He somehow ended up in my YouTube recommendation algorithm and I hit play because I was intrigued by the title.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rf8NaH61f6M?si=axbIEUsTJUCvHomy" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>It was one of those talks that just kind of ringed true to me, it made sense. It also happened to be super relevant to a conversation I had had with my wife just a day before on how we wanted to approach making games. This guy has under 1000 views on his videos and I guess it could be because of his extremely basic video format but it’s a little hilarious to see that from someone marketing themselves as a marketing pro. But his videos are on the shorter side (under 30 minutes) and he talks really fast which is something that helps hold my attention (I often watch videos at 1.5 speed but I don’t need to turn this guy up at all lol). So I plan to go through his last few months of videos.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/marketing-indies#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>There is still a lot for us to learn how to play this marketing game. Our first two games were made within a month each, that’s not a long time to market a game. Common knowledge is to have your Steam page up for at least 3 months before launch to have time to gather wishlists. We had no Steam page and launched our games in 30 days, so of course the early marketing window was tiny.</p>
<p>Our current focus is to get Spellphage into as many Steam festivals as possible to keep fishing for Wishlists. At the same time we’ll be drip marketing our brand new, in-progress game. Those drips being what you’re reading right now, ah ha, I got ya.</p>
<p>We’re giving ourselves multiple months for our next game (gasp! So much time!) and I’m really hoping to document a lot of that process. Both for archival purposes but also because being able to share our process and maybe even some tips or tricks feels like an honest way of both marketing but also connecting with other devs and gamers. So I hope to keep writing devlogs documenting our progress.</p>
<p>We’re also going to be showing Spellphage in-person at a conference here in Montreal in September. This will be a brand new experience for us and hopefully a good place to get feedback and maybe even look for possible future studio coworkers.</p>
<p>We haven’t heard back from any of the online festivals yet, so we don’t know if we’ve gotten into any of them. But if we do I’ll do a follow up marketing post to share any impacts a festival has on wishlists!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>video games</category>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paper Prototyping Fateweaver]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Our approach to paper prototyping our next game.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From game design classes to paper prototyping our new game. We’re moving fast over here.</p>
<p>Paper prototyping is the idea of making a physical version of your game so that you can play it as quickly as possible. This doesn’t mean making nice art assets or finding the perfect meeple. It’s very much the idea of a minimal viable product that gets you playing faster.</p>
<p>This doesn’t work for all video games of course. There isn’t much benefit for trying to paper prototype a platformer or a huge open world game. Unless you can boil down a part of those games into a form that can be simplified enough to play by hand.</p>
<p>By having quick access to a playable version of your game idea you can start testing out your design. Do the rules make sense? Is it too easy? Can a player complete the game? Does it need more cards or less cards? If you can paper prototype it, you can test it, toss it, iterate on it, in less time than it would take to program your original idea. It’s this time save that makes paper prototyping so useful. Instead of spending a month developing a minimal digital version you can have something going in an hour. You can even have other people playing it before even opening a game engine. As a young studio with minimal runway, this felt like the obvious path forward for our new game.</p>
<p>So we cut some sheets of papers into smaller rectangles, created a few cards, and started playing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="round-one">Round one<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping#round-one" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Round one" title="Direct link to Round one">​</a></h2>
<p>The first version of our cards were cut up lined loose leaf paper. We had our concept only in our heads, we hadn’t even tried to align on rules between each other yet. We sat down, created the most basic cards for getting the idea across and tested out what we imagined the flow to be.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A photo of our first version of the cards, penciled in rules on loose leaf paper." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fateweaver-v1cards-7629a940843ca27109f55ca020d23a15.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Because we were moving so quickly we were making up cards on the fly, making edits by pulling the paper out of the sleeves and building out the basic concepts while also making our first round of assets.</p>
<p>This felt very promising after just two hours of trialing ideas. We didn’t have to buy anything to even do it, but we left the exercise feeling the potential of the game.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cider-card-ide">CIDEr (Card IDE)<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping#cider-card-ide" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to CIDEr (Card IDE)" title="Direct link to CIDEr (Card IDE)">​</a></h2>
<p>Our hand cut and hand written cards didn’t last long. After dedicating some time to card ideas we wanted a better way to manage and track our unique decks. Turns out there are multiple tools for this as people love card games.</p>
<p>We ended up going with <a href="https://oatear.github.io/cider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CIDEr</a>.</p>
<p>CIDEr lets you create both the text and visuals of the cards and provides a template for exporting them to PDF for printing. It uses HTML and CSS as a layout engine with real-time previewing, so it was quick and easy to get a basic design going for the various card types. We still needed to cut out each individual card from the printer paper but we no longer had to write out each card by hand. And now our card list and styles can live over on GitHub so it’s easier for the two of us to collaborate. GitHub also makes versioning a snap. All the cards end up in a .csv file which we hope to then feed into Godot directly to generate the cards in the engine when we’re ready. Overall, despite its low version number, it's an excellent piece of software I would recommend to anyone interested in designing a card game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="A screenshot of the csv file in our GitHub repo." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/cider-card-list-9a29694e58a5b027e6fc1745f170486b.png" width="2022" height="938" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>We’re getting close to a very streamlined production flow but cutting by hand was starting to slow us down due to the increasing number of cards we were developing. It was time for a trip to an office supply store.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Photo of our newly printed CIDEr cards sleeved and ready to play." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/cider-cards-fefff4070d1ca5223e805a026fb8cd98.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="resources--tools">Resources &amp; tools<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping#resources--tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Resources &amp; tools" title="Direct link to Resources &amp; tools">​</a></h2>
<p>Now it was very tempting to pick up a <a href="https://www.staples.ca/products/434777-en-x-acto-12-heavy-duty-plastic-base-paper-trimmer?listId=collection" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">paper trimmer</a> to speed up cutting all the cards. You can cut through so many sheets of paper all at once. But we’re on a tight budget with limited apartment space, we weren’t going to find a permanent spot to house a full on guillotine.</p>
<p>We settled on <a href="https://www.staples.ca/products/2070838-en-fiskars-9-surecut-paper-trimmer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this paper slicer</a>. 10 sheets at a time is still a huge improvement over 1 and it only cost us 20$.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/paper-slicer-edb5714adb930ceeb371d7cdaae1a7fc.jpg" width="1200" height="1200" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The paper cutter is the only money we’ve had to put into this project so far as our Magic the Gathering card collection has been a huge boon of resources.</p>
<p>We knew we’d need land cards because our game revolves around traversing over a “landscape”. The basic land types from Magic were basically perfect right out the gate for this so we just sleeved some land cards, broke them into 4 decks, Spring, Summer, Fall, and Winter, and called it a day on land cards.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/season-decks-305e3ca606be6dc47f3a58cc937b6fec.jpg" width="4032" height="2268" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>We did re-flavour and rename the base Magic lands. Partially because it would be obvious where the types originated but also because our land cards all have unique mechanics which felt like they could use more fitting names.</p>
<ul>
<li>Plains became Meadows</li>
<li>Islands became Mists</li>
<li>Forests became Mazes</li>
<li>Mountain remain Mountains because it really fits our naming scheme</li>
<li>Swamps became Mires</li>
</ul>
<p>The development of the season decks did add a decent amount of complexity to running each play test because it slowed down both clean up and setup. Once programmed, a computer will manage the odds and deal out the landscape, but us humans need to manage it right now. So to speed up testing we did move out to shuffling all the season decks together into one deck because we can deal them out quickly thanks to the sleeve colour. A small compromise on sticking true to the future format but it feels like the right call for the moment to keep things moving.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/merge-seasons-c2ed04c847a5ec9f85d847d0b3738247.jpg" width="2268" height="1405" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>For our Fate Cards and Journey Cards (the cards the user plays) we sleeved a bunch of regular magic cards and then slid the printed versions of our cards over top so that when playing you still feel like you’re holding a nice solid playing card and not just printed loose paper.</p>
<p>As the complexity of our decks grew we broke down our different deck types by colours. 1 colour for our Fate cards, 1 colour for our Journey cards, and 1 colour for each season of land cards. This makes it easier to clean up after each play session and quickly short the cards back into their appropriate deck.</p>
<p>Some of our other Magic supplies have also come in handy so far too. When you buy certain release sets of magic cards you get to pop out little cardboard tabs that you put on top of your Magic cards during games to indicate things like status effects. We have a huge collection of these little things so we’ve been putting them to use to track our own game mechanics like the path our character has travelled and which pathways have Degraded. And thanks to some door tokens from the haunted house set from last year we have been able to use the doors to indicate Entrance and Exit of each level.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Some of the Magic the Gathering tokens we’ve been using and some dice." src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/tokens-e4b175af79e2afb77e63e000a166046c.jpg" width="4032" height="1651" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The whole project has basically been finding alternate uses from our existing game collection. Didn’t have to buy anything new, just re-purposed a lot of objects from our games shelf.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="play-testing">Play testing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping#play-testing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Play testing" title="Direct link to Play testing">​</a></h2>
<p>Thanks to the incremental approach we took starting with the most basic rules we had: lay down a path (cards) on the landscape to traverse the landscape, we have been able to play test since day 1 of our paper prototype. We were playing every day for a while as we were building out the Fate Cards and the mechanics for each land type. Almost a week in and we managed to rope 2 friends into trying it out as well.</p>
<p>It was really validating to have new eyes on the game and seeing the rules start to click for people who aren’t us. Ideally we’d have someone new come by every week to get their feedback on the state of the game so far but it’s hard to lure friends into being testers.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fateweaver2-d72922fc5f6d7340e154ad250c22e5a5.jpeg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>It is the one main downside to paper prototyping, we can only share the game in person. We do have the rules fully typed out and it would be easy to share a PDF of the cards for other people to print out and play but it’s a huge request to make when you’re still constantly shifting cards around and actively developing. So we’ll probably just keep forcing anyone who comes into our home to play a round or two until we have a digital prototype.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/paper-prototyping#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Being able to see your game idea come together and become playable so quickly with paper prototyping has been amazing. It makes sense why so many teachers/textbooks/experienced game devs tout it as being so important. Just having physical things to touch and engage with has also made iteration faster both through</p>
<ol>
<li>Being able to test out new ideas on the fly</li>
<li>Being able to think about physical limitations or expansions</li>
</ol>
<p>It’s one thing to keep thinking about concepts and ideas in your head, but being able to move things around on a table really lets new neurons fire and make new connections in your brain much faster. This has been made extra clear from doing our game design homework where, during the exercises, they want you to spend time designing small games. We kept them all ideas/notes based and it took way more time than I thought it would to come up with ideas that felt good. Compared to our paper prototype where it feels like we come up with good, new ideas every time we play through it.</p>
<p>We’re likely to keep paper prototyping for a little while longer as we still have some ideas we want to put to the test that feel central to the main progression of the game. Once the main flow and mechanics make sense to us we’ll probably spend some time considering, and testing, balance.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>video games</category>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting into Game Design]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Some general musing and record keeping of foundational studio steps.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Game design isn’t a brand new field to me, but I can’t say that I ever studied it formally.</p>
<p>I’ve been playing video games since before I can remember, some of my earliest memories being watching my parents try to beat the first world in Super Mario World on a SNES they won at a gas station on a road trip. They never really played again after that, my brother and I took over the system and eventually breezed past that first world.</p>
<p>Video games have always been a hobby, one that for a long time that I wanted to make into a career. But that still didn’t really lead me to thinking about the deeper levels of game design. Not until I started trying to make games myself, which crashed pretty quickly back in my 20s. And then not again until I started writing D&amp;D adventures.</p>
<p>While D&amp;D is already itself a game with rules and expectations, writing my own one-shots and more <a href="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/292510/A-Stolen-Sun" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">serious adventures</a> really helped me get the feeling of what makes games good.</p>
<p>I didn’t realize it back when I was writing A Stolen Sun because I didn’t have the words for it, but the design choices that felt best to be were the ones that I now see aligning with MDA framework. I wanted to create choices and unique rules in my adventures that paired Mechanics, Dynamics, and Aesthetics all together. It’s those design choices that make systems feel alive and “realistic”. Not in a “it happens in real life” way, but in a way that when thought about can make logical sense to a brain. Instead of mechanics that a brain might see as strange and try to reject.</p>
<p>Now coming up with those rules is one thing, but then having to execute them as a DM is a whole other side of the coin! In a way it makes it harder to pull off in a TTRPG because in a video game a computer gets to pull it off instead.</p>
<p>So then still the question, why get back into it now?</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-next-game">Our next game<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#our-next-game" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our next game" title="Direct link to Our next game">​</a></h2>
<p>As we go through the motions of a game studio; creating a Steam Developer Account, setting up a website, creating press kits, we also need to think of what’s next.</p>
<p>We have <a href="https://wtchcrft.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">two visual novels so far</a> and we’re ready to move away from the traditional visual novel format (visuals, text, choices). Which honestly, is basically just “throw a few more game genres in there” and now you’ve got yourself a narrative game instead of a visual novel.</p>
<p>Since every Steam page costs 100$ to launch we started thinking about how to capitalize on what we have already as a foundation and make it more game-like. This led us to the work we’re doing on Fate Spinner which I wrote about in my last blog post.</p>
<p>But we didn’t just want to jump in blind, we’re both fairly education and learning oriented so reaching a solid understanding of the foundational text, language, and history of game design was important to us. So we started to study.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-course">The course<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#the-course" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The course" title="Direct link to The course">​</a></h2>
<p>My wife found an old online, self-directed course on Wordpress titled <a href="https://gamedesignconcepts.wordpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game Design Concepts</a> by <a href="https://www.edx.org/bio/ian-schreiber-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ian Schreiber</a>. It’s one of those old blogs that’s delightful to see still alive. Something someone put a lot of work into that hasn’t disappeared to one of the vanishing social media.</p>
<p>The course has 20 lessons with its own recommended reading and exercises. We flipped to lesson 1 and began.</p>
<p>Some of the lessons are straight forward while some of them have homework that’s decently time and brain consuming. It’s been fun though. After being away from school for over 10 years it’s nice to have a semi-serious study habit developing. Basically it just still feels nice to learn new things.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="game-design-books">Game design books<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#game-design-books" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Game design books" title="Direct link to Game design books">​</a></h2>
<p>There were a few recommended books in the course so far but not all of them have been findable through free options like the library. We did get a copy of Challenges for Game Designers (available on the Internet Archive) which feels like the most central book to the course and we’ve been trying to do all of the exercises that it offers at the end of the chapters. It’s been a real test of trying to quickly apply what you’ve learned even though you feel like you maybe haven’t learnt much yet.</p>
<p>Besides game design I also decided to finally read <a href="https://www.writingfor.games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Writing for Games by Hannah Nicklin</a>. I had been putting it off because it was an expensive book. I’ve now finally made it through the bulk of the content and can dive into some of the exercises at the end of the book. It was interesting to read a book from someone who’s background just felt so grounded more in theatre than other forms of writing. I can definitely see it giving Nicklin an advantage in game writing but I don’t see myself getting interested in theatre any time soon….</p>
<p>Next up book wise will be <a href="https://www.thevideogamelibrary.org/book/the-art-of-game-design-a-book-of-lenses" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Art of Game Design: A Book of Lenses by Jesse Schell</a>, which my wife has talked up a fair bit already.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="video-learning">Video learning<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#video-learning" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Video learning" title="Direct link to Video learning">​</a></h2>
<p>I’ve really come around to learning from videos ever since I got more heavily into art practice. It’s not a medium that does great with written tutorials, being able to see someone doing the physical motions of creating art is important to learning how. But due to the nature of the many YouTube art tutorials I watch, my brain also wants sharp editing! Sound bites! High quality and flashy! Even if the high quality visuals and flashy content might be hiding lower quality information.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8uE6-vIi1rQ?si=oqQYmDJ7yw6p8kpx" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>My first instinct on YouTube is to pull up old GDC talks. There’s now nearly a decade of those, gotta be plenty for me to spend years trying to take it all in. Some of those early years have not so great visual and audio quality but you can still get the information being presented. I thought there’d be an obvious “go-to” kind of best of the best collection of talks but the views are decently spread across the videos so I’ve been trying to watch a bunch of different ones. Over time I’ve started to prioritize the 5 small talks in 1 talk. I enjoy these smaller lessons that are often trying to drive one point forward. It makes for a cleaner takeaway message for me to remember.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d8QAVGeEj-U?si=9La4Jh1uAc9PAUga" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>My other approach is to search around specific genres, mechanics, or even games. Since we’re working on a card game I’ve been searching for talks about those. Often ending up on Slay the Spire talks as it’s still one of the most dominant touch-points for the genre. We’re not making a Slay the Spire though so only a few key lessons to be gleaned from that content.</p>
<p>My second most common YouTube channel is now probably <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqJ-Xo29CKyLTjn6z2XwYAw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game Makers Tool Kit (GMTK)</a>. These are often shorter than GDC talks, more in the 20 minute area so I can put one on when I want to give my brain something to chew on or get activated to pursue a more serious creative project. Kind of like an appetizer for the more serious academic papers referenced in the game design course. But the other fun part of GMTK videos is that I don’t always agree with all the points the host makes. Which turns into a boon because it then means that these videos often become more like discussion topics for me and my wife. Giving us something to dissect and articulate our own feelings about.</p>
<p>But maybe what GMTK is best at is just having so many references! I don’t know how he finds the time to play/learn about so many games to talk about them in his videos but it’s just so nice to see concrete examples of the things being talked about.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="my-idle-walking-game-idea">My idle-walking game idea<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#my-idle-walking-game-idea" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to My idle-walking game idea" title="Direct link to My idle-walking game idea">​</a></h2>
<p>I teased this idea mostly <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kymira.ca/post/3lpk2ihxors2h" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on BlueSky last month</a> because it was inspired by another game designer's post from there. An idle-battler where the battles take place at locations you need to walk to. Kind of like Pokemon Go’s gym system but instead of Pokemon you have 1 or multiple adventurers and they go explore a dungeon for a set time before returning to you with results.</p>
<p>I really like games that encourage me to go outside. I don’t love just going for a walk, I really like having a destination or goal. Pokemon Go was able to give me that for a while but it’s faded over the last 10 years. So now I’m free to think about what other kinds of walking games would get me outside.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/walker-brainstorming-371936abeb9c21cd4acffb772d437f10.jpg" width="4341" height="3554" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This really took up a lot of space in my brain for a few weeks and doing the visual mock-ups helped off load the mini-obsession. I still really like the idea and there are some fun game design problems to puzzle over in the project, but I’m not super interested in developing a phone game at the moment. Desktop and web feel like enough for now. But maybe someday, when I learn more about UI design. Because a big thing about phone games is that you need to nail the UI, but that’s possibly more of a pet peeve than a rule of thumb.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/game-design-begins#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>One of the interesting realizations from studying game design has been how similar it is to writing. You can read and watch all you want about game design but you aren’t going to get any better at it until you do it. Going through some of the early exercises was tough, you grasp at simple ideas, things that are familiar. But with each iterative exercise I felt like we were getting both faster at coming up with ideas but also coming up with ideas that made more sense. Like any skill, you need to use it. Mostly because there isn’t a step by step process to making a game, you aren’t going to repeat what you did for the last one all over again as you might need a whole new approach, a whole new set of knowledge. What you need to refine are your ways of thinking and not just your ideas.</p>
<p>I was going to use this blog post to talk more about the paper prototyping we’ve been doing but the post has already gotten pretty long. So I’ll leave you with this, another basic mock-up. And in a month or so we’ll see how much it’s changed.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fateweaver-layout1-cf18655da5995cb2e5632c61fb086f00.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>video games</category>
            <category>studio wtchcrft</category>
            <category>game design</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May Recap]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A summary post of May projects and happenings.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After valiantly trying to keep posting through my sickness in March and April, I finally lost the energy to keep up. All my energy was going into getting through the days and staying present at work. Hobbies are always the first thing to suffer when the going gets tough.</p>
<p>And as a person who works best with momentum and consistency, losing my stride is one of the worst things that can happen to my practice.</p>
<p>I’m now in the stages of trying to get re-interested in drawing. Doing focused practice isn’t “fun” but I did it regularly because I do find myself improving because of it. But that doesn’t make it desirable. So instead of trying to get back into WAPs and anatomy studies and doing the classic “draw what you want” approach.</p>
<p>Currently that means having a bunch of half-finished pieces hanging around with no idea if I’m ever going to finish them or not. But they have gotten me drawing again.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-skril-piece">New Skril piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025#new-skril-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Skril piece" title="Direct link to New Skril piece">​</a></h2>
<p>I did this base sketch back during my Hades art week. It’s from an Adorka Stock reference piece and I was really proud of how I managed the hands.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/skril-fire-circle-d5e0aef0b03eef8e5a8d2f84aeb7b064.jpg" width="2825" height="3887" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>In the last few weeks I’ve done a cleanup pass and added clothes. Last week I started watching a lot of improve your lineart technique videos in preparation for inks. But first I want to clean up the face because it’s at an angle I’ve never worked at before and the hair could use more confident shapes. After that I hope to give working with vector lines a try.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="trueref-draw-this-monthly-challenge">TrueRef Draw This! Monthly challenge<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025#trueref-draw-this-monthly-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to TrueRef Draw This! Monthly challenge" title="Direct link to TrueRef Draw This! Monthly challenge">​</a></h2>
<p>I follow a few stock pose creators on socials as it’s always nice to have quick access to images to work from for poses, anatomy, and gesture studies. <a href="https://trueref.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TrueRef</a> is a newer one to me and I only learned of their <a href="https://trueref.io/pages/draw-this" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Draw This! Challenge</a> this month. The month's image was inspiring to me so I wanted to work from it and then ended up liking how it was turning out.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Two drow " src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/trueref-may-9318cb7c313c5054300d4833dcf08195.jpg" width="2476" height="2880" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I ended up doing multiple cleanup passes on it before submitting it to a Drawfee critique class to get some feedback. I now want to do a few alterations and fixes to it before moving it on to lines. What I really want to do is try to push the expressions on the faces, it’s an area I struggle with so I’m happy to have an opportunity to focus on it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fatespinner">Fatespinner<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025#fatespinner" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fatespinner" title="Direct link to Fatespinner">​</a></h2>
<p>After finally finishing Blue Prince we’ve been preparing to return to studio and game work. This led to starting a self guided online course on game design and then to do a paper prototype of a card game.</p>
<p>As a studio we’ve been thinking of ways to make our original game <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/littos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Love in the Time of Spellphage</a> more interactive. It’s currently a Visual Novel with choices that change the game but it doesn’t have much for gameplay elements beyond that. So we wanted to introduce something that doesn’t feel like a tacked on mini game. It needs to fit in the world and contribute to the existing elements of choices and magic. This led to what we’re currently calling Fatespinner. A puzzle card game about finding your way.</p>
<p>We’ve been actively working on it for about 2 weeks now. We’re still refinding and developing the mechanics but we’re very happy with the central make-up of the game so far. Now it’s about tuning for difficulty and finding ways for players to customize their own approaches.</p>
<p>I’ve started to do some concept work for the cards. We aren’t set on a specific style yet so I’m very much in the zone of trying out a lot of different things. With our main requirement being that we don’t want it to take forever…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/fatespinner-v1-460b7132819edcd88b1e7a2315adac76.jpg" width="2268" height="3070" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>While Spellphage was the original building block for the game we’re now deep into thinking about the themes and what’s fun about this card game. About how many layers of complexity we want and what kind of story it would best serve. So there is a chance that this card game grows beyond what we envisioned for Spellphage to the point of becoming its whole own game.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/may2025#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>June is shaping up to be a very busy month so I’m not sure if I’m going to be able to fully return to any kind of scheduled, consistent art practice. I suspect it will be more chipping away at existing pieces while workshopping lots of different card styles.</p>
<p>We’re going to attend the <a href="https://narrascope.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Narrascope conference</a> online later in the month. And I’ve signed up for <a href="https://spencerwan.tumblr.com/post/780816079738011648/hey-yall-im-teaching-another-workshop-i-dont" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spencer Wan’s draftmanship for animation</a> lesson. Which I can’t find a page for so might actually be sold out already!</p>
<p>July is going to bring it possibly multiple medical things so I also don’t want to bank on feeling super great and inspired then. So maybe August, in the peak of summer heat, things might start to stabilise again...</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playing guitar - anatomy]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A week spent practicing guitar playing poses.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We launched our studio website the other week and while I’m happy with it I do feel like it’s lacking in art. I’d love to do little cartoon versions of myself and my wife but cartoon versions of real people is something I’ve never been great at. This week's study of guitar playing poses is me starting the baseline work for that as I know I’m going to do a few attempts of my wife playing guitar.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>While I at least understand how guitars are held and played, keeping a large object in proportion to a body is still difficult for me.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-1-035d31dc72e5c5c8593acc4e1e24f050.jpg" width="2268" height="1689" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Found some decent references, I was worried they might all just be some guy sitting down, but Pinterest had some decent in motion poses going on.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-2-de68cdce08244a15701fc6c8d7ab85cb.jpg" width="2268" height="1592" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m finding that I lose a lot of movement and energy in these more precise studies. They’re great for proportions but I feel like I use the arcs of action. Lots of the little arrows I draw around the final are places where I feel like the angle should be pushed.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-3.1-c84303c4d6c8163b00148df522556b39.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-3.2-a8a53484c3e1ace1afc34573040edd25.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-3.3-ca74a95bb7cf7950568fe026f7490896.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---drawing-from-imagination">Day 4 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses#day-4---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Putting the practice into action.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/guitar-4-28d5f659e710914f497ead71db0d20e7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/guitar-poses#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Another thing this week made me notice is that I’m starting to feel pretty confident about basic anatomy and poses. I would never expect to nail detailed, muscular anatomy but I feel like I’m at a level that’s good enough for the kind of character art I like to do now. What I feel less confident about is faces.</p>
<p>I spent some time focusing on mouths, eyes, and noses for our first video game in January. And I’m still pretty happy with how those faces turned out, but I still panic and need to do 10 passes when I draw a new character. So I might change up my anatomy weeks with some face studies. Then maybe I’ll stop drawing all these faceless bodies during my anatomy weeks.</p>
<p>Next week is supposed to be a new style study but I didn’t do the usual research in preparation for which style I want to do with D; I have some Pokemon art I want to work on so I might do that instead. Maybe do some practice capsule art for preparing to put games on steam. Basically all to say I don’t know what I’ll be working on next but I’ve got some projects in mind.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-guitar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of guitar poses.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reference Study - Squirrel Adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Taking 3 reference images and making them into 1.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This 3 image reference study stretched into 2 weeks as I got distracted by other art projects and also had my energy drained due to on-going health problems.</p>
<p>And then Blue Prince was released and I forgot that blogging was a thing I did.</p>
<p>But a long weekend has given me the downtime I need to return to my hobbies and project and also Blue Prince.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-images">Reference Images<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#reference-images" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reference Images" title="Direct link to Reference Images">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2_refs-38ad41a0ac1e5e2d7220554c78953da4.jpg" width="2000" height="902" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The big masked creature is by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/artwithbryn/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bryn Jones @artwithbryn</a>. Trying to find the source really highlighted for me how awful it is when artists only have an Instagram page. I don’t want Facebook/Meta touching my computer so I’m not going to log into Instagram on my computer, which means I can only see the last 9 posts from a user &gt;_&gt;</p>
<p>The squirrel is <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/moussee/art/Acorn-collector-856841684" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Acorn collector by mousse on DeviantArt</a>.</p>
<p>And the boat on the waves, my piece used as colour scheme inspiration, is by <a href="https://dribbble.com/shots/14961000-Waves" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dmitrij on Dribble</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="thumbnailing">Thumbnailing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#thumbnailing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Thumbnailing" title="Direct link to Thumbnailing">​</a></h2>
<p>Tried out a few different compositions and angles for the piece. Most of them focused on a squirrel POV. I wanted to show the size difference, to convey how large this forest monster could be.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2_thumbnails-88290d2f29e218f2119d5f1a037814d8.jpg" width="5524" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="basic-colours">Basic colours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#basic-colours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Basic colours" title="Direct link to Basic colours">​</a></h2>
<p>I tried out a few different colour variations on the thumbnail after choosing the winning one. I knew all the blue would be a challenge given I was working with a forest instead of the ocean.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2_thumbnail_colours-b3dee41a80c90ae8ea75259cab4a62cc.jpg" width="5524" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---refining">Day 2 - Refining<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#day-2---refining" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Refining" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Refining">​</a></h2>
<p>I went with the middle option for colours but felt it still needed to be revisited. I tried to push the colours a bit and see where I would go brighter or darker.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2_thumbnail_refined-7191f4c163f01cc58a1945199dfc6a15.jpg" width="5524" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---oil-paints">Day 3 - oil paints<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#day-3---oil-paints" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - oil paints" title="Direct link to Day 3 - oil paints">​</a></h2>
<p>I once again felt overwhelmed by how to begin painting. I was coming off of the hard lines of the Hades study, which felt safe and doable, but not fitting for this piece. I wanted to be a little more consistent than my last reference study, they Fey Boat, but I wasn’t sure which way I wanted to go.</p>
<p>I really liked the painted style of the monster piece so I ended up doing some <a href="https://kagi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kagi searches</a> for some CSP oil paint tutorials.</p>
<p>I ended up finding one that even included a free custom made brush pack. So I downloaded the brush pack, watched the video a few times, downloaded a canvas texture and started laying in the light and dark areas.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2_light-dark-bd0d40cfa6a0a8a20c2ba612dc5a5512.jpg" width="3505" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5-vMUcP3YMY?si=-CNP98LDQ2bxb-1t" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="work-continues">Work continues<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#work-continues" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Work continues" title="Direct link to Work continues">​</a></h2>
<p>I was trying to follow the light and dark focus on the oil paint base layer but I really struggled with when it came to laying down the colours. Everything felt really messy and muddy while barely having any oil paint vibe at all.</p>
<p>I didn’t save any in-progress shots from this time which was a weird choice given how slowly this piece moved. Something I’ll want to get into the habit of. Need to fight off the fear that I’ll fill up the computer with a bunch of in-progress JPEGs.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-piece">Final piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#final-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final piece" title="Direct link to Final piece">​</a></h2>
<p>While I went through a few stages of really hating this and feeling like I didn’t know what I was doing, I do like the final piece.</p>
<p>I spent a lot of time trying to fix the field and it’s the one part I’m still unhappy with. I really like the field in the original monster inspo piece, and I just have a feeling it’s gotta be thanks to a brush? I hate to lean on “I didn’t have the right brush though”. It could easily be that I also just didn’t master the brushes I did have.</p>
<p>But aside from that I really like how the tree stump turned out, the squirrel itself has a nice fuzz. The trees are basic but I think that’s okay because they aren’t the focus. And the monster even came out looking kind of fuzzy? So I like enough of it that I think I’ll give oil brushes another shot in the future.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs2-squirrel-final-5ab25f9f34d11884993e10c8e7ae0bce.jpg" width="2659" height="3072" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-game-release">New game release!<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#new-game-release" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New game release!" title="Direct link to New game release!">​</a></h2>
<p>For the month of March my wife teamed up with a comic artist to work on another VN project, a point and click adventure titled Escape from Precinct 27.</p>
<iframe src="https://itch.io/embed/3474720" width="552" height="167" frameborder="0"><a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/escape-from-precinct-27">Escape from Precinct 27: 4K Deluxe Edition by sophiefromhowls, Andrew Greenstone</a></iframe>
<p>Along with it we launched our little studio into the world, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/studio-wtchcrft.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Studio Wtchcrft</a>, and now I’m spending 10% of my time on marketing and research, and looking into ways we can make money to keep making games. Also been spending time doing web dev. Made the studio a website and hand wrote a presskit page for Precinct 27 that I’m thinking of making available to the public as a template.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/oil-squirrel#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>My spare time is being pulled in a lot of different directions right now, and my health isn’t feeling good enough to pursue them all. Going to do either a WAP or anatomy week next as a hopefully easier art time while I keep pursuing game studio stuff.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pink Pawmi Club]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Putting shiny Pawmis in Chappell Roan’s Pink Pony Club.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week started off as a reference study. I had my 3 references selected, got through some thumbnails, did some different colour compositions and even started painting.</p>
<p>But then there was a joke; What if Pink Pony Club, but it’s Pawmi instead of Pony. As context, a Pawmi is a recent gen Pokemon. This is a Pawmi:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/pawmi-a696dd7839baddf57c4d94a5e8f8f79b.jpg" width="900" height="793" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The next day I went to see what colour shiny Pawmis are, and well, they’re pink. The joke basically writes itself. So I paused my reference study and drew Pawmis for a few days.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="chappell-roans-pink-pony-club">Chappell Roan’s Pink Pony Club<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc#chappell-roans-pink-pony-club" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Chappell Roan’s Pink Pony Club" title="Direct link to Chappell Roan’s Pink Pony Club">​</a></h2>
<p>The first step to working on this visual gag was to actually watch the music video for Chappell Roan’s Pink Pony Club. I’ve known the song for a few years now but I’m not in the habit of watching music videos. Overall I found it to be pretty underwhelming, I was hoping for more over the top visuals to work with.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GR3Liudev18?si=mcykRJn6tsfNjrHV" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="early-sketches">Early sketches<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc#early-sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Early sketches" title="Direct link to Early sketches">​</a></h2>
<p>After choosing the stage from the video as the main scene I started to do some sketches in Procreate. At first I had envisioned one of each Pawmi evolution on stage so I did two passes at that to find a composition. I ended up with two Pawmos that I really liked (Pawmis middle evolution) so I ended up keeping four of the sketches on stage.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ppc-sketches-f9a8d9214ccf0ea6c414fa947f110510.jpg" width="2732" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rendering">Rendering<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc#rendering" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rendering" title="Direct link to Rendering">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn’t want to do the lines on the iPad so I sent the file over to my laptop and continued the piece in CSP. I wasn’t certain how I wanted to render the piece but I knew I wanted to keep it simple and at least close to the Pokemon style. I ended up really liking my first pass which was using the ink style from my Hades study week, using a pen with a set size. So 7px for the exterior lines and get smaller as you go inwards. I’ve just come to like its consistency and not worrying about how hard I’m pressing while trying to focus on getting the right lines down.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/pawmot-42b4da7581242cd75bcbdaf6bfd41aef.jpg" width="789" height="1207" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Took a break after that guy and continued the next day. Which happened to be my birthday where I was gifted two Pokemon for keeping company at my art desk. Gender is a drawing support who I now put between me and the desk to stop me from hunching forward too much while drawing at the tablet. And Pawmot is there because I love him.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/deskphoto-649f4a78320caa32fd69182c297849f4.jpg" width="1814" height="2442" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The full render took about 3 days of working on it here and there and it came together pretty easily. My wife suggested that there should be some cowboy accessories so I did give them some rhinestone garments. I didn’t want to spend ages on the background because this piece was mostly done to just show a joke but I feel like it sells pretty well for a simple background.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ppc-final-5f8fedd995d3d322fc71db798bce258c.jpg" width="2732" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/ppc#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I had a lot of fun with this piece. It’s easy to keep working on something when just looking at it makes you happy. I got to search and look at a lot of pawmi images. What more could a girl want?</p>
<p>Since I like looking at my guys so much I did then return and make a vertical format so that I could possibly use them as a phone background to see them every day. I’ll now try to return to my reference study, maybe give it a few extra days while I try to learn some digital oil painting techniques.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ppc-phone-background-98e0f2c7e7ea4b763f36d1c07b2a4762.png" width="1080" height="2400" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>pokemon</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 42]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 42 - Axolotl]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for a casual WAP week with axolotls. Partially inspired by the axolotl I drew during Root week, I thought it might be a good time to really look at them and see what features I might have missed in my quick cartoonification.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>I really couldn’t remember what their feet looked like.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.1-b207ba5d2f9180b91f1081328654cd98.jpg" width="2102" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>A little better but they still seem a little wonky. But possibly realizing these guys might just naturally be a little wonky.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.2-65269808a902b75f8c10371e9eed9487.jpg" width="2174" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Something I hadn’t really paid too much attention to before was the intense rib cage thing going on. They almost look like a row of gills.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.3.1-f2559acfd2f9a1c1bd23dfa74cdc9d34.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.3.2-d718e4b78a3b67c607a839c2bc98f0a6.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.3.3-c5abe2ded98d8bada7abf8009bf9f556.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.4.1-d907284a699cb8f204614e3be9179df6.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Axolotls by <a href="https://cara.app/naniiebim" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Naniiebim on Cara</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.4.2-c1fb2e537e042af1d846ec86da4f24b5.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: By <a href="https://x.com/yura_inaho?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yura Inaho on X</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.4.3-467186daf718c4b695115f10b6c606e7.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: This seems to come from the deactivated Tumblr account of <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/micahdillustrations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@micahdillustrations</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>In the end these guys aren’t that complicated, just a little weird. Their hands are more simple then I originally thought, their heads on the overly large side. Just got a slight alien vibe to them.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-42.5-300f006547b7e6fe29b0eef193f038ea.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-42#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>It was fun to spend time browsing axolotl art, there's a lot of really cute and cool takes on them out there. Beyond figuring out what they look like I should go learn some facts about them like what they eat, where they live, what are they up to in the water?</p>
<p>I'm keeping WAP posts short as they are kind of my "rest" weeks and I've been needed my rest weeks while my body goes through some sort of internal guts overhaul. But I'm now gearing up for a new reference image week and those end up feeling more intense. But it's time to roll the dice and see what I'm working with.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-axolotl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of axolotls</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Style Study - Hades]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A week spent studying the art style of the video game Hades, as led by Jen Zee.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Second style study of the year is the art of Hades, the hit Supergiant game and one of my all time faves.</p>
<p>My approach to this week was to re-create some existing game assets and then adapt one of my characters into a Hades styled portrait shot. A slightly different approach from my Root week as I found this style much more difficult and just mentally draining because of how central the line art is to the style.</p>
<p>Main focuses for the week:</p>
<ul>
<li>Line art style</li>
<li>Colours</li>
<li>Ink black shadows</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="research">Research<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#research" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Research" title="Direct link to Research">​</a></h2>
<p>I knew this would be a pretty easy art style to research because Hades is so beloved. So there are multiple videos of people breaking down the style, people sharing their research, others compiling a list of inspiration and techniques used from multiple interviews with the art director.</p>
<p>Which is an amazing amount of resources to learn from, but because this is an official in-house style used by multiple artists, there aren’t really first hand reports from them. Which I think makes sense because while the style is going to be replicated, you don’t need to make it super easy for people to make knock-offs.</p>
<p>There is however one very short sequence in <a href="https://youtu.be/oQPk9J7spw0?si=3PLDkZbc8TjjvVIh&amp;t=831" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">episode 3 of the the Developing Hell</a> documentary that shows the layers coming together on Jen Zee’s screen.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="style-inspiration">Style inspiration<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#style-inspiration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Style inspiration" title="Direct link to Style inspiration">​</a></h3>
<p>While I did 5 years of art in highschool, I never really learned much about… art styles. Our teacher touched on a few classical artists but there was a big push to focus on Canadian content so the only artists I know are like The Group of Seven.</p>
<p>Because of that it makes learning about professional artist inspirations all the more beneficial. These are some of the names that came up when Jen Zee talk’s about the inspiration for Hades’s look:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mike Mignola (Specifically inspired the direction of the Hades art)</li>
<li>Yoji Shinkawa (For his strongly sculpted character art)</li>
<li>Fred Taylor (For his use of colour and setting)</li>
</ul>
<p>Then there were a few art techniques and inspirations that have also been identified by artists or mentioned by the team. And have been put into a huge list <a href="https://www.pointnthink.fr/en/the-art-of-hades-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in this Point n’ Click blog post</a>. Covering things like classic Greek statues, the importance of diversity, pottery art, and the myths themselves.</p>
<p>As someone who spends a lot of time looking at reference images, and now this year trying to do more studies, it’s cool to see someone else’s clear lines that link what an artist is currently doing to what has come before.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="breakdowns">Breakdowns<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#breakdowns" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Breakdowns" title="Direct link to Breakdowns">​</a></h3>
<p>I think I’ve shared this video before but it’s easily one of my favourite approaches to style studies; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abHLAgvhUGs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Breaking Down the Hades Art Style</a>. Thom catches a lot of details and does a really cool basic sphere to show off the important style features.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-sphere-25ebf6f6e10766db579802d45a8f46b2.png" width="2646" height="1382" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Another interesting breakdown is <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/kDyR9x" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dayron Desmet’ study to create a style bible</a> where he goes over multiple different facets of the style before designing his own 3 accessories in the game style.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="style-warm-ups">Style warm-ups<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#style-warm-ups" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Style warm-ups" title="Direct link to Style warm-ups">​</a></h2>
<p>I started with recreating a few smaller art assets from Hades. No full character portraits, except for Dusa who is probably the smallest portrait in the game.</p>
<p>I chopped these birds off of Artemis’s bow because I love them but also hardly noticed them before since they’re so far away from the rest of her body. I suspect they’re cropped out in most scenes when she’s on the screen.</p>
<p>I struggled with these guys a lot. I felt like I wasn’t getting the shapes down. I hated the way the line art looked. I had no wait in the fixed sized brush. Sunday and Monday were mostly try &gt; delete &gt; restart. Then I finally mentally gave myself permission to not try to match the shapes as accurately and really turned up stabilisation on the brush settings.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-practices-a214ae39439c6eb3ee43aac4a5aca883.jpg" width="4973" height="1958" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The wallet came out okay but my drop of focus on the shape made for some uneven edges but I enjoyed the gold bits.</p>
<p>Dusa was more of a struggle, just being more complex than the previous two practice pieces. But I really wanted to draw the snakes so I stuck with this one even with her slightly off-tilt face.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="brush">Brush<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#brush" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Brush" title="Direct link to Brush">​</a></h3>
<p>It was during these practices that I was able to figure out the right brush because the line work is another part of the distinguished style. It's main feature being a lack of tapering and consistent width.</p>
<p>Thom, in his render breakdown video name dropped the brush he used but I don't have that one. I ended up using a Clip Studio default: The Milli pen.</p>
<p>This marker has no tapering, a locked size, and no pressure sensitivity turned on. So to work with smaller or larger lines I would manually change the size. Keeping my range from 7-4. 7 being used only for the external lines and then going down a number for each time I felt like I was going more "interior" to the piece.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/milli-pen-57720aa4e22991f67a0845f7e323dd98.png" width="374" height="110" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-piece">Final piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#final-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final piece" title="Direct link to Final piece">​</a></h2>
<p>I had already made up my mind to use Skril as my Hades adaptation character, I have a few outfits for her, so I wouldn't have to start from zero design wise.  What I did need was a pose.</p>
<p>I tried sketching out a few options and then decided the hand forward pose was the right amount of drama. Used <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/pin/598978819231278895/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this as my reference</a>.</p>
<p>Following the workflow from the Style Breakdown video I started with the lines. I now had more confidence in the process and also the look of the lines compared to my earlier practices. One change up I did go for was to not do the hard black shadows in the first pass. Sticking to only the functional lines.</p>
<p>I then moved on to flats which was a study in itself. Due to an old laptop dying I didn’t have easy access to a Skril reference and instead colour picked them from a photograph of a marker piece from 5 years ago. This ended up being decently accurate.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-base-colours-ee6651ea91c7807720ff56472410a808.jpg" width="1322" height="1890" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>But I had a problem, Hades portraits are colour balanced very carefully.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="colour-breakdown">Colour breakdown<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#colour-breakdown" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Colour breakdown" title="Direct link to Colour breakdown">​</a></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours1-9370b217fc52b6a7335ca8aac4b16329.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q">
From reading and watching other people break down the style it became clear that I shouldn’t have too many different saturated colours. Characters usually have one main focus colour, often their outfit, while the other large swatches of colour are more de-saturated.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours2-e81391f7024710c319620d95a48466d1.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I also checked the values but these didn’t say much to me. If anything it only highlighted that the colour balance does a lot of work to make the characters easily readable without having any very high values (Less white and less high contrast zones than I would have thought). Or maybe the sheer amount of pure black was throwing off my evaluation.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours-values-ad27b604c1a24d5a653a7a2fa4756798.jpg" width="1680" height="910" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>With this knowledge I changed up Skril’s skin, horn, and hair colour.  Leaving just the saturated reds and golds. As the red fell into a similar zone as the prime colours for Hypnos and Meg:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-colours3-d1f468a3a3b0365d0e5fb715bf2b456b.jpg" width="210" height="140" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-skril-desat-462d5b2e3b5c9eaae4c343fc36650333.jpg" width="1889" height="2700" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>With the colours changed I spent some time choosing the shadow and terminator line colour for my main colours. The terminator line colour is one of the unique calling card features of the Hades style. The terminator line is the line of colour around the darker shadow colour. Usually it would just be a colour between the base and the shadow but in this style it’s usually a colour between the two but also decently hue shifted.</p>
<p>With lines, flats, and shading done, it was time to start adding the black shadows. I don’t know if it was good to leave this part for last. If only because I ended up covering multiple areas I spent time shading…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-shadows-fce9128cf8f02907fc99ed396a9ed808.jpg" width="1889" height="2700" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m still not sure if there should be more black. General art advice is to not use pure whites or pure blacks so it still feels extreme to me to have those big black areas.</p>
<p>With the piece nearly done, it was time for random sparkles.</p>
<p>This is another unique feature of the style that people have noticed. All art pieces have what appear to be random specks of teal, purple, pink, and a few other colours. I couldn’t find any evidence of these colours being applied in a specific way so I kind of just put them around randomly.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ss-hades-skril-done-82347598a6cf11cd67b41183a26f297f.jpg" width="1283" height="2130" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-i-missed">What I missed<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#what-i-missed" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What I missed" title="Direct link to What I missed">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a few places where I deviated from the official style.</p>
<p>Firstly is in my smooth lines. In Hades art you'll almost never find a perfect circle, even perfect curves are rare. But I was drawing a curvy lady so I drew curvy lines. I also hadn't been able to build up line confidence in my warm-ups and I was relying a lot of brush stabalization to get lines I was happy with. Downside being that those almost come out <strong>too</strong> perfect.</p>
<p>Another issue, building on those curved lines was my lack of squares. A lot of Hades art has points and hard curves, also called 'Sharp Shape Language' in Thom's breakdown. If you look at characters fingers you'll see they have square tips. This was a bit because of the lines and a bit because I forgot. Line work is what I struggle with so it takes up a lot of my attention. So while I'm focused on just trying to get lines I like I forgot there were other rules to be following.</p>
<p>For colours I feel like I maybe didn't use enough? The official art has an almost busy feeling to it when you look closely. There is a lot going on. While I left some rather large basic red zones in my pieces. I probably could have tried a few ways of making it more lively.</p>
<p>Oh and I didn't draw legs. I thought the image would crop higher up for the fake screenshot so I hadn't bothered to give them lines and then by the end of it I didn't want to go back and add them back in lol.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="in-game-screenshot">“In-game” screenshot<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#in-game-screenshot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to “In-game” screenshot" title="Direct link to “In-game” screenshot">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-box-final-c7f003753dafe07c9e5d979eaba42bd9.jpg" width="788" height="521" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Making fake Hades screenshots is a pretty popular artist project so finding all the pieces needed was very easy. But in case anyone ever comes looking here they are in one place.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="text-box">Text box<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#text-box" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Text box" title="Direct link to Text box">​</a></h3>
<p>I suspect a few people have done this themselves already, but <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/theemonkeyprince/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TheeMonkeyPrince</a>’s <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/theemonkeyprince/art/Hades-Dialogue-Box-Template-859250942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> comes up first in a search result. There’s some clear pixelation issues found in the shape they used to hide text from the screenshot they used but that’s easy to fix with a little blur.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="fonts">Fonts<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#fonts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Fonts" title="Direct link to Fonts">​</a></h3>
<p>I didn’t have these ready to go when I started the text box but as I suspected someone had done the research long ago. Even named which font is used for what in this <a href="https://graphicdesign.stackexchange.com/questions/163095/what-fonts-are-used-in-the-video-game-hades" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">helpful StackExchange comment</a>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/hades-fonts-8b5a9f907dd8c20d0477c1d5223baae7.png" width="1248" height="120" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’ve become very fond of the font for character names which is titled <a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Caesar+Dressing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Caesar Dressing</a>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background" title="Direct link to Background">​</a></h3>
<p>For the background, I grabbed <a href="https://joannetran.artstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joanne Tran</a>’s official work <a href="https://joannetran.artstation.com/projects/v2401Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">from her ArtStation page</a> where she’s shared a lot of Hades art.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/hades-study#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I have given myself a stretch goal of creating a more Underdark themed background to use in my fake screenshot since that's where Skril's from. Just not sure when I'll have time to squeeze in an extra background.</p>
<p>This study took a few days longer than I normally allow. Fell on a D&amp;D week and I lose my creative window on D&amp;D days to D&amp;D prep. And then I felt under the weather on Sunday so that was my main art days gone. So instead of my planned WAP week I'm going to spend this week getting familiar with some tools.</p>
<p>I upgraded to Clip Studio v4 last week so I'm excited to try out some of it's new features. And I want to learn the new features in the ToonSquid v2 release that happened a few months ago. So maybe I'll try and get back into some animation stuff this week.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>style study</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anatomy practice - Yoga]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Drawing bodies in yoga poses.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last practice in the weekly rotation is classic anatomy and posing. I don’t even dislike doing pose practice but doing it for a week straight is a little much and by day 4 I’m tired of it. But I still want to push myself through the motions so I don’t just try to keep cutting corners with it.</p>
<p>I am still trying to keep these weeks on a theme to be a little more focused and also to keep getting new kinds of poses. This week is yoga, so not the most natural of poses but a good reminder in the ways bodies can bend and move. With the extra difficulty of really needing to focus on the length of limbs because they often need to land in certain places.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Drawing what poses I can remember, which isn’t very many.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.1-1aad99928cdf1c1483bf99554cb8c346.png" width="1489" height="1168" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>Doing some quick figure studies to remember shapes better.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.2-6db51203a06fd7ba282d389cf2ee4212.jpg" width="1544" height="1065" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>My current approach to the study days is to do a trace version as it really helps to figure out the limbs you can’t see and then do a free hand version to try to reinforce what I got from the trace. What I want to add to my practice days is one for pushing the pose. Which wouldn’t have really worked for yoga as it’s already a rather extreme shape for a body to take but I think will work well for other activities.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.3-b82bd1fc7b709041ac15b94f13708831.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.4-fe72cea4b8428aaaceebe9a6d48d9e2d.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---reference-studies">Day 4 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-4---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.5-08a19a625daec3709806a6cda44d26c5.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.6-46cf79ac18130816e4686749ddb4b016.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.7-708ea0cdf8405eb4d006a4aace9c8075.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>For the test day I wanted to try different angles instead of different poses. Since I struggled to get much beyond profile shots for yoga poses I thought it would be good to make my brain work by changing the camera angle.</p>
<p>I did two basic poses first, warrior and cobra. Then I did front angles for both and then a top down, birds eye view for warrior. I think I maybe kept things too sketchy and worry these might not be readable. But since it’s mostly practice on making sure body parts are in the correct place and not using this for a future piece I do want to keep things sketchy and light.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/yoga-1.8-d1ea42631df68f528eb789775b1d5753.jpg" width="806" height="454" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/yoga-poses#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Something I struggled with this week was finding references of yoga poses not in full profile. It’s just how most photography is done as it’s the best way to view the pose if you want to replicate it yourself. But it made for rather static looking bodies when they’re all at the exact same angle. Next anatomy theme needs to be something that’s, weirdly, photographed less.</p>
<p>This anatomy week brings my first practice cycle of the year to a close. Did one; Style study, WAP, Reference study, and one anatomy week. So today the cycle starts again as I return to style studies, with this week's style being The Art of Hades (the video game). A fairly iconic style now, the game has a huge fandom of people replicating the style so I know I’ll find Youtube videos. But there isn’t as much from the studio and art director, which makes sense as you don’t really want another game copying your visual style.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-yoga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of yoga poses.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reference Study - Fey Boat]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Taking 3 reference images and making them into 1.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was preparing my art practice goals for the new year I knew I wanted to practice finishing pieces more often. My WAP weeks were about expanding my mental library of images and drawing things I don’t often draw. But those barely ever left the sketch phase as they were focused on getting the shapes down. The style studies are a lot of fun and I’ll keep doing them but they mean working in a very focused way to achieve a rather limited goal, matching someone else’s style. And while these will help me learn things that will eventually become my style, the execution won’t always feel natural.</p>
<p>And so I came up with this new exercise after watching a few “learning from references” art tutorial videos on YouTube. Basically the idea is that instead of just using one image as inspiration you use multiple so you’re leaning less on one particular artist or style.</p>
<p>Last week in my <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-41" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">beetles WAP</a> I wrote about how this would go. Rolling dice to select 3 images and then go from there. So we’ll start with my 3 images:</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-images">Reference Images<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#reference-images" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reference Images" title="Direct link to Reference Images">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_refs-a7050718f8ae8426611287bf5be5da35.jpg" width="2340" height="815" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I was pretty excited about getting the boat first. Thought I could do some sort of Dredge inspired piece with it. The piece is by concept artist <a href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/r33nO" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arthus Pilorget</a>.</p>
<p>But then I got the colour palette… which isn’t very Dredge like at all. The Genshin Impact Kazuha palette was put together by <a href="https://ko-fi.com/s/090280618a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Caramello__o over on Ko-fi</a>.</p>
<p>Dice roll 3 added these nature spirit guys by <a href="https://x.com/dagasi_yk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dagasi_yk on Twitter</a> as the main characters.</p>
<p>Wanting to expand my ideas beyond just the three images so I made a mini board of things I felt were in a similar vibe. <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/2025-num-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Full board</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="thumbnailing">Thumbnailing<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#thumbnailing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Thumbnailing" title="Direct link to Thumbnailing">​</a></h2>
<p>First step was to do some basic brainstorming. Starting with what first came to mind and then pushing the POV around to see if the scene got more interesting from other angles.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_thumbnails-c1f37a72fe1109b58f5efaeac14ef79c.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="basic-colours-and-shapes">Basic colours and shapes<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#basic-colours-and-shapes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Basic colours and shapes" title="Direct link to Basic colours and shapes">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sketch-2f8c816c115192426339f6625989de9c.jpg" width="3456" height="1944" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I had a decent amount of time on Sunday so after choosing which thumbnail to go with I enlarged it and started to play around with the main colours. I was fairly fixated on have a big orange sky, which may have not been the best choice in the end but I found it rather pleasant to work with as it gave a quickly, otherworldly-ness, to the piece.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1-progress">Day 1 progress<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#day-1-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 progress" title="Direct link to Day 1 progress">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s not often that I give myself a whole week to work on a single piece. During my Root style study week I made 3 complete pieces in 7 days. Having 7 days for one felt extravagant.</p>
<p>Or at least it did until I started painting. I couldn’t choose how I wanted to do the piece. Did I want hard black lines? Did I want lineless? A softer painting style? Or flat and blocky?</p>
<p>While I had 3 images as references to build the piece, I didn’t use any of them to really dictate the style. So I pulled up some digital painting videos and waited for inspiration to reach me. Eventually, I got my first piece down; the roof.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sunday1-a23b6ec386f46fe9c83cdbbaaa86d646.png" width="1392" height="1127" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I was pretty happy with how these shingles looked but my attempt to make it more readable by changing the colours instantly broke my colour palette and also made the scene look like it was made out of candy. But I already felt myself floundering so I pushed on. Grabbing the part of the image that interested me most, the little guys.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_sunday2-5a888fc03e9bda734d353164d08cee92.png" width="331" height="698" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>These guys I was happy with. With these guys I could end my day not hating the piece.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="work-continues">Work continues<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#work-continues" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Work continues" title="Direct link to Work continues">​</a></h2>
<p>With the weekend done I made it a goal to try to put 1 hour into the piece everyday after work. Some days saw more progress than others. By Tuesday I had most of a boat.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_tuesday-939423d8f0bde3af6c0f692ae6af56ac.png" width="1068" height="832" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After that I kind of stopped saving progress shots….</p>
<p>I finished most of the boat before going to the background. I returned to my struggles of choosing a stylistic choice once more and you can see me growing impatient by turning to leaf brushes for the tree and grass brushes to fill in the small islands. I’m not against using these kinds of brushes but since I only use them for these 2 features and they’re off to the side on their own island it does make them stand out more by not being consistent with the rest of the piece. If I had thought ahead and maybe balanced the islands in the background differently I could probably have made it look more normalized. But I’m kind of a “just push through” kind of artist. A habit I’m going to try to fix.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="final-piece">Final piece<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#final-piece" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Final piece" title="Direct link to Final piece">​</a></h2>
<p>I was able to wrap up the whole thing on Saturday, rushing to get it done before running D&amp;D and having taken the morning off to make a map and draw some goblins for the game.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/rs1_final-c8c72af12704e8575235d5d1dc91bcac.jpg" width="3456" height="1944" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Overall I think about somewhere between 10-15 hours went into this piece. Being able to take my time led to some parts I’m really happy with, like some of the wood texturing on the boat, how textured the clouds look, the little plant guys. There are definitely some areas I rushed either because I didn’t know how to accomplish what I wanted or because I was losing interest. I think next time I do this challenge I’m going to try to give myself a Friday deadline so I can spend a whole Saturday just working on light and shadows and colour corrections because that’s something I really enjoy but rarely give myself enough time to do properly.</p>
<p>I’m not sure how well I was able to stick to the palette. I probably wouldn’t have chosen these colours on my own so it was nice to have the restriction, but it also made me constantly worry about deviating too far when wanting to do some hue shifted shadows. I also didn't keep some of the main points I highlighted in my thumbnails. I didn't keep the side wheel which I really wanted, or have there be plants on the boat. It just felt like I had enough going on when I made the choices but I kind of regret it now.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/fey-boat#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>While I could talk about all the cut corners and the things I’m not particularly pleased with, this was a very big project for me and it makes me happy when I look at it. I do wish I had played with more foreground/background stuff but this was my first project in this practice format so plenty of time to take more chances in the future. Maybe I’ll even enforce the palette further by not allowing any shifts and having to use only the chosen colours as highlights and shadows. Lots of options for the next one!</p>
<p>Next week I’m going back to anatomy studies as it’s another facet I want to keep improving at and the secret to that one is basically just keep doing it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Art Practice - Week 41]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Week 41 - Beetles]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First WAP of 2025!</p>
<p>I’m keeping some WAPs in the mix with my other practice things this year to give me some easier weeks and also to keep drawing things I don’t usually draw. It’s nice to return to a practice format that’s familiar and feels doable. Versus some of the larger challenges I’m also trying to give myself this year.</p>
<p>This first WAP is beetles, so I guess stop reading now if you don’t like looking at bugs as there will be zoomed in pictures of bugs.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---drawing-from-imagination">Day 1 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-1---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>Beetles aren’t too complex right? I can just draw some from the ether.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.1-467b3282dc16b9a7e6aa03f66ceef5f6.jpg" width="2179" height="1760" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---figure-sketching">Day 2 - Figure sketching<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-2---figure-sketching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching" title="Direct link to Day 2 - Figure sketching">​</a></h2>
<p>There are a lot of hercules and rhinoceros beetles on Pinterest so that’s what I ended up focusing on. I didn’t know how large these bugs were until this week and boy, I’m not sure if I’m better off knowing or not.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Quick hand sketches using references" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.2-7eb055637a1f0a5c06c7994bf341e9e0.jpg" width="2484" height="1773" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---reference-studies">Day 3 - Reference studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-3---reference-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Reference studies">​</a></h2>
<p>Some of the biggest things I missed in my initial sketches were how complex beetle legs are. They are very spiky and have a decent amount of joints. I also missed that some have some antenna things going on but you need a very good photo to see them.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.3.1-24d79669425e23e8a092ceb4112257f4.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.3.2-18ab45a94f6e461afa9e7597dc4a56a2.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---style-studies">Day 4 - Style studies<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-4---style-studies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Style studies">​</a></h2>
<p>There are some really nice stylized beetles out there. And it was nice to see how much people simplified the complicated limbs.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.1-2509e8defbf5f42339db3955f6b20bcf.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: Pinterest says this is by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/opossum_jesus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">opossum_jesus on Instagram</a> but their account is private so I can’t verify. There is also a Redbubble account selling a sticker version but it’s been taken down. So whoever drew this has been taking down their art from public spaces.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.2-903266f2a73b73b6b17a227dada6a6f9.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I didn’t do the really pretty pattern as it wasn’t going to contribute to grasping the shape of a beetle but i do really love this piece by Oddarette.</p>
<p>Reference: <a href="https://cara.app/post/e8dafedc-1170-4eb4-94ad-fa3311ad83cc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">By Oddarette on Cara</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.4.3-2b904afad7d053f3c369048e4d480149.jpg" width="3000" height="2000" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Reference: A vector image from[Freepik]<a href="https://www.freepik.com/premium-vector/beetle-illustration-cartoon-character-drawing_69868105.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.freepik.com/premium-vector/beetle-illustration-cartoon-character-drawing_69868105.htm</a>)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---drawing-from-imagination">Day 5 - Drawing from imagination<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#day-5---drawing-from-imagination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination" title="Direct link to Day 5 - Drawing from imagination">​</a></h2>
<p>For test day I drew some basic guys but then also wanted to do a slightly more cartoon-y character. Hence the warrior beetle holding a staff in the corner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/wap-41.5-25efb74724d8f704aa4107456971c569.jpg" width="2690" height="1995" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/wap-41#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Insects definitely aren’t something I draw regularly, nor are they something I often want to look very closely at. But I think it’s important to draw them, and at least understand how to draw them as they are everywhere and looking at them so closely helps to demystify them. Makes me squirm a little less at each new photo.</p>
<p>It was nice to return to the WAP format, I feel like I can get through the daily task fairly quickly now. Made for a good practice exercise for a week where I was still feeling pretty ill and low energy. This coming week I’m trying something a little more intensive, doing an exercise to help learn how to draw from reference.</p>
<p>I created 3 pin boards:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colour schemes</li>
<li>Locations</li>
<li>Characters</li>
</ul>
<p>Then for each one of those boards I rolled a di so I would randomly get a colour scheme to use for a type of location which will feature a random character. Forcing me to get creative in how all three pieces fit together and create something new. I want these to be fully rendered pieces and I have the sketch for my first one completed already but I’m struggling with how to colour it. Do I want to try a digital painting style? Do I stick with my default black linework? Should I try to bring in some of the techniques I learned from my Root study week?????? Just so many options and none of them are working for me just yet.</p>
<p>Pinterest board <a href="https://ca.pinterest.com/maeanu3639/wap-beetles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of beetles</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>wap</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Style Study - Kyle Ferrin]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A week spent studying the art style of the board game Root, as done by Kyle Ferrin.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As part of my WAP year I did one style study, <a href="https://www.kymira.ca/blog/wap-34" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ken Sugimori’s Pokemon trainers</a>. This year I’m going to attempt to do a style study every month to push me out of my comfort zone and also to learn to break down what I’m looking at when it comes to art pieces.</p>
<p>Kyle Ferrin was an easy first choice as he has both a very distinct style that’s almost instantly recognizable to me and it’s extremely cute. For this study I’m focusing mostly on his visual style of the boardgame Root and not his whole portfolio but he is pretty consistent in some regards.</p>
<p>Before jumping in I wanted to identify the main things I wanted to learn or understand in this particular study:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ink work: Kyle uses blank ink for a lot of shadows, much more than I would usually</li>
<li>Shapes: We’re gonna be looking at a lot of little critters, how does he keep them recognizable?</li>
<li>Colours: The work in Root feels extremely vibrant while still natural.</li>
<li>Backgrounds: Kyle doesn’t do a lot of backgrounds but does have a few techniques he repeats.</li>
</ul>
<p>Studies are going to break down differently from my WAP weeks, and may even differ from artist to artist. I made a 5 day plan for this one and mostly managed to stick to it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-1---research-and-techniques">Day 1 - Research and techniques<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-1---research-and-techniques" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 1 - Research and techniques" title="Direct link to Day 1 - Research and techniques">​</a></h2>
<p>Root and Kyle are, thankfully, both very popular. An added bonus is that Kyle has some recorded streams of his full art process. This makes understanding his workflow pretty easy as you can watch him do it in real time. I was even able to find 2 interviews he did where he talks about art which led to a few gems that helped me approach this study week.</p>
<p>Interview 1: <a href="https://www.moregamesplease.com/art-in-boardgames/2018/3/15/kyle-ferrin-art-in-board-games-31" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kyle Ferrin: Art in Board Games #31</a></p>
<p>Interview 2: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/boardgames/comments/bu8a6l/interview_with_kyle_ferrin_artist_on_root/?rdt=54583" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Interview with Kyle Ferrin, Artist on Root!</a> (Original website seems broken)</p>
<p>It was in the images chosen for the More Games Please interview that I noticed the bush and tree techniques. So on day one I tried to recreate those techniques digitally. I then took my old goblin drawing and did an inking pass on it to practice where Kyle would put harder shadows, using this collection of skeleton warriors as examples to reference.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf_techniques1-bf0cb463cd44b34e8585b15afc24150b.jpg" width="3840" height="2160" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I then spent some time with the Root cover image and a collection of Kyle goblins. I love how expressive his characters are and I wanted to look more closely at Root character proportions.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-faces-15d86904f3527b60123afb87f1795b3a.jpg" width="3840" height="1735" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-2---first-attempt-at-the-style">Day 2 - First attempt at the style<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-2---first-attempt-at-the-style" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 2 - First attempt at the style" title="Direct link to Day 2 - First attempt at the style">​</a></h2>
<p>Feeling pretty excited by what I learned in day 1 I jumped into creating a Root fanart piece. I wanted to draw critters that aren’t as common in Root so I chose pigeon and squirrel. Kyle has done a few squirrels but I have to say they aren’t my favourite designs of his.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-full-scene1-0e4ce6745fd4c63a0e0e4750d4df6d07.jpg" width="2015" height="1443" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m happy with a lot of this piece but there are a few areas that stand out for improvement. Mostly the building. There aren’t many full buildings in the Root art so I didn’t have much to use as a reference. Because of that I kind of just floundered and used it to fill space. I also could have played with more line/ink colour variations instead of just black and white.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-3---workflow-replication">Day 3 - Workflow replication<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-3---workflow-replication" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 3 - Workflow replication" title="Direct link to Day 3 - Workflow replication">​</a></h2>
<p>To see Kyle’s workflow in action I watched his live stream from three months ago: <a href="https://youtu.be/kxlhol6JOhQ?si=ua68nO0f4xz1k0sk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leder Games | Art Stream with Kyle Ferrin!</a></p>
<p>Which seems to breakdown to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sketch</li>
<li>Ink</li>
<li>Scan</li>
<li>Digital colours</li>
</ol>
<p>So I would do the same. Instead of adding difficulty of coming up with a piece from scratch I decided to recreate a piece of Root art. I wanted something with a little bit of background as well as a character so I went with this raccoon behind a log piece.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Raccoon in behind a log by Kyle Ferrin" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kyle-forest-raccoon-bca23aeb7b245ced8eb1d16f2acfbbcc.jpg" width="736" height="1028" class="img_ev3q">
(This is an original Root piece.)</p>
<p>I did a sketch and then tested my pens because it’s been a long time since I inked anything by hand. Most of what I own are Microns which didn’t feel right for this, they are too small and precise. So I chose my pens that had more of a brush tip for larger areas.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/raccoon-inks-69861b128bfe57e65b28176c08ebf8ae.jpg" width="3072" height="4080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I don’t have a scanner so I had to rely on trying to get a good phone photo. It came out pretty decent after some level corrections in CSP but also felt like there were a lot of strange artifacts like red pixels and blurring in the photo.</p>
<p>I then colour picked from the original and tried out some digital watercolour brushes to get that textured look that Kyle gets. In the video Kyle shares the limited Root colour palette that he uses for all the board game pieces. And in one of the interviews he said:</p>
<p>“Most of the color pallet for the board art in Root is sampled from autumn foliage photography.”</p>
<p>So I also felt comfortable deviating a little from the source image as long as I kept the autumn colours in mind.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-copy-study-cf397222294342549691a70a1dfc2401.jpg" width="2004" height="3051" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>My own raccoon came out a little too small but I’m happy with the piece overall. I liked working with the water colour brushes as they keep the large colour areas interesting without even doing a shading pass. I did try taking some notes on areas of improvement.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-copy-study-notes-aca8bf19ed6d283e1dfa33cd26c4ca00.jpg" width="2004" height="3051" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You can see them side by side here:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-sidebyside-ae02cba9c1cdd34e990969cbd17a6147.jpg" width="3348" height="2193" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-4---watercolours">Day 4 - Watercolours<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-4---watercolours" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 4 - Watercolours" title="Direct link to Day 4 - Watercolours">​</a></h2>
<p>For day 4 I took it easy a bit by doing a physical watercolour pass on the inks I did previously. Mostly because I enjoy working with watercolours even if I’m not very skilled at them. Unfortunately my pens weren’t waterproof…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/raccoon-watercolour-f20d4e15d17665922fdb796bd105cab8.jpg" width="2254" height="3458" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Parts of it went okay while others got out of control rather quickly. But it was fun to do it physically after already doing the piece digitally.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="day-5---new-unique-piece-in-the-style">Day 5 - New unique piece in the style<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#day-5---new-unique-piece-in-the-style" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Day 5 - New unique piece in the style" title="Direct link to Day 5 - New unique piece in the style">​</a></h2>
<p>For the last day I wanted to draw something new again. I did some thumbnailing and chose the parts of the style I definitely wanted to incorporate.</p>
<p>While most of the art for Root is small cards and mostly individual character pieces, I’ve been in full “scene” mode from working on the visual novel. So a background and multiple characters. Basically gave myself hard mode for the final. But I really enjoyed the ways of doing forest plants, I wanted to keep doing those.</p>
<p>I also didn’t let myself colour pick from an image and instead eye balled the colours to see how far off I would be. I don’t think any of the Root pieces do much foreground background stuff but I did darker a whole section to create some depth to the image. Trying to push the style a bit and also just bring in my own techniques for creating a scene.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/kf-final-1e7ec3d2631398e70a5fcbb3b9b0f901.jpg" width="1691" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m pretty happy with the piece! Something I learned while working on it, while watching another Root art stream, was that Kyle works at very small sizes. He showed off the pens he used and it made me realize I’ve just been super over sizing everything. When I went to use my own pens my thoughts were “these are too small” when it turns out they were way too big. I didn’t imagine that he was working at such a small scale, but it makes filling in blacks so much easier when you are fighting to fill a whole page. Due to working at a larger size I also end up with a lot of empty space. Most of the Root pieces don't have much sky and I probably shouldn't have filled in more of the background with larger grasses and more trees.</p>
<p>Something learned from the interviews is that the colour palette and line work style for Root is chosen with a reason; communicating game state. The art pieces are meant to be easy to parse and understand at a glance thanks to high contrast, be that between lines, colours, or shapes. Something that I went against by darkening the foreground. I have the freedom of not drawing this fanart for a game but it's extremely interesting to learn why certain creative desicions are made for particular settings.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="resources">Resources<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#resources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Resources" title="Direct link to Resources">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m not the only person doing Kyle Ferrin or Root studies. I found one video on YouTube of another artist doing their best to replicate the style:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pfXEM3C8RZE?si=Qq0wve34b3kHabhh" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>
<p>The artist goes for a full digital approach which is what I did in my first attempt as well. I think it’s okay for a single character but the larger Root scenes with backgrounds and heavier inking feel like they really need a physical ink brush to capture the style properly.</p>
<p>I also found another person’s Root fanart over on Reddit that I really liked: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rootgame/comments/11kssrz/i_tried_to_recreate_the_root_artstyle_free_to_use/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I tried to recreate the Root artstyle!</a>. Their work also feels fully digital but I wasn’t able to find any active website or socials for them.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/kyle-ferrin-study#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I feel like this was a very promising first style study. I’m happy with the pieces I produced for it and there are tricks here that I can see myself relying on to create more stylized backgrounds. It was a fun kind of investigation to really watch someone work and try to analyses their pieces. I’d also like to be able to draw my own lovable little guys but I think I still have more practice in that area to do. Downside to this study, I now want to buy all the Root games...</p>
<p>Find Kyle’s work at:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/d20plusmodifier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His Instagram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://kyleferrin.threadless.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His store</a></li>
<li>Check out other games Kyle has worked on at <a href="https://ledergames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leder Games</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve been very sick all this week so I might take it easy next week with a more classic WAP or even a week of focusing on some Littos bits and pieces.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>style study</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 4]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Going into the final week, I’ve done my (very likely) final pull request for art assets. Have done a few playthroughs of the game, hunting down any bugs. Between how hard we worked early in the month and our success at avoiding too much scope creep, we’re hoping to submit the game in the next day or two with a day to spare before the deadline.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going into the final week, I’ve done my (very likely) final pull request for art assets. Have done a few playthroughs of the game, hunting down any bugs. Between how hard we worked early in the month and our success at avoiding too much scope creep, we’re hoping to submit the game in the next day or two with a day to spare before the deadline.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/week4-assets-a44526177e7b82fe90c539eedb7c2b4f.png" width="690" height="306" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I had pretty confidently thought I was done with backgrounds last week but while we were brainstorming final scenes it was clear having one more would help. This ended up launching a quick Clip Asset Store search, buying the CPS version update (I’ve been on v2.0 for years…) and hoping that nothing would break in the update.</p>
<p>It thankfully all went very smoothly and I got new Clip features to use out of it! And I drew I kitchen x_x Which I won’t share yet as it’s only for those who choose a specific ending.</p>
<p>It feels like we actually ended up with a lot of backgrounds for a game designed around lockdown. Helps that most of the characters live in the same building so I could keep the interior scenes consistent and reuse bits and pieces. As shown in this angled hallway shot that ties in with last week’s doorway shot. Didn’t think I’d be re-creating the wallpaper again and definitely had to re-learn the sequence of effects on it…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/apt_hallway-c18f38b48950bfc7225dbdeb22732071.png" width="1920" height="1280" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>But it also just became difficult to have emotional character scenes without giving the characters somewhere to go. And new backgrounds feel like game progression in this kind of game. Getting to see someone else’s apartment is both game progress and character relationship progress.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="assets">Assets<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Assets" title="Direct link to Assets">​</a></h2>
<p>Something I did in the last few days was do a shading pass on our 4 characters. I wasn’t sure I was going to have time when we started but I’m super happy it’s something I did in the end as it makes them fit into the scenes much better. The backgrounds all have shading so they look like part of the world by having their own shading.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-with-shading-12fcd9d61758433c7d6e3308a6616378.jpg" width="2035" height="798" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I also darkened Lauren’s skin tone to differentiate her more from Kim and show her wood nymph heritage.</p>
<p>Shading all the characters took about 2 days as I had to do each base differently and then jackets on top of bases.</p>
<p>I made an asset spread of all the Lauren pieces to show how few assets it takes to make what I feel like is a pretty expressive character.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-spread-4bf5cb11875f10c52cb67493953aa1d2.jpg" width="1500" height="1500" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>When I was first brainstorming how to do the characters I had mentally mapped it as “draw a happy face” “draw a sad face” thinking that each expression would require a face. But after some VN research it was decided that the more efficient but more programmatically demanding way to do expressions was by working with multiple assets at once. So instead of a fully drawn happy face asset, a happy face was made out of: a smile + neutral eyes. While an angry face would be made out of: a frown + squinting eyes + angled brows. And then an embarrassed face could be: a frown + blush. Basically letting us remix different eye + mouth assets to create a lot more expressions than having to draw an individual face for each expression. I feel like this really worked out for us as whenever I play the game I’m tickled by how much the characters move from sentence to sentence (which is largely to do with my wife’s programming timing of them all).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-4#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>It’s nearly time to package and upload the game to Itch! Some final fixes are going in and stress tested over the next 24 hours. Some issues are bound to have slipped through, it’s difficult to test every permutation of choices a player can make while going through the 2 days. So if you’re reading this and playing the game let us know if you see anything weird.</p>
<p>For me, next week is February so I’m back to smaller, weekly projects for art practice. With my first one being a style study of Kyle Ferrin, the board game artist of <a href="https://ledergames.com/products/root-a-game-of-woodland-might-and-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Root fame</a>. I also want to take some time next week and review all the assets I relied on for the game and share some of my favourites in their own blog post.</p>
<p>For LitToS, we’re probably going to take some time away from it and start looking for ways to make it a more sustainable project while lightly polishing what we have so far.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>games</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 3]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It’s time for the week 3 summary. That’s 21 days of working on our game non-stop. Neither of us has taken a full day off since we started, doing probably 7-10 hours of work a day each (well, a little less for me on the days I go to my paying job). We’re still progressing at a nice pace but with more than half the month gone the to-do list feels a little scarier with each passing day.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s time for the week 3 summary. That’s 21 days of working on our game non-stop. Neither of us has taken a full day off since we started, doing probably 7-10 hours of work a day each (well, a little less for me on the days I go to my paying job). We’re still progressing at a nice pace but with more than half the month gone the to-do list feels a little scarier with each passing day.</p>
<p>The assets list increases a little every week. Last week there were 77 needed assets, this week ending at 82. Some of those are ‘nice-to-haves’ which I’m going to start tracking as stretch goals so they don’t contribute to the overall number necessary for launch.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/week3-assets-d1d625c1169c65f2f8d83ab25bb71c0f.png" width="766" height="272" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I was able to finish 2 huge bedrooms in the last 10 days. They were so intense for me that I felt so much relief when I opened a new canvas and could just bask in the emptiness of it. Managed a smaller, more abstract background for Day 2 in just a day, which felt nice and productive. After that I started to work on “end scenes” for the game. Visual novels often end on a unique art scene so we wanted some of those. Like the “reward” for finishing the game.</p>
<p>I was able to finish up one of the ending images pretty quickly and it’s one of the cutest things I’ve ever drawn. I want to post it online real bad but it’s basically a spoiler that I want people to first see in game. So in game it will stay for a few months.</p>
<p>This background doesn’t have any spoilers so check out this good wall. The door even opens! I was able to get this done pretty quickly as well thanks to some wood panelling assets and a wallpaper material from the Clip Store. It’s simple but I feel like it really sells the scene in engine.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/apt-hallway-60dd18c47ae85da352c215b090616311.png" width="1920" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="assets">Assets<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Assets" title="Direct link to Assets">​</a></h2>
<p>Since I spent so much time populating a nerd room I ended up drawing a lot of Stuff to fill the room. Tried to give it a fair bit of character. This is my collection of Little Guys for Cass’s room.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/little-guys-swak-e1e808f2a5bf1399fcd960304a3e5180.jpg" width="573" height="410" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="making-a-montreal-like">Making a Montreal-like<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#making-a-montreal-like" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making a Montreal-like" title="Direct link to Making a Montreal-like">​</a></h2>
<p>The city in our game isn’t Montreal, but it’s got parts of Montreal with twists. It made sense to us to set the game in a city like Montreal since it’s where we live and we knew we could look around and find references easily. There are some clear Montreal landmarks that I used as reference for a few backgrounds so far.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/parc_vs_park-207490cd3ff50ae2b011d03bf4e350b9.jpg" width="3100" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This photo is my main inspiration for the park background. The statue changed into the amethyst obelisk and the cross on the mountain replaced by our magical school.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/outside-apartments-5a7e39ec887d61db18a27467d767b3a9.png" width="2648" height="1494" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The apartment front is based off of an apartment building where a friend lives.</p>
<p>The school in the game is called Crowstone and I used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ravenscrag,_Montreal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Montreal’s Ravenscrag manor</a> as inspiration. This manor turned psychiatric hospital (with an honestly very dark history that the Wiki page weirdly doesn’t mention) is a building near Mont Royal park but in the game I put it right on top of the hill to loom over the city. Making it visible in a few different backgrounds.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/ravenscrag-45977179a8df9a6a46f4e9f4fd2c843a.png" width="1454" height="832" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>The street scene is also very Montreal, I would have loved to include the classic spiral staircases but I would have hated doing those in perspective. Also debated having a French stop sign but we decided against it since we don’t have any French in the game. And it is meant to be more of a fantasy world than the real world.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-day-89b3797c1dff066b134bb3b77cadb007.png" width="1280" height="724" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>There are a few other iconic Montreal features like churches everywhere, constant construction, random art installation, and great parks that I’d like to include in future backgrounds. Given the strong D&amp;D influence in our game world, churches would probably become temples to different gods, construction might be magic that works on its own. But each background takes me at least 2-4 days so we’ve really tried to limit our location in this first part of the game so these things won’t come up in the next version. But I’ll definitely be using more image inspiration like with the statue and hill photo reference because I’ve really enjoyed incorporating my everyday world into a fantasy story world.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-3#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>I’m trying to wrap up the last art assets in the next 7 days so that we have a comfortable few days to implement everything and make sure it works before submitting the game to the jam. I’m feeling pretty confident about getting through the last needed art pieces but there’s still a lot of writing and other implementations to get done too.</p>
<p>Something I’m noticing for myself is that by spending so much time in the Creative Zone I find myself coming up with new ideas constantly. Not just art ideas but my other hobbies too. I want to do some video editing and make a trailer for the game. I have an idea for a level 1 intro adventure in D&amp;D. I want to work on my volunteer projects. I want to do art for the D&amp;D campaign I’m already running. And I recognize this feeling from my years doing NaNoWriMo. Part of it is longing for the thrill of a new project after being so intensely focused on a single one. Part of it is just that creative activity feeds creative energy. I’d love to say that I hope to carry this energy into February but there’s a solid chance I’ll crash and not want to touch my tablet for a while. I’ve started to get some back pain over the last few days so I’d like to give myself some rest time. So resting is my main plan for February 2nd, that and getting back into physio exercises.</p>
<p>You can still play Day 1 on our <a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/love-in-the-time-of-spellphage-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io page</a> for another week or so. We did a minor update after its first release to add a few more art assets and cat content. The current game will get replaced when we release Day 2 next week!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>games</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devlog - SWAK Week 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2</link>
            <guid>https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>14 days in, so it’s time for another progress report on Love in the Time of Spellphage.</p>
<p>Not a huge change in the asset tracker as I wrapped up most of the small part and have spent the last 5 days in focused background mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/asset-tracking-week2-8ee3e007d5ece8383347068f29718aab.png" width="544" height="254" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="asset-creation">Asset creation<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#asset-creation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Asset creation" title="Direct link to Asset creation">​</a></h2>
<p>Between backgrounds I was able to wrap up jackets (multiple forms for each character) for the 3 characters who can be seen outside on the first day of the game. Also designed this logo for an in-world restaurant:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/takeout-b8f96154c8d420e43885b0ac9bc6d3b6.png" width="254" height="300" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Drew a hand and a portal, multiple little cats. I really like doing these small one offs as I feel like I can experiment with them versus backgrounds which are way more demanding mentally. But since most of the small assets are done it’s been a pretty big week for background work.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backgrounds">Backgrounds<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#backgrounds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backgrounds" title="Direct link to Backgrounds">​</a></h2>
<p>I had a pretty terrible time with this street scene I worked on for 4 days.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-day-89b3797c1dff066b134bb3b77cadb007.png" width="1280" height="724" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I’m going to point out all the things wrong with it but I ask that you wipe the mistakes from your brain when you play the game.</p>
<p>I started fairly confidently, really loved the back line of buildings and managed to keep it mostly flat rectangles. Then I moved on to the right side of the street. Activated the perspective ruler and started to draw some buildings. It was decided that the eye line was too high and I told myself I would push all the lines down with the Transform tool once I had them done. But then I came back the next day and pushed them down and altered the perspective ruler and then started the left side. I didn’t realize how much I had altered the ruler by the time I was done with the lines on the left side. I kept returning to the right side, trying to push it down more, trying to fix the roof which I drew in after the shift because the top of the buildings didn’t exist in the first pass.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/street-perspective-lines-6337c03fc1bebab9261cb3c312117082.png" width="1282" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Something I had gotten good at for the first few days was Deleting My Art. A very common and helpful art tip. Didn’t like how a character was looking? Delete it. All the lines look bad? Delete them. There is learning to be taken from sticking with something incorrect and figuring out how to fix it, but I was mostly in ideation and discovery mode, so each deletion led to something better.</p>
<p>But as I feared with starting background, I fell into sunk cost fallacy and wasn’t willing to throw away 2 hours of work. The saving grace of the piece is that I am really happy with the left side buildings and the back row. It feels Montreal-esque without being too on the nose. And while I’m still struggling with colour selection in big pieces I don’t think there are too many mistakes.</p>
<p>I brought my fear into the next background I started and spent a lot of time in layout and perspective mode.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/lauren-room-measurements-f236e24903a38dbad90ab576bc982370.png" width="1281" height="721" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I am very happy with how main character Lauren’s room turned out. It doesn’t feel great to instantly jump into working on another character's bedroom but I’m hoping I can take what I learned from Lauren’s room and move a little faster. Lauren’s room took about 10 hours… I ended up downloading a lot of 3D objects from the Clip Studio Asset store which let me feel like I was playing with toys as I chose where to place them and size them.</p>
<p>I have 2-3 backgrounds to go, even if they all take 3 days each, which leaves me some wiggle room to revisit art pieces from earlier in the month and adding more details.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="version-01-launch">Version 0.1 launch<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#version-01-launch" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch" title="Direct link to Version 0.1 launch">​</a></h2>
<p>While conceptualizing our game we designed it around 7 days that the player would play through. When making a branching game, a solid rule is to build your Golden Path first. This can be your “happy” ending path, or the path you think most players will enjoy or gravitate towards.</p>
<p>Since our game is a romance sim it would mean choosing one of the love interests and completing their path before anyone else's. This proved difficult in a pretty big way in that one of the central parts of a romance sim is being able to choose who you romance. We worried that having one obviously foregrounded character would give the wrong vibe.</p>
<p>I kept pushing for finding a Golden Path during the build up week before the game as I’m familiar with watching new game makers spiral out of scope and get lost in the weeds. We talked it over multiple times, thinking about how the game breaks up in other ways. Just a day or two before the jam started we had the realization that if we wanted something that felt like a full game, we could scope by days instead of paths. We scoped down pretty drastically, to the first 2 days of the story. The major downside being that this scoping didn’t help with scoping down of asset requirements as we would still need art for each character and location.</p>
<p>And while this did mean rushing through as much art as possible in the first few days, I think this scope is what’s to credit for us being able to publish Day 1 as version 0.1 before the end of week two.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://kymira.ca/assets/images/littos-itch-3314046c65231a7437bbcbe7c4daffa5.png" width="2840" height="1404" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>You can play Day 1 on our <a href="https://sophiefromhowls.itch.io/love-in-the-time-of-spellphage-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Itch.io page</a> however I do recommend downloading a version instead of playing in the browser as you’ll have a better audio and performance experience that way. We’ve gotten some positive feedback from friends already and possibly some Beta Tester who are strangers to us and have fewer reasons to be nice to us <!-- -->:o</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://kymira.ca/blog/swak-2#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps">​</a></h2>
<p>The next big thing for the project is writing Day 2. We have some ideas on these scenes but it will likely be a fair bit of brainstorming still. For myself, I’ll likely be in background mode for the next week as we don’t even know all the scenes or locations we’ll need for Day 2 yet...</p>
<p>We’re also hoping to get feedback during week 3 and incorporate anything actionable before the end of the month.</p>
<p>It’s likely to be another focused week and I already feel myself longing to do art that doesn’t involve a perspective ruler. But feeling very accomplished in what we've been able to make so far!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>art</category>
            <category>games</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>